<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notebook – OG</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/ielts/reading/og/</link><description>Recent content in OG on Notebook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://note.codiy.net/docs/ielts/reading/og/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: R.OG1.1 The Dover Bronze-Age Boat</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og1.1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 13:11:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og1.1/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A beautifully preserved boat, made around 3,000 years ago and discovered by chance in a muddy hole, has had a profound impact on archaeological research.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It was 1992. In England, workmen were building a new road through the heart of Dover, to connect the ancient port and the Channel Tunnel, which, when it opened just two years later, was to be the first land link between Britain and Europe for over 10,000 years. A small team from the Canterbury Archaeological Trust (CAT) worked alongside the workmen, recording new discoveries brought to light by the machines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the base of a deep shaft six metres below the modern streets a wooden structure was revealed. Cleaning away the waterlogged site overlying the timbers, archaeologists realised its true nature. They had found a prehistoric boat, preserved by the type of sediment in which it was buried. It was then named the Dover Bronze-Age Boat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>About nine metres of the boat’s length was recovered; one end lay beyond the excavation and had to be left. What survived consisted essentially of four intricately carved oak planks: two on the bottom, joined along a central seam by a complicated system of wedges and timbers, and two at the side, curved and stitched to the others. The seams had been made watertight by pads of moss, fixed by wedges and yew stitches.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The timbers that closed the recovered end of the boat had been removed in antiquity when it was abandoned, but much about its original shape could be deduced. There was also evidence for missing upper side planks. The boat was not a wreck, but had been deliberately discarded, dismantled and broken. Perhaps it had been &amp;lsquo;ritually killed, at the end of its life, like other Bronze-Age objects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With hindsight, it was significant that the boat was found and studied by mainstream archaeologists who naturally focused on its cultural context. At the time, ancient boats were often considered only from a narrower technological perspective, but news about the Dover boat reached a broad audience. In 2002, on the tenth anniversary of the discovery, the Dover Bronze-Age Boat Trust hosted a conference, where this meeting of different traditions became apparent. Alongside technical papers about the boat, other speakers explored its social and economic contexts, and the religious perceptions of boats in Bronze-Age societies. Many speakers came from overseas, and debate about cultural connections was renewed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Within seven years of excavation, the Dover boat had been conserved and displayed, but it was apparent that there were issues that could not be resolved simply by studying the old wood. Experimental archaeology seemed to be the solution: a boat reconstruction, half-scale or full-sized, would permit assessment of the different hypotheses regarding its build and the missing end. The possibility of returning to Dover to search for the boat&amp;rsquo;s unexcavated northern end was explored, but practical and financial difficulties were insurmountable 一 and there was no guarantee that the timbers had survived the previous decade in the changed environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Detailed proposals to reconstruct the boat were drawn up in 2004. Archaeological evidence was beginning to suggest a Bronze-Age community straddling the Channel, brought together by the sea, rather than separated by it. In a region today divided by languages and borders, archaeologists had a duty to inform the general public about their common cultural heritage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The boat project began in England but it was conceived from the start as a European collaboration. Reconstruction was only part of a scheme that would include a major exhibition and an extensive educational and outreach programme. Discussions began early in 2005 with archaeological bodies, universities and heritage organisations either side of the Channel. There was much enthusiasm and support, and an official launch of the project was held at an international seminar in France in 2007. Financial support was confirmed in 2008 and the project then named BOAT 1550BC got under way in June 2011.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A small team began to make the boat at the start of 2012 on the Roman Lawn outside Dover museum. A full-scale reconstruction of a mid-section had been made in 1996, primarily to see how Bronze- Age replica tools performed. In 2012, however, the hull shape was at the centre of the work, so modem power tools were used to carve the oak planks, before turning to prehistoric tools for finishing. It was decided to make the replica half-scale for reasons of cost and time, and synthetic materials were used for the stitching, owing to doubts about the scaling and tight timetable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meanwhile, the exhibition was being prepared ready for opening in July 2012 at the Castle Museum in Boulogne-sur-Mer. Entitled &amp;lsquo;Beyond the Horizon: Societies of the Channel &amp;amp; North Sea 3,500 years ago&amp;rsquo;, it brought together for the first time a remarkable collection of Bronze-Age objects, including many new discoveries for commercial archaeology and some of the great treasure of the past. The reconstructed boat, as a symbol of the maritime connections that bound together the communities either side of the Channel, was the centrepiece.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R.OG1.2 The changing role of airports</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og1.2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 13:11:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og1.2/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Airports continue to diversify their role in an effort to generate income. Are business meeting facilities the next step? Nigel Halpern, Anne Graham and Rob Davidson investigate.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In recent times developing commercial revenues has become more challenging for airports due to a combination of factors, such as increased competition from Internet shopping, restrictions on certain sales, such as tobacco, and new security procedures that have had an impact on the dwell time of passengers. Moreover, the global economic downturn has caused a reduction in passenger numbers while those that are travelling generally have less money to spend. This has meant that the share of revenue from non-aeronautical revenues actually peaked at 54% at the turn of the century and has subsequently declined slightly. Meanwhile, the pressures to control the level of aeronautical revenues are as strong as ever due to the poor financial health of many airlines and the rapid rise of the low-cost carrier sector.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Some of the more obvious solutions to growing commercial revenues, such as extending the merchandising space or expanding the variety of shopping opportunities, have already been tried to their limit at many airports. A more radical solution is to find new sources of commercial revenue within the terminal, and this has been explored by many airports over the last decade or so. As a result, many terminals are now much more than just shopping malls and offer an array of entertainment, leisure, and beauty and wellness facilities. At this stage of facilities provision, the airport also has the possibility of taking on the role of the final destination rather than merely a facilitator of access.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>At the same time, airports have been developing and expanding the range of services that they provide specifically for the business traveller in the terminal. This includes offering business centres that supply support services, meeting or conference rooms and other space for special events. Within this context, Jarach (2001 ] discusses how dedicated meetings facilities located within the terminal and managed directly by the airport operator may be regarded as an expansion of the concept of airline lounges or as a way to reconvert abandoned or underused areas of terminal buildings. Previously it was primarily airport hotels and other facilities offered in the surrounding area of the airport that had the potential to take on this role and become active as a business space (McNeill, 2009).&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>When an airport location can be promoted as a business venue, this may increase the overall appeal of the airport and help it become more competitive in both attracting and retaining airlines and their passengers. In particular, the presence of meeting facilities could become one of the determining factors taken into consideration when business people are choosing airlines and where they change their planes. This enhanced attractiveness itself may help to improve the airport operator^ financial position and future prospects, but clearly this will be dependent on the competitive advantage that the airport is able to achieve in comparison with other venues.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In 2011, an online airport survey was conducted and some of the areas investigated included the provision and use of meeting facilities at airports and the perceived role and importance of these facilities in generating income and raising passenger numbers. In total, there were responses from staff at 154 airports and 68% of these answered yes* to the question: Does your airport own and have meetings facilities available for hire? The existence of meeting facilities therefore seems high at airports. In addition, 28% of respondents that did not have meeting facilities stated that they were likely to invest in them during the next five years. The survey also asked to what extent respondents agreed or disagreed with a number of statements about the meeting facilities at their airport. 49% of respondents agreed that they have put more investment into them during recent years; 41% agreed that they would invest more in the immediate future. These are fairly high proportions considering the recent economic climate.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The survey also asked airports with meeting facilities to estimate what proportion of users are from the local area, i.e. within a 90-minute drive from the airport, or from abroad. Their findings show that meeting facilities provided by the majority of respondents tend to serve local versus non-local or foreign needs. 63% of respondents estimated that over 60% of users are from the local area. Only 3% estimated that over 80% of users are from abroad. It is therefore not surprising that the facilities are of limited importance when it comes to increasing use of flights at the airport: 16% of respondents estimated that none of the users of their meeting facilities use flights when travelling to or from them, while 56% estimated that 20% or fewer of the users of their facilities use flights.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="g">G&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The survey asked respondents with meeting facilities to estimate how much revenue their airport earned from its meeting facilities during the last financial year. Average revenue per airport was just $12,959. Meeting facilities are effectively a non-aeronautical source of airport revenue. Only 1% of respondents generated more than 20% non-aeronautical revenue from their meetings facilities; none generated more than 40%. Given the focus on local demand, it is not surprising that less than a third of respondents agreed that their meeting facilities support business and tourism development in their home region or country.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="h">H&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The findings of this study suggest that few airports provide meetings facilities as a serious commercial venture. It may be that, as owners of large property, space is available for meeting facilities at airports and could play an important role in serving the needs of the airport, its partners, and stakeholders such as government and the local community. Thus, while the local orientation means that competition with other airports is likely to be minimal, competition with local providers of meetings facilities is likely to be much greater.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R.OG1.3 IS PHOTOGRAPHY ART?</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og1.3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 13:11:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og1.3/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This may seem a pointless question today. Surrounded as we are by thousands of photographs, most of us take for granted that, in addition to supplying information and seducing customers, camera images also serve as decoration, afford spiritual enrichment, and provide significant insights into the passing scene. But in the decades following the discovery of photography, this question reflected the search for ways to fit the mechanical medium into the traditional schemes of artistic expression.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The much-publicized pronouncement by painter Paul Delaroche that the daguerreotype* signalled the end of painting is perplexing because this clever artist also forecast the usefulness of the medium for graphic artists in a letter written in 1839. Nevertheless, it is symptomatic of the swing between the outright rejection and qualified acceptance of the medium that was fairly typical of the artistic establishment. Discussion of the role of photography in art was especially spirited in France, where the internal policies of the time had created a large pool of artists, but it was also taken up by important voices in England. In both countries, public interest in this topic was a reflection of the belief that national stature and achievement in the arts were related.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the maze of conflicting statements and heated articles on the subject, three main positions about the potential of camera art emerged. The simplest, entertained by many painters and a section of the public, was that photographs should not be considered &amp;lsquo;art&amp;rsquo; because they were made with a mechanical device and by physical and chemical phenomena instead of by human hand and spirit； to some, camera images seemed to have more in common with fabric produced by machinery in a mill than with handmade creations fired by inspiration. The second widely held view, shared by painters, some photographers, and some critics, was that photographs would be useful to art but should not be considered equal in creativeness to drawing and painting. Lastly, by assuming that the process was comparable to other techniques such as etching and lithography, a fair number of individuals realized that camera images were or could be as significant as handmade works of art and that they might have a positive influence on the arts and on culture in general.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Artists reacted to photography in various ways. Many portrait painters 一 miniaturists in particular - who realized that photography represented the ‘handwriting on the wall’ became involved with daguerreotyping or 60 paper photography in an effort to save their careers； some incorporated it with painting, while others renounced painting altogether. Still other painters, the most prominent among them the French painter, Jean- Auguste-Dominique Ingres, began almost immediately to use photography to make a record of their own output and also to provide themselves with source material for poses and backgrounds, vigorously denying at the same time its influence on their vision or its claims as art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The view that photographs might be worthwhile to artists was enunciated in considerable detail by Lacan and Francis Wey. The latter, an art and literary critic, who eventually recognised that camera images could be inspired as well as informative, suggested that they would lead to greater naturalness in the graphic depiction of anatomy, clothing, likeness, expression, and landscape. By studying photographs, true artists, he claimed, would be relieved of menial tasks and become free to devote themselves to the more important spiritual aspects of their work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wey left unstated what the incompetent artist might do as an alternative, but according to the influential French critic and poet Charles Baudelaire, writing in response to an exhibition of photography in 1859, lazy and untalented painters would become photographers. Fired by a belief in art as an imaginative embodiment of cultivated ideas and dreams, Baudelaire regarded photography as &amp;lsquo;a very humble servant of art and science,； a medium largely unable to transcend &amp;rsquo;external reality&amp;rsquo;. For this critic, photography was linked with &amp;rsquo;the great industrial madness&amp;rsquo; of the time, which in his eyes exercised disastrous consequences on the spiritual qualities of life and art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eugene Delacroix was the most prominent of the French artists who welcomed photography as help-mate but recognized its limitations. Regretting that &amp;lsquo;such a wonderful invention&amp;rsquo; had arrived so late in his lifetime, he still took lessons in daguerreotyping, and both commissioned and collected photographs. Delacroix&amp;rsquo;s enthusiasm for the medium can be sensed in a journal entry noting that if photographs were used as they should be, an artist might &amp;lsquo;raise himself to heights that we do not yet know&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The question of whether the photograph was document or art aroused interest in England also. The most important statement on this matter was an unsigned article that concluded that while photography had a role to play, it should not be &amp;lsquo;constrained&amp;rsquo; into &amp;lsquo;competition&amp;rsquo; with art； a more stringent viewpoint led critic Philip Gilbert Hamerton to dismiss camera images as &amp;rsquo;narrow in range, emphatic in assertion, telling one truth for ten falsehoods5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These writers reflected the opposition of a section of the cultural elite in England and France to the &amp;lsquo;cheapening of art&amp;rsquo; which the growing acceptance and purchase of camera pictures by the middle class represented. Technology made photographic images a common sight in the shop windows of Regent Street and Piccadilly in London and the commercial boulevards of Paris. In London, for example, there were at the time some commercial establishments where portraits, landscapes, and photographic reproductions of works of art could be bought. This appeal to the middle class convinced the elite that photographs would foster a desire for realism instead of idealism, even though some critics recognized that the work of individual photographers might display an uplifting style and substance that was consistent with the defining characteristics of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the name given to the first commercially successful photographic images&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: R.OG2.1 The Flavor of Pleasure</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og2.1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 13:11:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og2.1/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When it comes to celebrating the flavor of food, our mouth gets all the credit But in truth, it is the nose that knows.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>No matter how much we talk about tasting our favorite flavors, relishing them really depends on a combined input from our senses that we experience through mouth, tongue and nose. The taste, texture, and feel of food are what we tend to focus on, but most important are the slight puffs of air as we chew our food - what scientists call &amp;lsquo;retronasal smell&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Certainly, our mouths and tongues have taste buds, which are receptors for the five basic flavors: sweet, salty, sour, bitter, and umami, or what is more commonly referred to as savory. But our tongues are inaccurate instruments as far as flavor is concerned. They evolved to recognise only a few basic tastes in order to quickly identify toxins, which in nature are often quite bitter or acidly sour.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All the complexity, nuance, and pleasure of flavor come from the sense of smell operating in the back of the nose. It is there that a kind of alchemy occurs when we breathe up and out the passing whiffs of our chewed food. Unlike a hound&amp;rsquo;s skull with its extra long nose, which evolved specifically to detect external smells, our noses have evolved to detect internal scents. Primates specialise in savoring the many millions of flavor combinations that they can create for their mouths.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Taste without retronasal smell is not much help in recognising flavor. Smell has been the most poorly understood of our senses, and only recently has neuroscience, led by Yale University&amp;rsquo;s Gordon Shepherd, begun to shed light on its workings. Shepherd has come up with the term &amp;rsquo;neurogastronomy&amp;rsquo; to link the disciplines of food science, neurology, psychology, and anthropology with the savory elements of eating, one of the most enjoyed of human experiences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In many ways, he is discovering that smell is rather like face recognition. The visual system detects patterns of light and dark and, building on experience, the brain creates a spatial map. It uses this to interpret the interrelationship of the patterns and draw conclusions that allow us to identify people and places. In the same way, we use patterns and ratios to detect both new and familiar flavors. As we eat, specialised receptors in the back of the nose detect the air molecules in our meals. From signals sent by the receptors, the brain understands smells as complex spatial patterns. Using these, as well as input from the other senses, it constructs the idea of specific flavors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This ability to appreciate specific aromas turns out to be central to the pleasure we get from food, much as our ability to recognise individuals is central to the pleasures of social life. The process is so embedded in our brains that our sense of smell is critical to our enjoyment of life at large. Recent studies show that people who lose the ability to smell become socially insecure, and their overall level of happiness plummets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Working out the role of smell in flavor interests food scientists, psychologists, and cooks alike. The relatively new discipline of molecular gastronomy, especially, relies on understanding the mechanics of aroma to manipulate flavor for maximum impact. In this discipline, chefs use their knowledge of the chemical changes that take place during cooking to produce eating pleasures that go beyond the &amp;lsquo;ordinary&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, whereas molecular gastronomy is concerned primarily with the food or &amp;lsquo;smell, molecules, neurogastronomy is more focused on the receptor molecules and the brain&amp;rsquo;s spatial images for smell. Smell stimuli form what Shepherd terms *odor objects&amp;rsquo;, stored as memories, and these have a direct link with our emotions. The brain creates images of unfamiliar smells by relating them to other more familiar smells. Go back in history and this was part of our survival repertoire; like most animals, we drew on our sense of smell, when visual information was scarce, to single out prey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thus the brain&amp;rsquo;s flavor-recognition system is a highly complex perceptual mechanism that puts all five senses to work in various combinations. Visual and sound cues contribute, such as crunching, as does touch, including the texture and feel of food on our lips and in our mouths. Then there are the taste receptors, and finally, the smell, activated when we inhale. The engagement of our emotions can be readily illustrated when we picture some of the wide- ranging facial expressions that are elicited by various foods - many of them hard-wired into our brains at birth. Consider the response to the sharpness of a lemon and compare that with the face that is welcoming the smooth wonder of chocolate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The flavor-sensing system, ever receptive to new combinations, helps to keep our brains active and flexible. It also has the power to shape our desires and ultimately our bodies. On the horizon we have the positive application of neurogastronomy: manipulating flavor to curb our appetites.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R.OG2.2 Dawn of the robots</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og2.2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 13:11:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og2.2/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>They’re already here 一 driving cars, vacuuming carpets and feeding hospital patients. They may not be walking, talking, human-like sentient beings, but they are clever&amp;hellip; and a little creepy.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>At first sight it looked like a typical suburban road accident. A Land Rover approached a Chevy Tahoe estate car that had stopped at a kerb; the Land Rover pulled out and tried to pass the Tahoe just as it started off again. There was a crack of fenders and the sound of paintwork being scraped, the kind of minor mishap that occurs on roads thousands of times every day. Normally drivers get out, gesticulate, exchange insurance details and then drive off. But not on this occasion. No one got out of the cars for the simple reason that they had no humans inside them; the Tahoe and Land Rover were being controlled by computers competing in November&amp;rsquo;s DARPA (the U.S. Defence Advanced Research Projects Agency) Urban Challenge.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The idea that machines could perform to such standards is startling. Driving is a complex task that takes humans a long time to perfect. Yet here, each car had its on-board computer loaded with a digital map and route plans, and was instructed to negotiate busy roads; differentiate between pedestrians and stationary objects; determine whether other vehicles were parked or moving off; and handle various parking manoeuvres, which robots turn out to be unexpectedly adept at. Even more striking was the fact that the collision between the robot Land Rover, built by researchers at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, and the Tahoe, fitted out by Cornell University Artificial Intelligence (Al) experts, was the only scrape in the entire competition. Yet only three years earlier, at DARPA&amp;rsquo;s previous driverless car race, every robot competitor 一 directed to navigate across a stretch of open desert 一 either crashed or seized up before getting near the finishing line.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>It is a remarkable transition that has clear implications for the car of the future. More importantly, it demonstrates how robotics sciences and Artificial Intelligence have progressed in the past few years 一 a point stressed by Bill Gates, the Microsoft boss who is a convert to these causes. ‘The robotics industry is developing in much the same way the computer business did 30 years ago,&amp;rsquo; he argues. As he points out, electronics companies make toys that mimic pets and children with increasing sophistication. ‘I can envision a future in which robotic devices will become a nearly ubiquitous part of our day-to-day lives/ says Gates. ‘We may be on the verge of a new era, when the PC will get up off the desktop and allow us to see, hear, touch and manipulate objects in places where we are not physically present.'&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>What is the potential for robots and computers in the near future? ‘The fact is we still have a way to go before real robots catch up with their science fiction counterparts,&amp;rsquo; Gates says. So what are the stumbling blocks? One key difficulty is getting robots to know their place. This has nothing to do with class or etiquette, but concerns the simple issue of positioning. Humans orient themselves with other objects in a room very easily. Robots find the task almost impossible. &amp;ldquo;Even something as simple as telling the difference between an open door and a window can be tricky for a robot,&amp;rsquo; says Gates. This has, until recently, reduced robots to fairly static and cumbersome roles.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>For a long time, researchers tried to get round the problem by attempting to re-create the visual processing that goes on in the human cortex. However, that challenge has proved to be singularly exacting and complex. So scientists have turned to simpler alternatives: ‘We have become far more pragmatic in our work,’ says Nello Cristianini, Professor of Artificial Intelligence at the University of Bristol in England and associate editor of the Journal of Artificial Intelligence Research. ‘We are no longer trying to re-create human functions. Instead, we are looking for simpler solutions with basic electronic sensors, for example. &amp;lsquo;This approach is exemplified by vacuuming robots such as the Electrolux Trilobite. The Trilobite scuttles around homes emitting ultrasound signals to create maps of rooms, which are remembered for future cleaning. Technology like this is now changing the face of robotics, says philosopher Ron Chrisley, director of the Centre for Research in Cognitive Science at the University of Sussex in England.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Last year, a new Hong Kong restaurant, Robot Kitchen, opened with a couple of sensor-laden humanoid machines directing customers to their seats. Each possesses a touch-screen on which orders can be keyed in. The robot then returns with the correct dishes. In Japan, University of Tokyo researchers recently unveiled a kitchen zandroid7 that could wash dishes, pour tea and make a few limited meals. The ultimate aim is to provide robot home helpers for the sick and the elderly, a key concern in a country like Japan where 22 percent of the population is 65 or older. Over US$1 billion a year is spent on research into robots that will be able to care for the elderly. &amp;lsquo;Robots first learn basic competence 一 how to move around a house without bumping into things. Then we can think about teaching them how to interact with humans,’ Chrisley said. Machines such as these take researchers into the field of socialised robotics: how to make robots act in a way that does not scare or offend individuals. ‘We need to study how robots should approach people, how they should appear. That is going to be a key area for future research,&amp;rsquo; adds Chrisley.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R.OG2.3 It's your choice! 一 Or is it really?</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og2.3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 13:11:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og2.3/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>As we move from the industrial age to the information age, societal demands on our mental capabilities are no less taxing ···&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>We are constantly required to process a wide range of information to make decisions. Sometimes, these decisions are trivial, such as what marmalade to buy. At other times, the stakes are higher, such as deciding which symptoms to report to the doctor. However, the fact that we are accustomed to processing large amounts of information does not mean that we are better at it (Chabris &amp;amp; Simons, 2009). Our sensory and cognitive systems have systematic ways of failing of which we are often, perhaps blissfully, unaware.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Imagine that you are taking a walk in your local city park when a tourist approaches you asking for directions. During the conversation, two men carrying a door pass between the two of you. If the person asking for directions had changed places with one of the people carrying the door, would you notice? Research suggests that you might not. Harvard psychologists Simons and Levi (1998) conducted a field study using this exact set-up and found that the change in identity went unnoticed by 7 (46.6%) of the 15 participants. This phenomenon has been termed ‘change blindness&amp;rsquo; and refers to the difficulty that observers have in noticing changes to visual scenes (e.g. the person swap), when the changes are accompanied by some other visual disturbance (e.g. the passing of the door).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the past decade, the change blindness phenomenon has been replicated many times. Especially noteworthy is an experiment by Davies and Hine (2007) who studied whether change blindness affects eyewitness identification. Specifically, participants were presented with a video enactment of a burglary. In the video, a man entered a house, walking through the different rooms and putting valuables into a knapsack. However, the identity of the burglar changed after the first half of the film while the initial burglar was out of sight. Out of the 80 participants, 49 (61%) did not notice the change of the burglar&amp;rsquo;s identity, suggesting that change blindness may have serious implications for criminal proceedings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To most of us, it seems bizarre that people could miss such obvious changes while they are paying active attention. However, to catch those changes, attention must be targeted to the changing feature. In the study described above, participants were likely not to have been expecting the change to happen, and so their attention may have been focused on the valuables the burglar was stealing, rather than the burglar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Drawing from change blindness research, scientists have come to the conclusion that we perceive the world in much less detail than previously thought (Johansson, Hall, &amp;amp; Sikstrom, 2008). Rather than monitoring all of the visual details that surround us, we seem to focus our attention only on those features that are currently meaningful or important, ignoring those that are irrelevant to our current needs and goals. Thus at any given time, our representation of the world surrounding us is crude and incomplete, making it possible for changes or manipulations to go undetected (Chabris &amp;amp; Simons, 2010).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Given the difficulty people have in noticing changes to visual stimuli, one may wonder what would happen if these changes concerned the decisions people make. To examine choice blindness, Hall and colleagues (2010) invited supermarket customers to sample two different kinds of jams and teas. After participants had tasted or smelled both samples, they indicated which one they preferred. Subsequently, they were purportedly given another sample of their preferred choice. On half of the trials, however, these were samples of the non-chosen jam or tea. As expected, only about one-third of the participants detected this manipulation. Based on these findings, Hall and colleagues proposed that choice blindness is a phenomenon that occurs not only for choices involving visual material, but also for choices involving gustatory and olfactory information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, the phenomenon has also been replicated for choices involving auditory stimuli (Sauerland, Sagana, &amp;amp; Otgaar, 2012). Specifically, participants had to listen to three pairs of voices and decide for each pair which voice they found more sympathetic or more criminal. The voice was then presented again; however, the outcome was manipulated for the second voice pair and participants were presented with the non-chosen voice. Replicating the findings by Hall and colleagues, only 29% of the participants detected this change.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Merckelbach, Jelicic, and Pieters (2011) investigated choice blindness for intensity ratings of one&amp;rsquo;s own psychological symptoms. Their participants had to rate the frequency with which they experienced 90 common symptoms (e.g. anxiety, lack of concentration, stress, headaches etc.) on a 5-point scale. Prior to a follow-up interview, the researchers inflated ratings for two symptoms by two points. For example, when participants had rated their feelings of shyness, as 2 (i.e. occasionally), it was changed to 4 (i.e. all the time). This time, more than half (57%) of the 28 participants were blind to the symptom rating escalation and accepted it as their own symptom intensity rating. This demonstrates that blindness is not limited to recent preference selections, but can also occur for intensity and frequency.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Together, these studies suggest that choice blindness can occur in a wide variety of situations and can have serious implications for medical and judicial outcomes. Future research is needed to determine how, in those situations, choice blindness can be avoided.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R.OG3.1 SECRETS OF THE SWARM</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og3.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og3.1/</guid><description>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Insects, birds and fish tend to be the creatures that humans feel furthest from.Unlike many mammals they do not engage in human-like behaviour.The way they swarm or flock together does not usually get good press coverage either: marching like worker ants might be a common simile for city commuters, but it&amp;rsquo;s a damning, not positive, image.Yet a new school of scientific theory suggests that these swarms might have a lot to teach us.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>American author Peter Miller explains,&amp;rsquo;l used to think that individual ants knew where they were going,and what they were supposed to do when they got there.But Deborah Gordon, a biologist at Stanford University, showed me that nothing an ant does makes any sense except in terms of the whole colony.Which makes you wonder if, as individuals, we don &amp;rsquo;t serve a similar function for the companies where we work or the communities where we live.&amp;lsquo;Ants are not intelligent by themselves.Yet as a colony, they make wise decisions.And as Gordon discovered during her research, there&amp;rsquo;s no one ant making decisions or giving orders.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Take food collecting, for example.No ant decides, &amp;lsquo;There&amp;rsquo;s lots of food around today; lots of ants should go out to collect it.&amp;lsquo;Instead, some forager ants go out, and as soon as they find food, they pick it up and come back to the nest.At the entrance, they brush past reserve foragers, sending a &amp;lsquo;go out&amp;rsquo; signal.The faster the foragers come back, the more food there is and the faster other foragers go out, until gradually the amount of food being brought back diminishes.An organic calculation has been made to answer the question, &amp;lsquo;How many foragers does the colony need today?&amp;lsquo;And if something goes wrong - a hungry lizard prowling around for an ant snack, for instance - then a rush of ants returning without food sends waiting reserves a‘Don&amp;rsquo;t go out&amp;rsquo; signal.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>But could such decentralised control work in a human organisation? Miller visited a Texas gas company that has successfully applied formulas based on ant colony behaviour to‘optimise its factories and route its trucks&amp;rsquo;.He explains,&amp;rsquo;lf ant colonies had worked out a reliable way to identify the best routes between their nest and food sources, the company managers figured, why not take advantage of that knowledge?&amp;lsquo;So they came up with a computer model, based on the self-organising principles of an ant colony.Data is fed into the model about deliveries needing to be made the next day, as well as things like weather conditions, and it produces a simulation determining the best route for the delivery lorries to take.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Miller explains that he first really understood the impact that swarm behaviour could have on humans when he read a study of honeybees by Tom Seeley, a biologist at Cornell University.The honeybees choose as a group which new nest to move to.First, scouts fly off to investigate multiple sites.When they return they do a &amp;lsquo;waggle dance&amp;rsquo; for their spot, and other scouts will then fly off and investigate it.Many bees go out, but none tries to compare all sites.Each reports back on just one.The more they liked their nest, the more vigorous and lengthy their waggle dance and the more bees will choose to visit it.Gradually the volume of bees builds up towards one site; it&amp;rsquo;s a system that ensures that support for the best site snowballs and the decision is made in the most democratic way.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Humans, too, can make clever decisions through diversity of knowledge and a little friendly competition. &amp;lsquo;The best example of shared decision-making that I witnessed during my research was a town meeting I attended in Vermont,where citizens met face-to-face to debate their annual budget,&amp;rsquo; explains Miller. &amp;lsquo;For group decision-making to work well, you need away to sort through the various options they propose; and you need a mechanism to narrow down these options.‘Citizens in Vermont control their municipal affairs by putting forward proposals, or backing up others&amp;rsquo; suggestions, until a consensus is reached through a vote.As with the bees, the broad sampling of options before a decision is made will usually result in a compromise acceptable to all.The &amp;lsquo;wisdom of the crowd&amp;rsquo; makes clever decisions for the good of the group - and leaves citizens feeling represented and respected.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="g">G&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Internet is also an area where we are increasingly exhibiting swarm behaviour,without any physical contact.Miller compares a wiki website, for example, to a termite mound.Indirect collaboration is the key principle behind information-sharing web sites, just as it underlies the complex constructions that termites build.Termites do not have an architect&amp;rsquo;s blueprint or a grand construction scheme.They simply sense changes in their environment,as for example when the mound&amp;rsquo;s wall has been damaged, altering the circulation of air.They go to the site of the change and drop a grain of soil.When the next termite finds that grain,they drop theirs too.Slowly, without any kind of direct decision-making, a new wall is built.A termite mound, in this way, is rather like a wiki website.Rather than meeting up and talking about what we want to post online,we just add to what someone - maybe a stranger on the other side of the world - already wrote.This indirect knowledge and skill-sharing is now finding its way into the corridors of power.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R.OG3.2 High Speed, High Rise</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og3.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og3.2/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A Chinese entrepreneur has figured out a way to manufacture 30-story, earthquake-proof skyscrapers that snap together in just 15 days.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Zhang Yue is founder and chairman of Broad Sustainable Building (otherwise known as &amp;lsquo;Broad&amp;rsquo;) who, on 1 January, 2012, released a time-lapse video of its 30-story achievement. It shows construction workers buzzing around like gnats while a clock in the corner of the screen marks the time. In just 360 hours, a 100-metre-tall tower called the T30 rises from an empty site to overlook Hunan&amp;rsquo;s Xiang River.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the end of the video, the camera spirals around the building overhead as the Broad logo appears on the screen: a lowercase b that wraps around itself in an imitation of &lt;a href="mailto:the@symbol.The">the@symbol.The&lt;/a> company is in the process of franchising its technology to partners in India, Brazil, and Russia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What it is selling is the world&amp;rsquo;s first standardized skyscraper and with it, Zhang aims to turn Broad into the McDonald&amp;rsquo;s of the sustainable building industry.When asked why he decided to start a construction company,Zhang replies, &amp;lsquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not a construction company.It&amp;rsquo;s a structural revolution.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>So far,Broad has built 16 structures in China,plus another in Cancun. They are fabricated at two factories in Hunan, roughly an hour&amp;rsquo;s drive from Broad Town,the sprawling headquarters.The floors and ceilings of the skyscrapers are built in sections, each measuring 15.6 by 3.9 meters with a depth of 45 centimeters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pipes and ducts for electricity,water and waste are threaded through each floor module while it is still in the factory.The client&amp;rsquo;s choice of flooring is also pre-installed on top.Standardized truckloads carry two modules each to the site with the necessary columns, bolts and tools to connect them stacked on top of each other.Once they arrive at the location, each section is lifted by crane directly to the top of the building, which is assembled like toy Lego bricks.Workers use the materials on the module to quickly connect the pipes and wires.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The unique column design has diagonal bracing at each end and tabs that bolt into the floors above and below.In the final step, heavily insulated exterior walls and windows are slotted in by crane.The result is far from pretty but the method is surprisingly safe - and phenomenally fast.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Zhang attributes his success to his creativity and to his outsider perspective on technology.He started out as an art student in the 1980s, but in 1988,Zhang left the art world to found Broad.The company started out as a maker of non-pressurized boilers.His senior vice-president, Juliet Jiang, says, &amp;lsquo;He made his fortune on boilers. He could have kept doing this business, but &amp;hellip;he saw the need for nonelectric air-conditioning.&amp;lsquo;Towards the end of the decade, China&amp;rsquo;s economy was expanding past the capacity of the nation&amp;rsquo;s electricity grid, she explains.Power shortages were becoming a serious obstacle to growth.Large air-conditioning (AC) units fueled by natural gas could help companies ease their electricity load, reduce overheads, and enjoy more reliable climate control into the bargain.Today, Broad has units operating in more than 70 countries, in some of the largest buildings and airports on the planet.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>For two decades, Zhang&amp;rsquo;s AC business boomed.But a couple of events conspired to change his course.The first was that Zhang became an environmentalist.The second was the earthquake that hit China&amp;rsquo;s Sichuan Province in 2008, causing the collapse of poorly constructed buildings.Initially, he says, he tried to convince developers to refit existing buildings to make them both more stable and more sustainable, but he had little success.So Zhang drafted his own engineers and started researching how to build cheap, environmentally friendly structures that could also withstand an earthquake.Within six months of starting his research,Zhang had given up on traditional methods.He was frustrated by the cost of hiring designers and specialists for each new structure.The best way to cut costs, he decided, was to take building to the factory.But to create a factory-built skyscraper,Broad had to abandon the principles by which skyscrapers are typically designed.The whole load-bearing structure had to be different.To reduce the overall weight of the building, it used less concrete in the floors; that in turn enabled it to cut down on structural steel.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Around the world, prefabricated and modular buildings are gaining in popularity.But modular and prefabricated buildings elsewhere are, for the most part, low-rise.Broad is alone in applying these methods to skyscrapers.For Zhang, the environmental savings alone justify the effort.According to Broad&amp;rsquo;s numbers, a traditional high-rise will produce about 3,000 tons of construction waste, while a Broad building will produce only 25 tons.Traditional buildings also require 5,000 tons of water onsite to build, while Broad buildings use none.The building process is also less dangerous.Elevator systems - the base, rails, and machine room - can be installed at the factory, eliminating the risk of injury.And instead of shipping an elevator car to the site in pieces, Broad orders a finished car and drops it into the shaft by crane.In the future, elevator manufacturers are hoping to preinstall the doors, completely eliminating any chance that a worker might fall. &amp;lsquo;Traditional construction is chaotic,&amp;rsquo; he says.We took construction and moved it into the factory.&amp;lsquo;According to Zhang, his buildings will help solve the many problems of the construction industry and what&amp;rsquo;s more, they will be quicker and cheaper to build.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R.OG3.3 When conversations flow</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og3.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og3.3/</guid><description>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>We spend a large part of our daily life talking with other people and, consequently, we are very accustomed to the art of conversing.But why do we feel comfortable in conversations that have flow, but get nervous and distressed when a conversation is interrupted by unexpected silences? To answer this question we will first look at some of the effects of conversational flow.Then we will explain how flow can serve different social needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The positive consequences of conversational flow show some similarities with the effects of &amp;lsquo;processing fluency&amp;rsquo;.Research has shown that processing fluency - the ease with which people process information - influences peoples judgments across a broad range of social dimensions.For instance, people feel that when something is easily processed,it is more true or accurate.Moreover, they have more confidence in their judgments regarding information that came to them fluently, and they like things that are easy to process more than things that are difficult to process.Research indicates that a speaker is judged to be more knowledgeable when they answer questions instantly; responding with disfluent speech markers such as &amp;lsquo;uh&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;um&amp;rsquo; or simply remaining silent for a moment too long can destroy that positive image.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>One of the social needs addressed by conversational flow is the human need for &amp;lsquo;synchrony&amp;rsquo;- to be &amp;lsquo;in sync&amp;rsquo; or in harmony with one another.Many studies have shown how people attempt to synchronize with their partners,by coordinating their behavior.This interpersonal coordination underlies a wide array of human activities, ranging from more complicated ones like ballroom dancing to simply walking or talking with friends.In conversations, interpersonal coordination is found when people adjust the duration of their utterances and their speech rate to one another so that they can enable turn-taking to occur, without talking over each other or experiencing awkward silences.Since people are very well-trained in having conversations,they are often able to take turns within milliseconds, resulting in a conversational flow of smoothly meshed behaviors. A lack of flow is characterized by interruptions, simultaneous speech or mutual silences.Avoiding these features is important for defining and maintaining interpersonal relationships.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The need to belong has been identified as one of the most basic of human motivations and plays a role in many human behaviors.That conversational flow is related to belonging may be most easily illustrated by the consequences of flow disruptions.What happens when the positive experience of flow is disrupted by, for instance, a brief silence? We all know that silences can be pretty awkward, and research shows that even short disruptions in conversational flow can lead to a sharp rise in distress levels.In movies, silences are often used to signal non-compliance or confrontation (Piazza,2006).Some researchers even argue that &amp;lsquo;silencing someone&amp;rsquo; is one of the most serious forms of exclusion.Group membership is of elementary importance to our wellbeing and because humans are very sensitive to signals of exclusion, a silence is generally taken as a sign of rejection.In this way, a lack of flow in a conversation may signal that our relationship is not as solid as we thought it was.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Another aspect of synchrony is that people often try to validate their opinions to those of others.That is, people like to see others as having similar ideas or worldviews as they have themselves, because this informs people that they are correct and their worldviews are justified.One way in which people can justify their worldviews is by assuming that,as long as their conversations run smoothly,their interaction partners probably agree with them.This idea was tested by researchers using video observations.Participants imagined being one out of three people in a video clip who had either a fluent conversation or a conversation in which flow was disrupted by a brief silence.Except for the silence, the videos were identical.After watching the video, participants were asked to what extent the people in the video agreed with each other.Participants who watched the fluent conversation rated agreement to be higher than participants watching the conversation that was disrupted by a silence, even though participants were not consciously aware of the disruption.It appears that the subjective feeling of being out of sync informs people of possible disagreements, regardless of the content of the conversation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Because people are generally so well-trained in having smooth conversations,any disruption of this flow indicates that something is wrong, either interpersonally or within the group as a whole.Consequently,people who do not talk very easily may be incorrectly understood as being less agreeable than those who have no difficulty keeping up a conversation.On a societal level, one could even imagine that a lack of conversational flow may hamper the integration of immigrants who have not completely mastered the language of their new country yet.In a similar sense, the ever-increasing number of online conversations may be disrupted by misinterpretations and anxiety that are produced by insuperable delays in the Internet connection.Keeping in mind the effects of conversational flow for feelings of belonging and validation may help one to be prepared to avoid such misunderstandings in future conversations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R.OG4.1 South Pole Adventurer</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og4.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og4.1/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In the race to the South Pole,there was a Japanese team attempting to be first,led by heroic explorer Nobu Shirase.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>FOR a few weeks in January 1912,Antarctica was full of explorers.Norwegian Roald Amundsen had reached the South Pole on14 December and was speeding back to the coast.On 17 January,Robert Scott and the men of the British Antarctic expedition had arrived at the pole to find they had been beaten to it.Just then, a third man arrived; Japanese explorer Nobu Shirase.However; his part in one of the greatest adventure stories of the 20th century is hardly known outside his own country, even by fellow explorers.Yet as Scott was nearing the pole and with the rest of the world still unaware of Amundsen&amp;rsquo;s triumph,Shirase and his team sailed into Antarctica&amp;rsquo;s Bay of Whales in the smallest ship ever to try its luck in these dangerous waters.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Since boyhood Shirase had dreamed of becoming a polar explorer.Like Amundsen,he initially set his sights on the North Pole.But after the American Robert Peary clam,to have reached it in 1909,both men hastily altered their plans.Instead they would aim for the last big prize: the South Pole.In January 1910, Shirase put his plans before Japanese government officials,promising to raise the flag at the South Pole within three years.For many of them, the question wasn&amp;rsquo;t could he do it but why would it be worth doing? 15 years earlier the International Geographical Congress had said that as the last unknown continent the Antarctic offered the chance to add to knowledge in almost every branch of science.So, like the British，Shirase presented his expedition as a search for knowledge: he would bring back fossils,make meteorological measurements and explore unknown parts of the continent.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The response from the government was cool,however,and Shirase struggled to raise funds.Fortunately, a few months later;Japan&amp;rsquo;s former prime minister Shigenobu Okuma came to Shirase&amp;rsquo;s rescue.With Okuma&amp;rsquo;s backing, Shirase got together just enough money to buy and equip a small ship.He eventually acquired a scientist, too,called Terutaro Takeda.At the end of November 1910, his ship the Kainan Maru finally left Tokyo with 27 men and 28 Siberian dogs on board.Before leaving, Shirase confidently outlined his plans to the media.He would sail to New Zealand, then reach Antarctica in February, during the southern summer, and then proceed to the pole the following spring.This was not to be, however.Bad weather delayed the expedition and they didn&amp;rsquo;t reach New Zealand until 8 February; Amundsen and Scott had already been in Antarctica for a month,preparing for winter.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In New Zealand local reporters were astonished: the ship was half the size of Amundsen&amp;rsquo;s ship.True, it was reinforced with iron plate and extra wood, but the ship had only the feeblest engine to help force its way through ice.Few doubted Shirase&amp;rsquo;s courage,but most reckoned the expedition to be ill-prepared as the Japanese had only lightweight sledges for transport across the ice, made of bamboo and wood.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>But Shirase&amp;rsquo;s biggest challenge was time.Antarctica is only accessible by sea for a few weeks in summer and expeditions usually aimed to arrive in January or February. &amp;lsquo;Even with their determination and daring, our Japanese friends are running it rather fine,&amp;rsquo; wrote local reporters.Nevertheless, on 11 February the Kainan Maru left New Zealand and sailed straight into the worst weather the captain had ever seen.Then, on 6 March, they approached the coastline of Antarctica&amp;rsquo;s Ross Sea, looking for a place to land.The ice began to close in,threatening to trap them for the winter; an experience no one was likely to survive.With a remarkable piece of seamanship, the captain steered the ship out of the ice and turned north.They would have to wait out the winter in a warmer climate.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A year later than planned,Shirase and six men finally reached Antarctica.Catching up with Scott or Amundsen was out of the question and he had said he would stick to science this time.Yet Shirase still felt the pull of the pole and eventually decided he would head southward to experience the thrills and hardships of polar exploration he had always dreamed of.With provisions for 20 days, he and four men would see how far they could get.Shirase set off on 20 January 1912 with Takeda and two dog handlers, leaving two men at the edge of the ice shelf to make meteorological measurements.For a week they struggled through one blizzard after another, holing up in their tents during theworst of the weather.The temperature fell to-25C,and frostbite claimed some of the dogs.On 26 January, Shirase estimated there were enough provisions to continue for two more days.Two days later, he announced it was time to turn back.Takeda calculated they had reached 80° 5 south and had travelled 250 kilometres.The men hoisted the Japanese flag.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="g">G&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>On 3 February, all the men were heading home.The ship reached Tokyo in June 1912- and Shirase was greeted like a hero despite the fact that he never reached the pole.Nor did he contribute much to science - but then nor did Amundsen, whose only interest was in being first to the pole.Yet Shirase&amp;rsquo;s expedition was heroic.They travelled beyond 80°south,one of only four teams to have gone so far south at the time.Furthermore, they did it all without the advantages of the other teams and with no previous experience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R.OG4.2 The rise of the agribots</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og4.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og4.2/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The use of robots and automation in the farming industry.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The next time you stand at the supermarket checkout,spare a thought for the farmers who helped fill your shopping basket as life is hard for them right now.&amp;ldquo;This, in turn, inevitably means bigger grocery bills for consumers, and greater hardship for the millions in countries where food shortages are a matter of life and death.Worse,studies suggest that the world will need twice as much food by 2050.Yet while farmers must squeeze more out of the land, they must also address the necessity of reducing their impact on the soil, waterways and atmosphere.All this means rethinking how agriculture is practiced, and taking automation to a whole new level.On the new model farms of the future, precision will be key.Why dose a whole field with chemicals if you can spray only where they are needed?&amp;ldquo;Each plant could get exactly the right amount of everything, no more or less, an approach that could slash chemical use and improve yields in one move.&amp;ldquo;But this is easier said than done; the largest farms in Europe and the U.S. can cover thousands of acres.That&amp;rsquo;s why automation is key to precision farming.Specifically, say agricultural engineers,precision farming needs robot farmers.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>One day, we might see fields with ‘agribots&amp;rsquo;(agricultural robots) that can identify individual seedlings and encourage them along with drops of fertilizer.&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Other machines would distinguish problem weeds from crops and eliminate them with shots from high-power lasers or a microdot of pesticide.&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;These machines will also be able to identify and harvest all kinds of vegetables.&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;More than a century of mechanization has already turned farming into an industrial-scale activity in much of the world, with farms that grow cereals being the most heavily automated.&amp;ldquo;But a variety of other crops, including oranges and tomatoes destined to become processed foods, are also picked mechanically, albeit to a slightly lesser extent.Yet the next wave of autonomous farm machinery is already at work.&amp;ldquo;You probably haven&amp;rsquo;t even noticed, for these robots are disguised as tractors.&amp;ldquo;Many are self-steering, use GPS to cross a field, and can even &amp;rsquo;talk&amp;rsquo; to their implements - a plough or sprayer, for example.And the implements can talk back, telling the tractor that it&amp;rsquo;s going too fast or needs to move to the left.This kind of communication is also being developed in other farm vehicles.A new system allows a combine harvester, say, to send a call over to a tractor-trailer so the driver can unload the grain as and when necessary.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>However, when fully autonomous systems take to the field, they&amp;rsquo;ll look nothing like tractors.With their enormous size and weight, today&amp;rsquo;s farm machines have significant downsides:they compact the soil, reducing porosity and killing beneficial life, meaning crops don&amp;rsquo;t grow so well.&amp;ldquo;Simon Black more, who researches agricultural technology at Harper Adams University College in England believes that fleets of lightweight autonomous robots have the potential to solve this problem and that replacing brute force with precision is key.&amp;ldquo;A seed only needs one cubic centimeter of soil to grow.If we cultivate just that we only put tiny amounts of energy in and the plants still grow nicely.&amp;lsquo;There is another reason why automation may be the way forward according to Eldert van Henten, a robotics researcher at Wageningen University in the Netherlands. &amp;lsquo;While the population is growing and needs to be fed, a rapidly shrinking number of people are willing to work in agriculture,&amp;rsquo; he points out.Other researchers such as Linda Calvin, an economist at the U.S.Department of Agriculture, and Philip Martin at the University of California, predict how US farms might fare.Calvin and costs have led to the adoption of labour-saving farm technology in the past, citing the raisin industry as an example.In 2000, a bumper harvest crashed prices and, with profits squeezed, farmers looked for a solution.With labour one of their biggest costs-42 percent of production expenses on U.S. farms, on average- they started using a mechanical harvester adapted from a machine used by wine makers.By 2017,almost half of California&amp;rsquo;s raisins were mechanically harvested and a labour force once numbering 50,000 had shrunk to 30,000.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>As well as having an impact on the job market,the widespread adoption of agribots might bring changes at the supermarket.&amp;ldquo;Lewis Holloway,who studies agriculture at the University of Hull, UK, says that robotic milking is likely to influence the genetics of dairy herds as farmers opt for &amp;lsquo;robot-friendly&amp;rsquo; cows, with udder shape, and even attitudes, suited to automated milking.&amp;ldquo;Similarly, he says, it&amp;rsquo;s conceivable that agribots could influence what fruit or vegetable varieties get to the shops, since farmers may prefer to grow those with, say, leaf shapes that are easier for their robots to discriminate from weeds.Almost inevitably, these machines will eventually alter the landscape, too.The real tipping point for robot agriculture will come when farms are being designed with agribotsin mind, says Salah Sukkarieh, a robotics researcher at the Australian Center for Field Robotics,Sydney.This could mean a return to smaller fields, with crops planted in grids rather than rows and fruit trees pruned into two-dimensional shapes to make harvesting easier.This alien terrain tended by robots is still a while away, he says &amp;lsquo;but it will happen.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R.OG4.3 Homer's Literary Legacy</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og4.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og4.3/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Why was the work of Homer, famous author of ancient Greece, so full of cliches?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Until the last tick of history&amp;rsquo;s clock, cultural transmission meant oral transmission and poetry, passed from mouth to ear, was the principal medium of moving information across space and from one generation to the next.&amp;ldquo;Oral poetry was not simply a way of telling lovely or important stories, or of flexing the imagination.It was, argues the classicist Eric Have lock, a &amp;ldquo;massive repository of useful knowledge, a sort of encyclopedia of ethics,politics, history and technology which the effective citizen was required to learn as the core of his educational equipment&amp;rdquo;. The great oral works transmitted a shared cultural heritage, held in common not on bookshelves, but in brains. ln India, an entire class of priests was charged with memorizing the Vedas with perfect fidelity.In pre-Islamic Arabia,people known as Rawis were often attached to poets as official memorizers. The Buddha&amp;rsquo;s teachings were passed down in an unbroken chain of oral tradition for four centuries until they were committed to writing in Sri Lanka in the first century B.C.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The most famous of the Western tradition&amp;rsquo;s oral works,and the first to have been systematically studied, were Homer&amp;rsquo;s Odyssey and lliad.These two poems - possibly the first to have been written down in the Greek alphabet - had long been held up as literary archetypes. However, even as they were celebrated as the models to which all literature should aspire, Homer&amp;rsquo;s master works had also long been the source of scholarly unease.The earliest modern critics sensed that they were somehow qualitatively different from everything that came after - even a little strange.For one thing, both poems were oddly repetitive in the way they referred to characters. Odysseus was always &amp;ldquo;clever Odysseus&amp;rdquo;.Dawn was always “&amp;ldquo;rosy-fingered&amp;rdquo;. Why would someone write that? Sometimes the epithets seemed completely off-key. Why call the murderer of Agamemnon&amp;quot;blameless Aegisthos&amp;rdquo;?Why refer to&amp;quot;swift-footed Achilles&amp;quot; even when he was sitting down?Or to &amp;ldquo;laughing Aphrodite&amp;rdquo; even when she was in tears?In terms of both structure and theme, the Odyssey and lliad were also oddly formulaic, to the point of predictability.The same narrative units -gathering armies,heroic shields, challenges between rivals - pop up again and again, only with different characters and different circumstances.In the context of such finely spun,deliberate masterpieces, these quirks* seemed hard to explain.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>At the heart of the unease about these earliest works of literature were two fundamental questions: first, how could Greek literature have been born ex nihilo* with two masterpieces? Surely a few less perfect stories must have come before, and yet these two were among the first on record.And second, who exactly was their author? Or was it authors?There were no historical records of Homer, and no trustworthy biography of the man exists beyond a few self-referential hints embedded in the texts themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Jean-Jacques Rousseau was one of the first modern critics to suggest that Homer might not have been an author in the contemporary sense of a single person who sat down and wrote a story and then published it for others to read.In his 1781 Essay on the Origin of Languages, the Swiss philosopher suggested that the Odyssey and lliad might have been&amp;quot;written only in men&amp;rsquo;s memories. Somewhat later they were laboriously collected in writing&amp;quot; - though that was about as far as his enquiry into the matter went.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In 1795, the German philologist Friedrich August Wolf argued for the first time that not only were Homer&amp;rsquo;s works not written down by Homer, but they weren&amp;rsquo;t even by Homer.They were, rather, a loose collection of songs transmitted by generations of Greek bards*,and only redacted* in their present form at some later date.In 1920, an eighteen-year-old scholar named Milman Parry took up the question of Homeric authorship as his Master&amp;rsquo;s thesis at the University of California, Berkeley.He suggested that the reason Homer&amp;rsquo;s epics seemed unlike other literature was because they were unlike other literature.Parry had discovered what Wood and Wolf had missed: the evidence that the poems had been transmitted orally was right there in the text itself.All those stylistic quirks, including the formulaic and recurring plot elements and the bizarrely repetitive epithets -&amp;ldquo;clever Odysseus&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;gray-eyed Athena&amp;rdquo;- that had always perplexed readers were actually like thumbprints left by a potter: material evidence of how the poems had been crafted.They were mnemonic* aids that helped the bard(s) fit the meter and pattern of the line, and remember the essence of the poems.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The greatest author of antiquity was actually, Parry argued, just&amp;quot;one of a long tradition of oral poets that &amp;hellip; composed wholly without the aid of writing&amp;quot;. Parry realised that if you were setting out to create memorable poems, the Odyssey and the liad were exactly the kind of poems you&amp;rsquo;d create. It&amp;rsquo;s said that cliches* are the worst sin a writer can commit,but to an oral bard, they were essential.The very reason that cliches so easily seep into our speech and writing - their insidious memorability - is exactly why they played suchan important role in oral storytelling.The principles that the oral bards discovered as they sharpened their stories through telling and retelling were the same mnemonic principles that psychologists rediscovered when they began conducting their first scientific experiments on memory around the turn of the twentieth century.Words that rhyme are much more memorable than words that don&amp;rsquo;t, and concrete nouns are easier to remember than abstract ones.Finding patterns and structure in information is how our brains extract meaning from the world, and putting words to music and rhyme is a way of adding extra levels of pattern and structure to language.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R.OG5.1 Trees in trouble</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og5.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og5.1/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>What is causing the decline of the world&amp;rsquo;s giant forests?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Big trees are incredibly important ecologically.For a start, they sustain countless other species.They provide shelter for many animals, and their trunks and branches can become gardens, hung with green ferns, orchids and bromeliads, coated with mosses and draped with vines.With their tall canopies* basking in the sun, they capture vast amounts of energy.This allows them to produce massive crops of fruit,flowers and foliage that sustain much of the animal life in the forest.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Only a small number of tree species have the genetic capacity to grow really big.The mightiest are native to North America, but big trees grow all over the globe,from the tropics to the boreal forests of the high latitudes.To achieve giant stature, a tree needs three things: the right place to establish its seedling, good growing conditions and lots of time with low adult mortality*.&amp;ldquo;Disrupt any of these, and you can lose yourbiggest trees.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In some parts of the world, populations of big trees are dwindling because their seedlings cannot survive or grow.In southern India, for instance, an aggressive non-native shrub, Lantana camara, is invading the floor of many forests.Lantana grows so thickly that young trees often fail to take root.With no young trees to replace them, it is only a matter of time before most of the big trees disappear.Across much of northern Australia, gamba grass from Africa is overrunning native savannah woodlands.The grass grows up to four metres tall and burns fiercely,creating super-hot fires that cause catastrophic tree mortality.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Without the right growing conditions trees cannot get really big, and there is some evidence to suggest tree growth could slow in a warmer world, particularly in environments that are already warm.&amp;ldquo;Having worked for decades at La SelvaBiological Station in Puerto Viejo de Sarapiqui, Costa Rica, David and Deborah Clark and colleagues have shown that tree growth there declines markedly in warmer years.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;During the day, their photosynthesis* shuts down when it gets too warm,and at night they consume more energy because their metabolic rate increases, much as a reptile&amp;rsquo;s would when it gets warmer,&amp;ldquo;explains David Clark. With less energy produced in warmer years and more being consumed just to survive, there is even less energy available for growth.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Clarks&amp;rsquo; hypothesis, if correct, means tropical forests would shrink over time.The largest, oldest trees would progressively die off and tend not to be replaced.According to the Clarks, this might trigger a destabilisation of the climate; &amp;ldquo;as older trees die, forests would release some of their stored carbon into the atmosphere,prompting a vicious cycle of further warming, forest shrinkage and carbon emissions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Big trees face threats from elsewhere.&amp;ldquo;The most serious is increasing mortality,especially of mature trees.&amp;ldquo;Across much of the planet, forests of slow-growing ancient trees have been cleared for human use.In western North America,most have been replaced by monocultures of fast-growing conifers.Siberia&amp;rsquo;s forests are being logged at an incredible rate.Logging in tropical forests is selective but the timber cutters usually prioritise the biggest and oldest trees.In the Amazon, my colleagues and I found the mortality rate for the biggest trees had tripled in small patches of rainforest surrounded by pasture land.This happens for two reasons.First, as they grow taller,big trees become thicker and less flexible: when winds blow across the surrounding cleared land, there is nothing to stop their acceleration.When they hit the trees, the impact can snap them in half.Second, rainforest fragments dry out when surrounded by dry, hot pastures and the resulting drought can have devastating consequences:one four-year study has shown that death rates will double for smaller trees but will increase 4.5 times for bigger trees.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="g">G&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Particular enemies to large trees are insects and disease.Across vast areas of western North America, increasingly mild winters are causing massive outbreaks of bark beetle.These tiny creatures can kill entire forests as they tunnel their way through the inside of trees.In both North America and Europe,fungus-causing diseases such as Dutch elm disease have killed off millions of stately trees that once gave beauty to forests and cities.As a result of human activity, such enemies reach even the remotest corners of the world, threatening to make the ancient giants a thing of the past.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R.OG5.2 Whale Strandings</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og5.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og5.2/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Why do whales leave the ocean and become stuck on beaches?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>When the last stranded whale of a group eventually dies, the story does not end there.A team of researchers begins to investigate,collecting skin samples for instance, recording anything that could help them answer the crucial question: why?Theories abound, some more convincing than others.In recent years, navy sonar has been accused of causing certain whales to strand.It is known that noise pollution from offshore industry, shipping and sonar can impair underwater communication, but can it really drive whales onto our beaches?&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In 1998, researchers at the Pelagos Cetacean Research Institute, a Greek non-profit scientific group, linked whale strandings with low-frequency sonar tests being carried out by the North Atlantic Treaty Organisation (NATO).They recorded the stranding of 12 Cuvier&amp;rsquo;s beaked whales over 38.2 kilometres of coastline.NATO later admitted it had been testing new sonar technology in the same area at the time as the strandings had occurred.Mass&amp;rsquo; whale strandings involve four or more animals.Typically they all wash ashore together, but in mass atypical strandings (such as the one in Greece), the whales don&amp;rsquo;t strand as a group; they are scattered over a larger area.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>For humans, hearing a sudden loud noise might prove frightening, but it does not induce mass fatality.For whales, on the other hand,there is a theory on how sonar can kill.The noise can surprise the animal, causing it to swim too quickly to the surface.The result is decompression sickness, a hazard human divers know all too well.If a diver ascends too quickly from a high pressure underwater environment to a lower-pressure one, gases dissolved in blood and tissue expand and form bubbles.The bubbles block the flow of blood to vital organs,and can ultimately lead to death.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Plausible as this seems, it is still a theory and based on our more comprehensive knowledge of land-based animals.For this reason, some scientists are wary.Whale expert Karen Evans is one such scientist.Another is Rosemary Gales, a leading expert on whale strandings.She says sonar technology cannot always be blamed for mass strandings. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s a case-by-case situation.Whales have been stranding for a very long time -pre-sonar.&amp;ldquo;And when 80% of all Australian whale strandings occur around Tasmania, Gales and her team must continue in the search for answers.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>When animals beach next to each other at the same time, the most common cause has nothing to do with humans at all.They&amp;rsquo;re highly social creatures&amp;rdquo; says Gales. &amp;ldquo;When they mass strand -it&amp;rsquo;s complete panic and chaos.If one of the group strands and sounds the alarm, others will try to swim to its aid, and become stuck themselves.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Activities such as sonar testing can hint at when a stranding may occur, but if conservationists are to reduce the number of strandings, or improve rescue operations, they need information on where strandings are likely to occur as well.With this in mind, Ralph James, physicist at the University of Western Australia in Perth, thinks he may have discovered why whales turn up only on some beaches. In 1986 he went to Augusta, Western Australia, where more than 100 false killer whales had beached. I found out from chatting to the locals that whales had been stranding there for decades.So I asked myself,what is it about this beach?&amp;rdquo; From this question that James pondered over 20 years ago, grew the university&amp;rsquo;s Whale Stranding Analysis Project.Data has since revealed that all mass strandings around Australia occur on gently sloping sandy beaches, some with inclines of less than 0.5%. For whale species that depend on an echolocation system to navigate, this kind of beach spells disaster.Usually, as they swim, they make clicking noises, and the resulting sound waves are reflected in an echo and travel back to them.However, these just fade out on shallow beaches, so the whale doesn&amp;rsquo;t hear an echo and it crashes onto the shore.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="g">G&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>But that is not all.Physics, it appears, can help with the when as well as the where.The ocean is full of bubbles.Larger ones rise quickly to the surface and disappear, whilst smaller ones- called microbubbles - can last for days.It is these that absorb whale &amp;lsquo;clicks.&amp;lsquo;Rough weather generates more bubbles than usual,&amp;quot; James adds.So, during and after a storm, echolocating whales are essentially swimming blind.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="h">H&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Last year was a bad one for strandings in Australia.Can we predict if this - or any other year - will be any better? Some scientists believe we can.They have found trends which could be used to forecast &amp;lsquo;bad years&amp;rsquo; for strandings in the future.In 2005, a survey by Klaus Vanselow and Klaus Ricklefs of sperm whale strandings in the North Sea even found a correlation between these and the sunspot cycle,and suggested that changes in the Earth&amp;rsquo;s magnetic field might be involved.But others are sceptical.&amp;ldquo;Their study was interesting &amp;hellip; but the analyses they use were flawed on a number of levels,&amp;rdquo; says Evans.In the same year, she co-authored a study on Australian strandings that uncovered a completely different trend.&amp;ldquo;We analysed data from 1920 to 2002 &amp;hellip;and observed a clear periodicity in the number of whales stranded each year that coincides with a major climatic cycle.&amp;ldquo;To put it more simply, she says, in the years when strong westerly and southerly winds bring cool water rich in nutrients closer to the Australia coast, there is an increase in the number of fish.The whales follow.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="i">I&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>So what causes mass strandings? &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s probably many different components,&amp;rdquo; says James.And he is probably right. But the point is we now know what many of those components are.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R.OG5.3 Science in Space</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og5.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og5.3/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>How will NASA transform the International Space Station from a building site into a cutting-edge research laboratory?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A premier, world-class laboratory in low Earth orbit.That was how the National Aeronautics and Space Administration agency (NASA) sold the International Space Station (ISS) to the US Congress in 200I.Today no one can doubt the agency&amp;rsquo;s technological ambition.The most complex engineering project ever attempted has created an enormous set of interlinked modules that orbits the planet at more than 27,000 kilometres per hour. lt might be travelling fast but, say critics, as a lab it is going nowhere.So far, it has gone through $150 billion.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>So where should its future priorities lie?This question was addressed at the recent 1st annual ISS research and development conference in Colorado.Among the presenters was Satoshi lwase of Aichi Medical University in Japan who has spent several years developing an experiment that could help solve one of the key problems that humans will face in space: keeping our bodies healthy in weightlessness.One thing that physiologists have learned is that without gravity our bodies begin to lose strength, leaving astronauts with weakened bones, muscles and cardiovascular systems.To counter these effects on a long-duration mission to, say,Mars, astronauts will almost certainly need to create their own artificial gravity.This is where lwase comes in.He leads a team designing a centrifuge for humans.In their preliminary design, an astronaut is strapped into the seat of a machine that resembles an exercise bike.Pedalling provides a workout for the astronaut&amp;rsquo;s muscles and cardiovascular system, but it also causes the seat to rotate vertically around a central axis so the rider experiences artificial gravity while exercising.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The centrifuge project highlights the station&amp;rsquo;s potential as a research lab.Similar machines have flown in space aboard NASA&amp;rsquo;s shuttles, but they couldn&amp;rsquo;t be tested for long enough to prove whether they were effective.It&amp;rsquo;s been calculated that to properly assess a centrifuge&amp;rsquo;s impact on human physiology, astronauts would have to ride it for 30 minutes a day for at least two months.The only way to test this is in weightlessness,and the only time we have to do that is on the space station, says Laurence Young, a space medicine expert at the Massachusetts lnstitute of Technology.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>There are certainly plenty of ideas for other experiments: but many projects have yet to fly.Even if the centrifuge project gets the green light,it will have to wait another five years before the station&amp;rsquo;s crew can take a spin.Lengthy delays like this are one of the key challenges for NASA,according to an April 2011 report from the US National Academy of Sciences.Its authors said they were &amp;lsquo;deeply concerned&amp;rsquo; about the state of NASA&amp;rsquo;s science research, and made a number of recommendations.Besides suggesting that the agency reduces the time between approving experiments and sending them into space, it also recommended setting clearer research priorities.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>NASA has already begun to take action, hiring management consultants ProOrbis to develop a plan to cut through the bureaucracy.And Congress also directed NASA to hire an independent organisation,the Centre for the Advancement of Science in Space (CASIS), to help manage the station&amp;rsquo;s US lab facilities.One of CASIS&amp;rsquo;s roles is to convince public and private investors that science on the station is worth the spend because judged solely by the number of papers published, the ISS certainly seems poor value: research on the station has generated about 3,100 papers since 1998.The Hubble Space Telescope, meanwhile, has produced more than 11,300 papers in just over 20 years,yet it cost less than one-tenth of the price of the space station.Yet Mark Uhran, assistant associate administrator for the ISS,refutes the criticism that the station hasn&amp;rsquo;t done any useful research.He points to progress made on a salmonella vaccine, for example.To get the ISS research back on track,CASIS has examined more than I00 previous microgravity experiments to identify promising research themes.From this, it has opted to focus on life science and medical research,and recently called for proposals for experiments on muscle wasting, osteoporosis and the immune system.The organisation also maintains that the ISS should be used to develop products with commercial application and to test those that are either close to or already on the market.Investment from outside organisations is vital, saus Uhran, and a balance between academic and commercial research will help attract this.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The station needs to attract cutting-edge research, yet many scientists seem to have little idea what goes on aboard it. Jeanne DiFrancesco at ProOrbis conducted more than 200 interviews with people from organisations with potential interests in low gravity studies. Some were aware of the lSS but they didn&amp;rsquo;t know what&amp;rsquo;s going on up there, she says.Others know there&amp;rsquo;s science, but they don&amp;rsquo;t know what kind.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="g">G&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>According to Alan Stern, planetary scientist, the biggest public relations boost for the lSS may come from the privately funded space flight industry.Companies like SpaceX could help NASA and its partners when it comes to resupplying the ISS, as it suggests it can reduce launch costs by two-thirds.Virgin Atlantic&amp;rsquo;s SpaceShipTwo or Zero2Infinity&amp;rsquo;s high-altitude balloon could also boost the space station&amp;rsquo;s fortunes.They might not come close to the lSS&amp;rsquo;s orbit, yet Stern believes they will revolutionise the way we, the public, see space.Soon everyone will be dreaming of interplanetary travel again, he predicts.More importantly, scientists are already queuing for seats on these low-gravity space-flight services so they can collect data during a few minutes of weightlessness.This demand for low-cost spaceflight could eventually lead to a service running on a more frequent basis, giving researchers the chance to test their ideas before submitting a proposal for experiments on the lSS.Getting flight experience should help them win a slot on the station, says Stern.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R.OG6.1 Why Are Finland's Schools Successful?</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og6.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og6.1/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The country’s achievements in education have other nations doing their bomework.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>At Kirkkojarvi Comprehensive School in Espoo, a suburb west of Helsinki, Kari Louhivuori, the school&amp;rsquo;s principal, decided to try something extreme by Finnish standards.One of his sixth-grade students, a recent immigrant, was falling behind,resisting his teacher&amp;rsquo;s best efforts.So he decided to hold the boy back a year.Standards in the country have vastly improved in reading, math and science literacy over the past decade, in large part because its teachers are trusted to do whatever it takes to turn young lives around. &amp;rsquo;l took Besart on that year as my private student,&amp;rsquo; explains Louhivuoni.When he was not studying science, geography and math, Besart was seated next to Louhivuori&amp;rsquo;s desk, taking books from a tall stack, slowly reading one, then another, then devouring them by the dozens.By the end of the year, he had conquered his adopted country&amp;rsquo;s vowel-rich language and arrived at the realization that he could, in fact, learn.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>This tale of a single rescued child hints at some of the reasons for Finland&amp;rsquo;s amazing record of education success.The transformation of its education system began some 40 years ago but teachers had little idea it had been so successful until 2000.In this year, the first results from the Programme for International Student Assessment(PISA), a standardized test given to 15-year-olds in more than 40 global venues, revealed Finnish youth to be the best at reading in the world.Three years later, they led in math.By 2006, Finland was first out of the 57 nations that participate in science.In the latest PISA scores, the nation came second in science, third in reading and sixth in math among nearly half a million students worldwide.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>ln the United States, government officials have attempted to improve standards by introducing marketplace competition into public schools.In recent years, a group of wall Street financiers and philanthropists such as Bill Gates have put money behind private-sector ideas, such as charter schools, which have doubled in number in the past decade.President Obama, too,apparently thought competition was the answer.One policy invited states to compete for federal dollars using tests and other methods to measure teachers, a philosophy that would not be welcome in Finland.I think, in fact, teachers would tear off their shirts,&amp;rsquo; said Timo Heikkinen, a Helsinki principal with 24 years of teaching experience. lf you only measure the statistics, you miss the human aspect.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>There are no compulsory standardized tests in Finland,apart from one exam at the end of students&amp;rsquo; senior year in high school.There is no competition between students,schools or regions.Finland&amp;rsquo;s schools are publicly funded.The people in the government agencies running them,from national officials to local authorities, are educators rather than business people or politicians.Every school has the same national goals and draws from the same pool of university-trained educators.The result is that a Finnish child has a good chance of getting the same quality education no matter whether he or she lives in a rural village or a university town.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>lt&amp;rsquo;s almost unheard of for a child to show up hungry to school.Finland provides three years of maternity leave and subsidized day care to parents, and preschool for all five-year-olds, where the emphasis is on socializing.ln addition, the state subsidizes parents, paying them around 150 euros per month for every child until he or she turns 17.Schools provide food, counseling and taxi service if needed.Health care is even free for students taking degree courses.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Finland&amp;rsquo;s schools were not always a wonder.For the first half of the twentieth century, only the privileged got a quality education.But ln 1963, the Finnish Parliament made the bold decision to choose public education as the best means of driving the economy forward and out of recession.Public schools were organized into one system of comprehensive schools for ages 7 through 16.Teachers from all over the nation contributed to a national curriculum that provided guidelines, not prescriptions,for them to refer to.Besides Finnish and Swedish (the country&amp;rsquo;s second official language), children started learning a third language (English is a favorite) usually beginning at age nine.The equal distribution of equipment was next, meaning that all teachers had their fair share of teaching resources to aid learning.As the comprehensive schools improved, so did the upper secondary schools(grades 10 through 12).The second critical decision came in 1979, when it was required that every teacher gain a fifth-year Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in theory and practice,paid for by the state.From then on, teachers were effectively granted equal status with doctors and lawyers.Applicants began flooding teaching programs, not because the salaries were so high but because autonomous decision-making and respect made the job desirable.And as Louhivuori explains, &amp;ldquo;We have our own motivation to succeed because we love the work.'&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R.OG6.2 Australia's Lost Giants</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og6.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og6.2/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>What happened to Australia&amp;rsquo;s megafauna, the giant animals that once existed across this enormous continent?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In 1969, a fossil hunter named Rod Wells came to Naracoorte in South Australia to explore what was then known as Victoria Cave.Wells clawed through narrow passages, and eventually into a huge chamber.Its floor of red soil was littered with strange objects.It took Wells a moment to realize what he was looking at; the bones of thousands of creatures that must have fallen through holes in the ground above and become trapped.Some of the oldest belonged to mammals far larger than any found today in Australia.They were the ancient Australian megafauna - huge animals of the Pleistocene epoch.In boneyards across the continent, scientists have found the fossils of a giant snake, a huge flightless bird, and a seven foot kangaroo,to name but a few.Given how much ink has been spilled on the extinction of the dinosaurs, it&amp;rsquo;s a wonder that even more hasn&amp;rsquo;t been devoted to megafauna.Prehistoric humans never threw spears at Tyrannosaurus rex but really did hunt mammoths and mastodons.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The disappearance of megafauna in America - mammoths, saber-toothed cats,giant sloths, among others - happened relatively soon after the arrival of human beings, about 13,000 years ago.In the 1960s, paleoecologist Paul Martin developed what became known as the blitzkrieg hypothesis.Modern humans, Martin said, created havoc as they spread through the Americas, wielding spears to annihilate animals that had never faced a technological predator.But this period of extinction wasn&amp;rsquo;t comprehensive.North America kept its deer, black bears and a small type of bison, and South America its jaguars and llamas.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>What happened to Australia&amp;rsquo;s large animals is baffling.For years scientists blamed the extinctions on climate change.Indeed, Australia has been drying out for over a million years, and the megafauna were faced with a continent where vegetation began to disappear.Australian paleontologist Tim Flannery suggests that people,who arrived on the continent around 50,000 years ago, used fire to hunt, which led to deforestation.Here&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s certain, Flannery says.Something dramatic happened to Australia&amp;rsquo;s dominant land creatures - somewhere around 46,000 years ago, strikingly soon after the invasion of a tool-wielding, highly intelligent predator.In Flannery&amp;rsquo;s 1994 book called The Future Eaters, he sets out his thesis that human beings are a new kind of animal on the planet, and are in general, one prone to ruining ecosystems.Flannery&amp;rsquo;s book proved highly controversial.Some viewed it as critical of the Aborigines, who pride themselves on living in harmony with nature.The more basic problem with Flannery&amp;rsquo;s thesis is that there is no direct evidence that they killed any Australian megafauna.It would be helpful if someone uncovered a Diprotodon skeleton with a spear point embedded in a rib -or perhaps Thylacoleo bones next to the charcoal of a human campfire.Such kill sites have been found in the Americas but not in Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The debate about megafauna pivots to a great degree on the techniques for dating old bones and the sediments in which they are buried.If scientists can show that the megafauna died out fairly quickly and that this extinction event happened within a few hundred, or even a couple thousand years, of the arrival of people,that&amp;rsquo;s a strong case - even if a purely circumstantial one- that the one thing was the direct result of the other.As it happens, there is one place where there may be such evidence: Cuddie Springs in New South Wales.Today the person most vocal about the site is archeologist Judith Field.In 1991, she discovered megafauna bones directly adjacent to stone tools - a headline-making find.She says there are two layers showing the association, one about 30,000 years old, the other 35,000 years old.If that dating is accurate, it would mean humans and megafauna coexisted in Australia for something like 20,000 years.&amp;ldquo;What Cuddie Springs demonstrates is that you have an extended overlap of humans and megafauna,Field says.Nonsense, say her critics.They say the fossils have been moved from their original resting places and redeposited in younger sediments.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Another famous boneyard in the same region is a place called Wellington Caves,where Diprotodon, the largest known marsupial* , was first discovered.Scientist Mike Augee says that:&amp;ldquo;This is a sacred site in Australian paleontology.&amp;rdquo; Here&amp;rsquo;s why: In 1830 a local official named George Rankin lowered himself into the cave on a rope tied to a protrusion in the cave wall.The protrusion turned out to be a bone.A surveyor named Thomas Mitchell arrived later that year, explored the caves in the area, and shipped fossils off to Richard Owen, the British paleontologist who later gained fame for revealing the existence of dinosaurs.Owen recognized that the Wellington cave bones belonged to an extinct marsupial. Later, between 1909 and 1915 sediments in Mammoth Cave that contained fossils were hauled out and examined in a chaotic manner that no scientist today would approve. Still, one bone in particular has drawn extensive attention: a femur with a cut in it, possibly left there by a sharp tool.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, the Earth preserves its history haphazardly. Bones disintegrate, the land erodes, the climate changes, forests come and go, rivers change their course- and history, if not destroyed, is steadily concealed.By necessity, narratives are constructed from limited data. Australia&amp;rsquo;s first people expressed themselves in rock art. Paleontologist Peter Murray has studied a rock painting in far northern Australia that shows what looks very much like a megafauna marsupial known as Palorchestes. In Western Australia another site shows what appears to be a hunter with either a marsupial lion or a Tasmanian tiger - a major distinction, since the marsupial lion went extinct and the much smaller Tasmanian tiger survived into the more recent historical era. But as Murray says, &amp;ldquo;Every step of the way involves interpretation.The data doesn&amp;rsquo;t just speak for itself.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R.OG6.3 The Swiffer</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og6.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og6.3/</guid><description>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>For a fascinating tale about creativity, look at a cleaning product called the Swiffer and how it came about,urges writer Jonah Lehrer.In the story of the Swiffer, he argues, we have the key elements in producing break through ideas: frustration, moments of insight and sheer hard work.The story starts with a multinational company which had invented products for keeping homes spotless, and couldn&amp;rsquo;t come up with better ways to clean floors, so it hired designers to watch how people cleaned.Frustrated after hundreds of hours of observation, they one day noticed a woman do with a paper towel what people do all the time: wipe something up and throw it away.An idea popped into lead designer Harry West&amp;rsquo;s head: the solution to their problem was a floor mop with a disposable cleaning surface.Mountains of prototypes and years of teamwork later, they unveiled the Swiffer, which quickly became a commercial success.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Lehrer, the author of lmagine, a new book that seeks to explain how creativity works,says this study of the imagination started from a desire to understand what happens in the brain at the moment of sudden insight.But the book definitely spiraled out of control,&amp;rsquo; Lehrer says.When you talk to creative people, they&amp;rsquo;ll tell you about the &amp;rsquo;eureka&amp;rsquo;* moment, but when you press them they also talk about the hard work that comes afterwards, so l realised I needed to write about that, too.And then i realised I couldn&amp;rsquo;t just look at creativity from the perspective of the brain, because it&amp;rsquo;s also about the culture and context, about the group and the team and the way we collaborate.'&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>When it comes to the mysterious process by which inspiration comes into your head as if from nowhere, Lehrer says modern neuroscience has produced a &amp;lsquo;first draft&amp;rsquo; explanation of what is happening in the brain. He writes of how burnt-out American singer Bob Dylan decided to walk away from his musical career in 1965 and escape to a cabin in the woods, only to be overcome by a desire to write. Apparently &amp;lsquo;Like a Rolling Stone&amp;rsquo; suddenly flowed from his pen. It&amp;rsquo;s like a ghost is writing a song,&amp;rsquo; Dylan has reportedly said. &amp;lsquo;It gives you the song and it goes away.&amp;rsquo; But it&amp;rsquo;s no ghost, according to Lehrer.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Instead, the right hemisphere of the brain is assembling connections between past influences and making something entirely new. Neuroscientists have roughly charted this process by mapping the brains of people doing word puzzles solved by making sense of remotely connecting information. For instance, subjects are given three words- such as &amp;lsquo;age&amp;rsquo; , &amp;lsquo;mile&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;sand&amp;rsquo; - and asked to come up with a single word that can precede or follow each of them to form a compound word. (It happens to be &amp;lsquo;stone&amp;rsquo;.)Using brain-imaging equipment, researchers discovered that when people get the answer in an apparent flash of insight, a small fold of tissue called the anterior superior temporal gyrus suddenly lights up just beforehand. This stays silent when the word puzzle is solved through careful analysis. Lehrer says that this area of the brain lights up only after we&amp;rsquo;ve hit the wall on a problem. Then the brain starts hunting through the &amp;lsquo;filing cabinets of the right hemisphere&amp;rsquo; to make the connections that produce the right answer.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Studies have demonstrated it&amp;rsquo;s possible to predict a moment of insight up to eight seconds before it arrives.The predictive signal is a steady rhythm of alpha waves emanating from the brain&amp;rsquo;s right hemisphere, which are closely associated with relaxing activities. &amp;ldquo;When our minds are at ease - when those alpha waves are rippling through the brain - we&amp;rsquo;re more likely to direct the spotlight of attention towards that stream of remote associations emanating from the right hemisphere,&amp;rsquo; Lehrer writes. &amp;rsquo; In contrast,when we are diligently focused, our attention tends to be towards the details of the problems we are trying to solve. In other words, then we are less likely to make those vital associations.So, heading out for a walk or lying down are important phases of the creative process, and smart companies know this.Some now have a policy of encouraging staff to take time out during the day and spend time on things that at first glance are unproductive (like playing a PC game), but day-dreaming has been shown to be positively correlated with problem-solving.However, to be more imaginative, says Lehrer, it&amp;rsquo;s also crucial to collaborate with people from a wide range of back grounds because if colleagues are too socially intimate, creativity is stifled.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Creativity, it seems, thrives on serendipity.American entrepreneur Steve Jobs believed so.Lehrer describes how at Pixar Animation, Jobs designed the entire workplace to maximise the chance of strangers bumping into each other,striking up conversations and learning from one another.He also points to a study of 766 business graduates who had gone on to own their own companies.Those with the greatest diversity of acquaintances enjoyed far more success.Lehrer says he has taken all this on board,and despite his inherent shyness, when he&amp;rsquo;s sitting next to strangers on a plane or at a conference,forces himself to initiate conversations.As for predictions that therise of the Internet would make the need for shared working space obsolete, Lehrer says research shows the opposite has occurred; when people meet face-to-face, the level of creativity increases.This is why the kind of place we live in is so important to innovation.According to theoretical physicist Geoffrey West, when corporate institutions get bigger,they often become less receptive to change.Cities, however,allow our ingenuity to grow by pulling huge numbers of different people together,who then exchange ideas.Working from the comfort of our homes may be convenient, therefore, but it seems we need the company of others to achieve our finest &amp;rsquo;eureka&amp;rsquo; moments.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R.OG7.1 The Hidden Histories of Exploration Exhibition</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og7.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og7.1/</guid><description>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>We have all heard tales of lone, heroic explorers, but what about the local individuals who guided and protected European explorers in many different parts of the globe? Or the go-betweens - including interpreters and traders -who translated the needs and demands of explorers into a language that locals could understand? Such questions have received surprisingly little attention in standard histories, where European explorers are usually the heroes, sometimes the villains.The Hidden Histories of Exploration exhibition at Britain&amp;rsquo;s Royal Geographical Society in London sets out to present an alternative view, in which exploration is a fundamentally collective experience of work, involving many different people.Many of the most famous examples of explorers said to have been &amp;rsquo;lone travellers&amp;rsquo;- say, Mungo Park or David Livingstone in Africa - were anything but &amp;lsquo;alone&amp;rsquo; on their travels.They depended on local support of various kinds - for food, shelter, protection, information, guidance and solace - as well as on other resources from elsewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Royal Geographical Society (RGS) seeks to record this story in its Hidden Histories project,using its astonishingly rich collections.The storage of geographical information was one of the main rationales for the foundation of the RGS in 1830,and the Society&amp;rsquo;s collections now contain more than two million individual items, including books, manuscripts, maps, photographs,art-works, artefacts and film - a rich storehouse of material reflecting the wide geographical extent of British interest across the globe.In addition to their remarkable scope and range, these collections contain a striking visual record of exploration: the impulse to collect the world is reflected in a large and diverse image archive.For the researcher, this archive can yield many surprises: materials gathered for one purpose - say, maps relating to an international boundary dispute or photographs taken on a scientific expedition - may today be put to quite different uses.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In their published narratives,European explorers rarely portrayed themselves as vulnerable or dependent on others, despite the fact that without this support they were quite literally lost.Archival research confirms that Europeans were not merely dependent on the work of porters, soldiers,translators, cooks, pilots, guides, hunters and collectors: they also relied on local expertise.Such assistance was essential in identifying potential dangers- poisonous species, unpredictable rivers, uncharted territories - which could mean the difference between life and death.The assistants themselves were usually in a strong bargaining position.In the Amazon, for example, access to entire regions would depend on the willingness of local crew members and other assistants to enter areas inhabited by relatively powerful Amerindian groups.In an account of his journey across South America, published in 1836,William Smyth thus complained of frequent &amp;lsquo;desertion&amp;rsquo; by his helpers: &amp;lsquo;without them it was impossible to get on&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Those providing local support and information to explorers were themselves often not &amp;rsquo;locals &amp;lsquo;.For example, the history of African exploration in the nineteenth century is dominated by the use of Zanzibar as a recruiting station for porters, soldiers and guides who would then travel thousands of miles across the continent.In some accounts, the leading African members of expedition parties - the &amp;lsquo;officers&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;foremen&amp;rsquo;- are identified, and their portraits published alongside those of European explorers.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The information provided by locals and intermediaries was of potential importance to geographical science.How was this evidence judged?The formal procedures of scientific evaluation provided one framework.Alongside these were more &amp;lsquo;common sense&amp;rsquo; notions of veracity and reliability,religiously-inspired judgments about the authenticity of testimony, and the routine procedures for cross-checking empirical observations developed in many professions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Given explorers&amp;rsquo; need for local information and support, it was in their interests to develop effective working partnerships with knowledgeable intermediaries who could act as brokers in their dealings with local inhabitants.Many of these people acquired far more experience of exploration than most Europeans could hope to attain.Some managed large groups of men and women, piloted the explorers&amp;rsquo; river craft, or undertook mapping work.The tradition was continued with the Everest expeditions in the 1920s and 1930s,which regularly employed the Tibetan interpreter Karma Paul.In Europe, exploration was increasingly thought of as a career; the same might be said of the non-Europeans on whom their expeditions depended.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="g">G&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>These individuals often forged close working relationships with European explorers.Such partnerships depended on mutual respect, though they were not always easy or intimate, as is particularly clear from the history of the Everest expeditions depicted in the Hidden Histories exhibition.The entire back wall is covered by an enlarged version of a single sheet of photographs of Sherpas taken during the 1936 Everest expedition.The document is a powerful reminder of the manpower on which European mountaineering expeditions depended, and also of the importance of local knowledge and assistance.Transformed from archive to wall display, it tells a powerful story through the medium of individual portraits - including Karma Paul, veteran of previous expeditions,and the young Tensing Norgay, 17 years before his successful 1953 ascent.This was a highly charged and transitional moment as the contribution of the Sherpas, depicted here with identity tags round their necks, was beginning to be much more widely recognised.These touching portraits encourage us to see them as agents rather than simply colonial subjects or paid employees.Here is a living history, which looks beyond what we already know about exploration: a larger history in which we come to recognise the contribution of everyone involved.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R.OG7.2 Fatal Attraction</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og7.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og7.2/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Evolutionist Charles Darwin first marvelled at flesh-eating plants in the mid-19th century.Today, biologists, using 21st-century tools to study cells and DNA, are beginning to understand how these plants hunt, eat and digest - and how such bizarre adaptations arose in the first place.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The leaves of the Venus flytrap plant are covered in hairs.When an insect brushes against them, this triggers a tiny electric charge, which travels down tunnels in the leaf and opens up pores in the leaf&amp;rsquo;s cell membranes.Water surges from the cells on the inside of the leaf to those on the outside, causing the leaf to rapidly flip in shape from convex to concave, like a soft contact lens.As the leaves flip, they snap together, trapping the insect in their sharp-toothed jaws.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The bladderwort has an equally sophisticated way of setting its underwater tap.It pumps water out of tiny bag-like bladders, making a vacuum inside. When small creatures swim past, they bend the hairs on the bladder, causing a flap to open.The low pressure sucks water in, carrying the animal along with it. In one five-hundredth of a second, the door swings shut again.The Drosera sundew,meanwhile, has a thick, sweet liquid oozing from its leaves, which first attracts insects, then holds them fast before the leaves snap shut. Pitcher plants use yet another strategy, growing long tube-shaped leaves to imprison their prey.Raffles&amp;rsquo; pitcher plant, from the jungles of Borneo,produces nectar that both lures insects and forms a slick surface on which they can&amp;rsquo;t get a grip. Insects that land on the rim of the pitcher slide on the liquid and tumble in.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Many carnivorous plants secrete enzymes to penetrate the hard exoskeleton of insects so they can absorb nutrients from inside their prey.But the purple pitcher plant, which lives in bogs and infertile sandy soils in North America, enlists other organisms to process its food.It is home to an intricate food web of mosquito larvae, midges and bacteria, many of which can survive only in this unique habitat.These animals shred the prey that fall into the pitcher, and the smaller organisms feed on the debris.Finally, the plant absorbs the nutrients released.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>While such plants clearly thrive on being carnivorous, the benefits of eating flesh are not the ones you might expect.Carnivorous animals such as ourselves use the carbon in protein and the fat in meat to build muscles and store energy.Carnivorous plants instead draw nitrogen, phosphorus, and other critical nutrients from their prey in order to build light-harvesting enzymes.Eating animals, in other words, lets carnivorous plants do what all plants do: carry out photosynthesis, that is, grow by harnessing energy directly from the sun.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Carnivorous plants are, in fact,very inefficient at converting sunlight into tissue.This is because of all the energy they expend to make the equipment to catch animals - the enzymes, the pumps, and so on.A pitcher or a flytrap cannot carry out much photosynthesis because, unlike plants with ordinary leaves, they do not have flat solar panels that can grab lots of sunlight.There are, however, some special conditions in which the benefits of being carnivorous do outweigh the costs.The poor soil of bogs, for example, offers little nitrogen and phosphorus,so carnivorous plants enjoy an advantage over plants that obtain these nutrients by more conventional means.Bogs are also flooded with sunshine, so even an inefficient carnivorous plant can photosynthesise enough light to survive.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Evolution has repeatedly made this trade-off.By comparing the DNA of carnivorous plants with other species, scientists have found that they evolved independently on at least six separate occasions.Some carnivorous plants that look nearly identical turn out to be only distantly related.The two kinds of pitcher plants- the tropical genus Nepenthes and the North American Sarracenia - have,surprisingly, evolved from different ancestors, although both grow deep pitcher-shaped leaves and employ the same strategy for capturing prey.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="g">G&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In several cases, scientists can see how complex carnivorous plants evolved from simpler ones.Venus flytraps, for example, share an ancestor with Portuguese sundews, which only catch prey passively, via &amp;lsquo;flypaper&amp;rsquo; glands on their stems.They share a more recent ancestor with Drosera sundews, which can also curl their leaves over their prey.Venus flytraps appear to have evolved an even more elaborate version of this kind of trap, complete with jaw-like leaves.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="h">H&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, the adaptations that enable carnivorous plants to thrive in marginal habitats also make them exquisitely sensitive.Agricultural run-off and pollution from power plants are adding extra nitrogen to many bogs in North America.Carnivorous plants are so finely tuned to low levels of nitrogen that this extra fertilizer is overloading their systems, and they eventually burn themselves out and die.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="i">I&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Humans also threaten carnivorous plants in other ways.The black market trade in exotic carnivorous plants is so vigorous now that botanists are keeping the location of some rare species a secret.But even if the poaching of carnivorous plants can be halted, they will continue to suffer from other assaults.In the pine savannah of North Carolina, the increasing suppression of fires is allowing other plants to grow too quickly and outcompete the flytraps in their native environment.Good news, perhaps, for flies.But a loss for all who, like Darwin,delight in the sheer inventiveness of evolution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R.OG7.3 WANT TO BE FRIENDS?</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og7.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og7.3/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Could the benefits of online social networking be too good to miss out on?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>For many hundreds of thousands of people worldwide, online networking has become enmeshed in our daily lives.However, it is a decades-old insight from a study of traditional social networks that best illuminates one of the most important aspects of today&amp;rsquo;s online networking.In 1973 sociologist Mark Granovetter showed how the loose acquaintances,or &amp;lsquo;weak ties&amp;rsquo;, in our social network exert a disproportionate influence over our behaviour and choices.Granovetter&amp;rsquo;s research showed that a significant percentage of people get their jobs as a result of recommendations or advice provided by a weak tie.Today our number of weak-tie contacts has exploded via online social networking.You couldn&amp;rsquo;t maintain all of those weak ties on your own,&amp;rsquo; says Jennifer Golbeck of the University of Maryland.Online sites,such as Facebook,give you a way of cataloguing them.&amp;lsquo;The result?lt&amp;rsquo;s now significantly easier for the school friend you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen in years to pass you a tip that alters your behaviour; from recommendation of a low-cholesterol breakfast cereal to a party invite where you meet your future wife or husband.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The explosion of weak ties could have profound consequences for our social structures too, according to Judith Donath of the Berkman Center for lnternet and Society at Harvard University.We&amp;rsquo;re already seeing changes,&amp;rsquo; she says.For example, many people now turn to their online social networks ahead of sources such as newspapers and television for trusted and relevant news or information.What they hear could well be inaccurate, but the change is happening nonetheless.If these huge &amp;lsquo;supernets&amp;rsquo;-some of them numbering up to 5,000people - continue to thrive and grow,they could fundamentally change the way we share information and transform our notions of relationships.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>But are these vast networks really that relevant to us on a personal level? Robin Dunbar, an evolutionary anthropologist at the University of Oxford， believes that our primate brains place a cap on the number of genuine social relationships we can actually cope with: roughly 150.According to Dunbar; online social networking appears to be very good for &amp;lsquo;servicing&amp;rsquo; relationships, but not for establishing them.He argues that our evolutionary roots mean we still depend heavily on physical and face-to-face contact to be able to create ties.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Nonetheless, there is evidence that online networking can transform our daily interactions.In an experiment at Cornell University, psychologist Jeff Hancockasked participants to try to encourage other participants to like them via instant messaging conversation.Beforehand,some members of the trial were allowed to view the Facebook profile of the person they were trying to win over.He found that those with Facebook access asked questions to which they already knew the answers or raised things they had in common,and as result were much more successful in their social relationships.Hancock concluded that people who use these sites to keep updated on the activities of their acquaintances are more likely to be liked in subsequent social interactions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Online social networking may also have tangible effects on our well-being.Nicole Ellison of Michigan State University found that the frequency of networking site use correlates with greater self-esteem.Support and affirmation from the weak ties could be the explanation,for help or advice is nothing new,but we are seeing a lowering of barriers among acquaintances,&amp;rsquo; she says.People are readily sharing personal feelings and experiences to a wider circle than they might once have done.Sandy Pentland at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology agrees. &amp;lsquo;The ability to broadcast to our social group means we need never feel alone,&amp;rsquo; he says.&amp;lsquo;The things that befall us are often due to alack of social support.There&amp;rsquo;s more of a safety net now.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Henry Holzman,also at MIT, who studies the interface between online social networking and the real world, points out that increased visibility also means our various social spheres - family, work,friends - are merging, and so we will have to prepare for new societal norms.&amp;lsquo;We&amp;rsquo;ll have to learn how to live a more transparent life,&amp;rsquo; he says. &amp;lsquo;We may have to give up some ability to show very limited glimpses of ourselves to others.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="g">G&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Another way that online networking appears to be changing our social structures is through dominance. In one repeated experiment，Michael Kearns of the University of Pennsylvania asked 3D volunteers to quickly reach consensus in an online game over a choice between two colours. Each person was offered a cash reward if they succeeded in persuading the group to pick one or other colour. All participants could see the colour chosen by some of the other people, but certain participants had an extra advantage: the ability to see more others. Every time Kearns found that those who could see the choices of more participants( in other words, were better connected) persuaded the group to pick their colour, even when they had to persuade the vast majority to give up their financial incentive.While Kearns warns that the setting was artificial, he says its possible that greater persuasive power could lie with well-connected individuals in the everyday online world too.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R.OG8.1 The Phoenicians - an almost forgotten people</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og8.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og8.1/</guid><description>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Phoenicians inhabited the region of modern Lebanon and Syria from about 3000 BC.They became the greatest traders of the pre-classical world, and were the first people to establish a large colonial network.Both of these activities were based on seafaring, an ability the Phoenicians developed from the example of their maritime predecessors, the Minoans of Crete.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>An Egyptian narrative of about 1080 BC, the Story of Wen-Amen, provides an insight into the scale of their trading activity.One of the characters is Wereket-El, a Phoenician merchant living at Tanis in Egypt&amp;rsquo;s Nile delta.As many as 50 ships carry out his business, plying back and forth between the Nile and the Phoenician port of Sidon.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The most prosperous period for Phoenicia was the 10th century BC, when the surrounding region was stable.Hiram, the king of the Phoenician city of Tyre, was an ally and business partner of Solomon,King of Israel.For Solomon&amp;rsquo;s temple in Jerusalem,Hiram provided craftsmen with particular skills that were needed for this major construction project.He also supplied materials - particularly timber,including cedar from the forests of Lebanon.And the two kings went into trade in partnership.They sent out Phoenician vessels on long expeditions (of up to three years for the return trip) to bring back gold, sandalwood, ivory, monkeys and peacocks from Ophir.This is an unidentified place, probably on the east coast of Africa or the west coast of India.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Phoenicia was famous for its luxury goods.The cedar wood was not only exported as top-quality timber for architecture and ship building.It was also carved by the Phoenicians, and the same skill was adapted to even more precious work in ivory.The rare and expensive dye for cloth, Tyrian purple,complemented another famous local product, fine linen.The metalworkers of the region, particularly those working in gold, were famous.Tyre and Sidon were also known for their glass.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>These were the main products which the Phoenicians exported.In addition, as traders and middlemen, they took a commission on a much greater range of precious goods that they transported from elsewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The extensive trade of Phoenicia required much book-keeping and correspondence, and it was in the field of writing that the Phoenicians made their most lasting contribution to world history.&amp;ldquo;The scripts in use in the world up to the second millennium BC(in Egypt, Mesopotamia or China) all required the writer to learn a large number of separate characters - each of them expressing either a whole word or an element of its meaning.&amp;ldquo;By contrast,the Phoenicians, in about 1500 BC, developed an entirely new approach to writing.The marks made(with a pointed tool called a stylus, on damp clay)now attempted to capture the sound of a word.This required an alphabet of individual letters.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="g">G&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The trading and seafaring skills of the Phoenicians resulted in a network of colonies, spreading westwards through the Mediterranean.The first was probably Citium, in Cyprus, established in the 9thcentury BC.But the main expansion came from the 8th century BC onwards, when pressure from Assyria to the east disrupted the patterns of trade on the Phoenician coast.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="h">H&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Trading colonies were developed on the string of islands in the centre of the Mediterranean - Crete,Sicily,Malta, Sardinia, Ibiza - and also on the coast of north Africa.The African colonies clustered in particular around the great promontory which, with Sicily opposite, forms the narrowest channel on the main Mediterranean sea route.This is the site of Carthage.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="i">I&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Carthage was the largest of the towns founded by the Phoenicians on the north African coast, and it rapidly assumed a leading position among the neighbouring colonies.The traditional date of its founding is 814 BC, but archaeological evidence suggests that it was probably settled a little over a century later.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="j">J&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The subsequent spread and growth of Phoenician colonies in the western Mediterranean, and even out to the Atlantic coasts of Africa and Spain, was as much the achievement of Carthage as of the original Phoenician trading cities such as Tyre and Sidon.But no doubt links were maintained with the homeland,and new colonists continued to travel west.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="k">K&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>From the 8th century BC, many of the coastal cities of Phoenicia came under the control of a succession of imperial powers, each of them defeated and replaced in the region by the next: first the Assyrians, then the Babylonians,Persians and Macedonian Greeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="l">L&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In 64 BC,the area of Phoenicia became part of the Roman province of Syria.The Phoenicians as an identifiable people then faded from history, merging into the populations of modern Lebanon and northern Syria.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R.OG8.2 The Hollywood Film Industry</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og8.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og8.2/</guid><description>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>This chapter examines the &amp;lsquo;Golden Age&amp;rsquo; of the Hollywood film studio system and explores how a particular kind of filmmaking developed during this period in US film history.It also focuses on the two key elements which influenced the emergence of the classic Hollywood studio system: the advent of sound and the business ideal of vertical integration.In addition to its historical interest,inspecting the growth of the studio system may offer clues regarding the kinds of struggles that accompany the growth of any new medium.It might, in fact,be intriguing to examine which changes occurred during the growth of the Hollywood studio, and compare those changes to contemporary struggles in which production companies are trying to define and control emerging industries, such as online film and interactive television.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The shift of the industry away from &amp;lsquo;silent&amp;rsquo; films began during the late 1920s. WarnerBros.&amp;lsquo;1927 film The Jazz Singer was the first to feature synchronized speech, and with it came a period of turmoil for the industry.Studios now had proof that &amp;rsquo;talkie&amp;rsquo; films would make them money, but the financial investment this kind of film making would require, from new camera equipment to new projection facilities,made the studios hesitant to invest at first.In the end, the power of cinematic sound to both move audiences and enhance the story persuaded studios that talkies were worth investing in.Overall, the use of sound in film was well-received by audiences, but there were still many technical factors to consider.Although full integration of sound into movies was complete by 1930, it would take somewhat longer for them to regain their stylistic elegance and dexterity.The camera now had to be encased in a big, clumsy, unmoveable soundproof box.In addition, actors struggled, having to direct their speech to awkwardly-hidden microphones in huge plants, telephones or even costumes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Vertical integration is the other key component in the rise of the Hollywood studio system.The major studios realized they could increase their profits by handling each stage of a film&amp;rsquo;s life: production (making the film), distribution( getting the film out to people) and exhibition (owning the theaters in major cities where films were shown first).Five studios, &amp;lsquo;The Big Five&amp;rsquo;, worked to achieve vertical integration through the late 1940s, owning vast real estate on which to construct elaborate sets.In addition, these studios set the exact terms of films&amp;rsquo; release dates and patterns.Warner Bros.,Paramount, 20th Century Fox,MGM and RKO formed this exclusive club. &amp;ldquo;The Little Three&amp;rsquo; studios-Universal,Columbia and United Artists - also made pictures, but each lacked one of the crucial elements of vertical integration. Together these eight companies operated as a mature oligopoly, essentially running the entire market.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>During the Golden Age,the studios were remarkably consistent and stable enterprises, due in large part to long-term management heads - the infamous &amp;lsquo;movie moguls&amp;rsquo; who ruled their kingdoms with iron fists. At MGM, Warner Bros. and Columbia, the same men ran their studios for decades.The rise of the studio system also hinges on the treatment of stars, who were constructed and exploited to suit a studio&amp;rsquo;s image and schedule.Actors were bound up in seven-year contracts to a single studio, and the studio boss generally held all the options.Stars could be loaned out to other production companies at any time.Studio bosses could also force bad roles on actors, and manipulate every single detail of stars&amp;rsquo; images with their mammoth in-house publicity departments.Some have compared the Hollywood studio system to a factory, and it is useful to remember that studios were out to make money first and art second.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>On the other hand, studios also had to cultivate flexibility, in addition to consistent factory output.Studio heads realized that they couldn&amp;rsquo;t make virtually the same film over and over again with the same cast of stars and still expect to keep turning a profit.They also had to create product differentiation.Examining how each production company tried to differentiate itself has led to loose characterizations of individual studios&amp;rsquo; styles.MGM tended to put out a lot of all-star productions while Paramount excelled in comedy and Warner Bros. developed a reputation for gritty social realism.20th Century Fox forged the musical and a great deal of prestige biographies, while Universal specialized in classic horror movies.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In 1948,struggling independent movie producers and exhibitors finally triumphed in their battle against the big studios&amp;rsquo; monopolistic behavior.In the United States versus Paramount federal decree of that year, the studios were ordered to give up their theaters in what is commonly referred to as &amp;lsquo;divestiture&amp;rsquo;- opening the market to smaller producers.This, coupled with the advent of television in the 1950s, seriously compromised the studio system&amp;rsquo;s influence and profits.Hence,1930 and 1948 are generally considered bookends to Hollywood&amp;rsquo;s Golden Age.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R.OG8.3 Left or right?</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og8.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r.og8.3/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>An overview of some research into lateralisation: the dominance of one side of the body over the other.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Creatures across the animal kingdom have a preference even antenna for one foot, eye or even antenna.The cause of this trait, called lateralisation, is fairly simple: one side of the brain, which generally controls the opposite side of the body, is more dominant than the other when processing certain tasks.This does, on some occasions, let the animal down:such as when a toad fails to escape from a snake approaching from the right, just because its right eye is worse at spotting danger than its left.So why would animals evolve a characteristic that seems to endanger them?&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>For many years it was assumed that lateralisation was a uniquely human trait, but this notion rapidly fell apart as researchers started uncovering evidence of lateralisation in all sorts of animals.For example, in the 1970s, Lesley Rogers, now at the University of New England in Australia, was studying memory and learning in chicks.She had been injecting a chemical into chicks&amp;rsquo; brains to stop them learning how to spot grains of food among distracting pebbles, and was surprised to observe that the chemical only worked when applied to the left hemisphere of the brain.That strongly suggested that the right side of the chick&amp;rsquo;s brain played little or no role in the learning of such behaviours.Similar evidence appeared in songbirds and rats around the same time, and since then,researchers have built up an impressive catalogue of animal lateralisation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In some animals, lateralisation is simply a preference for a single paw or foot, while in others it appears in more general patterns of behaviour.The left side of most vertebrate brains, for example, seems to process and control feeding.Since the left hemisphere processes input from the right side of the body, that means animals as diverse as fish,toads and birds are more likely to attack prey or food items viewed with their right eye.Even humpback whales prefer to use the right side of their jaws to scrape sand eels from the ocean floor.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Genetics plays a part in determining lateralisation, but environmental factors have an impact too.Rogers found that a chick&amp;rsquo;s lateralisation depends on whether it is exposed to light before hatching from its egg - if it is kept in the dark during this period, neither hemisphere becomes dominant.In 2004, Rogers used this observation to test the advantages of brain bias in chicks faced with the challenge of multitasking.She hatched chicks with either strong or weak lateralisation, then presented the two groups with food hidden among small pebbles and the threatening shape of a fake predator flying overhead.As predicted, the birds incubated in the light looked for food mainly with their right eye, while using the other to check out the predator.The weakly-lateralised chicks, meanwhile, had difficulty performing these two activities simultaneously.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Similar results probably hold true for many other animals.In 2006,Angelo Bisazza at the University of Padua set out to observe the differences in feeding behaviour between strongly-lateralised and weakly-lateralised fish.He found that strongly-lateralised individuals were able to feed twice as fast as weakly-lateralised ones when there was a threat of a predator looming above them.Assigning different jobs to different brain halves may be especially advantageous for animals such as birds or fish, whose eyes are placed on the sides of their heads.This enables them to process input from each side separately, with different tasks in mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>And what of those animals who favour a specific side for almost all tasks? In 2009, Maria Magat and Culum Brown at Macquarie University in Australia wanted to see if there was general cognitive advantage in lateralisation.To investigate, they turned to parrots,which can be either strongly right- or left-footed, or ambidextrous (without dominance).The parrots were given the intellectually demanding task of pulling a snack on a string up to their beaks, using a co-ordinated combination of claws and beak.The results showed that the parrots with the strongest foot preferences worked out the puzzle far more quickly than their ambidextrous peers.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="g">G&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A further puzzle is why are there always a few exceptions, like left-handed humans,who are wired differently from the majority of the population?Giorgio Vallortigara and Stefano Ghirlanda of Stockholm University seem to have found the answer via mathematical models.These have shown that a group of fish is likely to survive a shark attack with the fewest casualties if the majority turn together in one direction while a very small proportion of the group escape in the direction that the predator is not expecting.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="h">H&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>This imbalance of lateralisation within populations may also have advantages for individuals.Whereas most co-operative interactions require participants to react similarly, there are some situations - such as aggressive interactions - where it can benefit an individual to launch an attack from an unexpected quarter.Perhaps this can partly explain the existence of left-handers in human societies. It has been suggested that when it comes to hand-to-hand fighting, left-handers may have the advantage over the right-handed majority.Where survival depends on the element of surprise, it may indeed pay to be different.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>