<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notebook – C6</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/ielts/reading/c6/</link><description>Recent content in C6 on Notebook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://note.codiy.net/docs/ielts/reading/c6/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: R6.1.1 AUSTRALIA’S SPORTING SUCCESS</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.1.1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 15:59:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.1.1/</guid><description>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>They play hard, they play often, and they play to win. Australian sports teams win more than their fair share of titles, demolishing rivals with seeming ease. How do they do it? A big part of the secret is an extensive and expensive network of sporting academies underpinned by science and medicine. At the Australian Institute of Sport (AIS), hundreds of youngsters and pros live and train under the eyes of coaches. Another body, the Australian Sports Commission (ASC), finances programmes of excellence in a total of 96 sports for thousands of sportsmen and women. Both provide intensive coaching, training facilities and nutritional advice.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Inside the academies, science takes centre stage.The AIS employs more than 100 sports scientists and doctors, and collaborates with scores of others in universities and research centres. AIS scientists work across a number of sports, applying skills learned in one - such as building muscle strength in golfers - to others, such as swimming and squash.They are backed up by technicians who design instruments to collect data from athletes.They all focus on one aim: winning.‘We can&amp;rsquo;t waste our time looking at ethereal scientific questions that don&amp;rsquo;t help the coach work with an athlete and improve performance,’ says Peter Fricker; chief of science at AIS.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A lot of their work comes down to measurement - everything from the exact angle of a swimmer&amp;rsquo;s dive to the second-by-second power output of a cyclist.This data is used to wring improvements out of athletes.The focus is on individuals, tweaking performances to squeeze an extra hundredth of a second here, an extra millimetre there. No gain is too slight to bother with. It&amp;rsquo;s the tiny, gradual improvements that add up to world-beating results.To demonstrate how the system works, Bruce Mason at AJ$ shows off the prototype of a 3D analysis tool for studying swimmers. A wire-frame model of a champion swimmer slices through the water , her arms moving in slow motion. Looking side-on, Mason measures the distance between strokes. From above, he analyses how her spine swivels. When fully developed, this system will enable him to build a biomechanical profile for coaches to use to help budding swimmers. Mason&amp;rsquo;s contribution to sport also includes the development of the SWAN (SWimming ANalysis) system now used in Australian national competitions. It collects images from digital cameras running at 50 frames a second and breaks down each part of a swimmer&amp;rsquo;s performance into factors that can be analysed individually - stroke length, stroke frequency, average duration of each stroke, velocity, start, lap and finish times, and so on. At the end of each race, SWAN spits out data on each swimmer.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>‘Take a look,&amp;rsquo; says Mason, pulling out a sheet of data. He points out the data on the swimmers in second and third place, which shows that the one who finished third actually swam faster. So why did he finish 35 hundredths of a second down? ‘His turn times were 44 hundredths of a second behind the other guy,’ says Mason.&amp;lsquo;If he can improve on his turns, he can do much better&amp;rsquo;This is the kind of accuracy that AIS scientists’ research is bringing to a range of sports. With the Cooperative Research Centre for Micro Technology in Melbourne, they are developing unobtrusive sensors that will be embedded in an athlete&amp;rsquo;s clothes or running shoes to monitor heart rate, sweating, heat production or any other factor that might have an impact on an athlete’s ability to run.There&amp;rsquo;s more to it than simply measuring performance. Fricker gives the example of athletes who may be down with coughs and colds 11 or 12 times a year. After years of experimentation, AIS and the University of Newcastle in New South Wales developed a test that measures how much of the immune-system protein immunoglobulin A is present in athletes&amp;rsquo; saliva. If IgA levels suddenly fall below a certain level, training is eased or dropped altogether. Soon, IgA levels start rising again, and the danger passes. Since the tests were introduced, AIS athletes in all sports have been remarkably successful at staying healthy.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Using data is a complex business. Well before a championship, sports scientists and coaches start to prepare the athlete by developing a &amp;lsquo;competition model’, based on what they expect will be the winning times.&amp;lsquo;You design the model to make that time,&amp;rsquo; says Mason.&amp;lsquo;A start of this much, each free-swimming period has to be this fast, with a certain stroke frequency and stroke length, with turns done in these times.’All the training is then geared towards making the athlete hit those targets, both overall and for each segment of the race.Techniques like these have transformed Australia into arguably the world’s most successful sporting nation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing to stop other countries copying - and many have tried. Some years ago, the AIS unveiled coolant-lined jackets for endurance athletes. At the Atlanta Olympic Games in 1996, these sliced as much as two per cent off cyclists&amp;rsquo; and rowers’ times. Now everyone uses them.The same has happened to the &amp;lsquo;altitude tent’, developed by AIS to replicate the effect of altitude training at sea level. But Australia&amp;rsquo;s success story is about more than easily copied technological fixes, and up to now no nation has replicated its all-encompassing system.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R6.1.2 DELIVERING THE GOODS</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.1.2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 15:59:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.1.2/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The vast expansion in international trade owes much to a revolution in the business of moving freight&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>International trade is growing at a startling pace. While the global economy has been expanding at a bit over 3% a year, the volume of trade has been rising at a compound annual rate of about twice that. Foreign products, from meat to machinery, play a more important role in almost every economy in the world, and foreign markets now tempt businesses that never much worried about sales beyond their nation’s borders.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>What lies behind this explosion in international commerce? The general worldwide decline in trade barriers, such as customs duties and import quotas, is surely one explanation. The economic opening of countries that have traditionally been minor players is another. But one force behind the import-export boom has passed all but unnoticed: the rapidly falling cost of getting goods to market. Theoretically, in the world of trade, shipping costs do not matter. Goods, once they have been made, are assumed to move instantly and at no cost from place to place. The real world, however, is full of frictions. Cheap labour may make Chinese clothing competitive in America, but if delays in shipment tie up working capital and cause winter coats to arrive in spring, trade may lose its advantages.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>At the turn of the 20th century, agriculture and manufacturing were the two most important sectors almost everywhere, accounting for about 70% of total output in Germany, Italy and France, and 40-50% in America, Britain and Japan. International commerce was therefore dominated by raw materials, such as wheat, wood and iron ore, or processed commodities, such as meat and steel. But these sorts of products are heavy and bulky and the cost of transporting them relatively high.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Countries still trade disproportionately with their geographic neighbours. Over time, however, world output has shifted into goods whose worth is unrelated to their size and weight. Today, it is finished manufactured products that dominate the flow of trade, and, thanks to technological advances such as lightweight components, manufactured goods themselves have tended to become lighter and less bulky. As a result, less transportation is required for every dollar’s worth of imports or exports.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>To see how this influences trade, consider the business of making disk drives for computers. Most of the world’s disk-drive manufacturing is concentrated in South-east Asia. This is possible only because disk drives, while valuable, are small and light and so cost little to ship. Computer manufacturers in Japan or Texas will not face hugely bigger freight bills if they import drives from Singapore rather than purchasing them on the domestic market. Distance therefore poses no obstacle to the globalisation of the disk-drive industry.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>This is even more true of the fast-growing information industries. Films and compact discs cost little to transport, even by aeroplane. Computer software can be ‘exported’ without ever loading it onto a ship, simply by transmitting it over telephone lines from one country to another, so freight rates and cargo-handling schedules become insignificant factors in deciding where to make the product. Businesses can locate based on other considerations, such as the availability of labour, while worrying less about the cost of delivering their output.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="g">G&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In many countries deregulation has helped to drive the process along. But, behind the scenes, a series of technological innovations known broadly as containerisation and inter- modal transportation has led to swift productivity improvements in cargo-handling. Forty years ago, the process of exporting or importing involved a great many stages of handling, which risked portions of the shipment being damaged or stolen along the way. The invention of the container crane made it possible to load and unload containers without capsizing the ship and the adoption of standard container sizes allowed almost any box to be transported on any ship. By 1967, dual-purpose ships, carrying loose cargo in the hold* and containers on the deck, were giving way to all-container vessels that moved thousands of boxes at a time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="h">H&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The shipping container transformed ocean shipping into a highly efficient, intensely competitive business. But getting the cargo to and from the dock was a different story. National governments, by and large, kept a much firmer hand on truck and railroad tariffs than on charges for ocean freight. This started changing, however, in the mid-1970s, when America began to deregulate its transportation industry. First airlines, then road hauliers and railways, were freed from restrictions on what they could carry, where they could haul it and what price they could charge. Big productivity gains resulted. Between 1985 and 1996, for example, America’s freight railways dramatically reduced their employment, trackage, and their fleets of locomotives - while increasing the amount of cargo they hauled. Europe’s railways have also shown marked, albeit smaller, productivity improvements.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="i">I&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In America the period of huge productivity gains in transportation may be almost over, but in most countries the process still has far to go. State ownership of railways and airlines, regulation of freight rates and toleration of anti-competitive practices, such as cargo-handling monopolies, all keep the cost of shipping unnecessarily high and deter international trade. Bringing these barriers down would help the world’s economies grow even closer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R6.1.3 Climate Change and the Inuit</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.1.3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 15:59:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.1.3/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The threat posed by climate change in the Arctic and the problems faced by Canada’s Inuit people&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Unusual incidents are being reported across the Arctic. Inuit families going off on snowmobiles to prepare their summer hunting camps have found themselves cut off from home by a sea of mud, following early thaws. There are reports of igloos losing their insulating properties as the snow drips and refreezes, of lakes draining into the sea as permafrost melts, and sea ice breaking up earlier than usual, carrying seals beyond the reach of hunters. Climate change may still be a rather abstract idea to most of us, but in the Arctic it is already having dramatic effects - if summertime ice continues to shrink at its present rate, the Arctic Ocean could soon become virtually ice-free in summer. The knock-on effects are likely to include more warming, cloudier skies, increased precipitation and higher sea levels. Scientists are increasingly keen to find out what&amp;rsquo;s going on because they consider the Arctic the &amp;lsquo;canary in the mine&amp;rsquo; for global warming - a warning of what&amp;rsquo;s in store for the rest of the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>For the Inuit the problem is urgent. They live in precarious balance with one of the toughest environments on earth. Climate change, whatever its causes, is a direct threat to their way of life. Nobody knows the Arctic as well as the locals, which is why they are not content simply to stand back and let outside experts tell them what&amp;rsquo;s happening. In Canada, where the Inuit people are jealously guarding their hard-won autonomy in the country&amp;rsquo;s newest territory, Nunavut, they believe their best hope of survival in this changing environment lies in combining their ancestral knowledge with the best of modern science. This is a challenge in itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Canadian Arctic is a vast, treeless polar desert that&amp;rsquo;s covered with snow for most of the year. Venture into this terrain and you get some idea of the hardships facing anyone who calls this home. Farming is out of the question and nature offers meagre pickings. Humans first settled in the Arctic a mere 4,500 years ago, surviving by exploiting sea mammals and fish. The environment tested them to the limits: sometimes the colonists were successful, sometimes they failed and vanished. But around a thousand years ago, one group emerged that was uniquely well adapted to cope with the Arctic environment. These Thule people moved in from Alaska, bringing kayaks, sleds, dogs, pottery and iron tools. They are the ancestors of today&amp;rsquo;s Inuit people.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Life for the descendants of the Thule people is still harsh. Nunavut is 1.9 million square kilometres of rock and ice, and a handful of islands around the North Pole. It’s currently home to 2,500 people, all but a handful of them indigenous Inuit. Over the past 40 years, most have abandoned their nomadic ways and settled in the territory&amp;rsquo;s 28 isolated communities, but they still rely heavily on nature to provide food and clothing.
Provisions available in local shops have to be flown into Nunavut on one of the most costly air networks in the world, or brought by supply ship during the few ice-free weeks of summer. It would cost a family around £7,000 a year to replace meat they obtained themselves through hunting with imported meat. Economic opportunities are scarce, and for many people state benefits are their only income.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>While the Inuit may not actually starve if hunting and trapping are curtailed by climate change, there has certainly been an impact on people&amp;rsquo;s health. Obesity, heart disease and diabetes are beginning to appear in a people for whom these have never before been problems. There has been a crisis of identity as the traditional skills of hunting, trapping and preparing skins have begun to disappear. In Nunavut&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;igloo and email&amp;rsquo; society, where adults who were born in igloos have children who may never have been out on the land, there&amp;rsquo;s a high incidence of depression.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>With so much at stake, the Inuit are determined to play a key role in teasing out the mysteries of climate change in the Arctic. Having survived there for centuries, they believe their wealth of traditional knowledge is vital to the task. And Western scientists are starting to draw on this wisdom, increasingly referred to as &amp;lsquo;Inuit Qaujimajatuqangit&amp;rsquo;, or IQ. &amp;lsquo;In the early days scientists ignored us when they came up here to study anything. They just figured these people don&amp;rsquo;t know very much so we won&amp;rsquo;t ask them,&amp;rsquo; says John Amagoalik, an Inuit leader and politician. &amp;lsquo;But in recent years IQ has had much more credibility and weight.&amp;rsquo; In fact it is now a requirement for anyone hoping to get permission to do research that they consult the communities, who are helping to set the research agenda to reflect their most important concerns. They can turn down applications from scientists they believe will work against their interests, or research projects that will impinge too much on their daily lives and traditional activities.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="g">G&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Some scientists doubt the value of traditional knowledge because the occupation of the Arctic doesn&amp;rsquo;t go back far enough. Others, however, point out that the first weather stations in the far north date back just 50 years. There are still huge gaps in our environmental knowledge, and despite the scientific onslaught, many predictions are no more than best guesses. IQ could help to bridge the gap and resolve the tremendous uncertainty about how much of what we&amp;rsquo;re seeing is natural capriciousness and how much is the consequence of human activity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R6.2.1 Advantages of public transport</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.2.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.2.1/</guid><description>
&lt;p>A new study conducted for the World Bank by Murdoch University&amp;rsquo;s Institute for Science and Technology Policy (ISTP) has demonstrated that public transport is more efficient than cars. The study compared the proportion of wealth poured into transport by thirty-seven cities around the world. This included both the public and private costs of building, maintaining and using a transport system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The study found that the Western Australian city of Perth is a good example of a city with minimal public transport. As a result, 17% of its wealth went into transport costs. Some European and Asian cities, on the other hand, spent as little as 5%. Professor Peter Newman, ISTP Director, pointed out that these more efficient cities were able to put the difference into attracting industry and jobs or creating a better place to live.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to Professor Newman, the larger Australian city of Melbourne is a rather unusual city in this sort of comparison. He describes it as two cities: &amp;lsquo;A European city surrounded by a car-dependent one&amp;rsquo;. Melbourne&amp;rsquo;s large tram network has made car use in the inner city much lower, but the outer suburbs have the same car-based structure as most other Australian cities. The explosion in demand for accommodation in the inner suburbs of Melbourne suggests a recent change in many people&amp;rsquo;s preferences as to where they live.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Newman says this is a new, broader way of considering public transport issues. In the past, the case for public transport has been made on the basis of environmental and social justice considerations rather than economics. Newman, however, believes the study demonstrates that &amp;rsquo;the auto-dependent city model is inefficient and grossly inadequate in economic as well as environmental terms&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bicycle use was not included in the study but Newman noted that the two most &amp;lsquo;bicycle friendly&amp;rsquo; cities considered - Amsterdam and Copenhagen - were very efficient, even though their public transport systems were &amp;lsquo;reasonable but not special&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is common for supporters of road networks to reject the models of cities with good public transport by arguing that such systems would not work in their particular city. One objection is climate. Some people say their city could not make more use of public transport because it is either too hot or too cold. Newman rejects this, pointing out that public transport has been successful in both Toronto and Singapore and, in fact, he has checked the use of cars against climate and found &amp;lsquo;zero correlation&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When it comes to other physical features, road lobbies are on stronger ground. For example, Newman accepts it would be hard for a city as hilly as Auckland to develop a really good rail network. However, he points out that both Hong Kong and Zurich have managed to make a success of their rail systems, heavy and light respectively, though there are few cities in the world as hilly.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In fact, Newman believes the main reason for adopting one sort of transport over another is politics: &amp;lsquo;The more democratic the process, the more public transport is favored.&amp;rsquo; He considers Portland, Oregon, a perfect example of this. Some years ago, federal money was granted to build a new road. However, local pressure groups forced a referendum over whether to spend the money on light rail instead. The rail proposal won and the railway worked spectacularly well. In the years that have followed, more and more rail systems have been put in, dramatically changing the nature of the city. Newman notes that Portland has about the same population as Perth and had a similar population density at the time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>In the UK, travel times to work had been stable for at least six centuries, with people avoiding situations that required them to spend more than half an hour travelling to work. Trains and cars initially allowed people to live at greater distances without taking longer to reach their destination. However, public infrastructure did not keep pace with urban sprawl, causing massive congestion problems which now make commuting times far higher.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>There is a widespread belief that increasing wealth encourages people to live farther out where cars are the only viable transport. The example of European cities refutes that. They are often wealthier than their American counterparts but have not generated the same level of car use. In Stockholm, car use has actually fallen in recent years as the city has become larger and wealthier. A new study makes this point even more starkly. Developing cities in Asia, such as Jakarta and Bangkok, make more use of the car than wealthy Asian cities such as Tokyo and Singapore. In cities that developed later, the World Bank and Asian Development Bank discouraged the building of public transport and people have been forced to rely on cars - creating the massive traffic jams that characterize those cities.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Newman believes one of the best studies on how cities built for cars might be converted to rail use is The Urban Village report, which used Melbourne as an example. It found that pushing everyone into the city centre was not the best approach. Instead, the proposal advocated the creation of urban villages at hundreds of sites, mostly around railway stations.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>It was once assumed that improvements in telecommunications would lead to more dispersal in the population as people were no longer forced into cities. However, the ISTP team&amp;rsquo;s research demonstrates that the population and job density of cities rose or remained constant in the 1980s after decades of decline. The explanation for this seems to be that it is valuable to place people working in related fields together. &amp;lsquo;The new world will largely depend on human creativity, and creativity flourishes where people come together face-to-face.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R6.2.2 GREYING POPULATION STAYS IN THE PINK</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.2.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.2.2/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Elderly people are growing healthier, happier and more independent, say American scientists. The results of a 14-year study to be announced later this month reveal that the diseases associated with old age are afflicting fewer and fewer people and when they do strike, it is much later in life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the last 14 years, the National Long-term Health Care Survey has gathered data on the health and lifestyles of more than 20,000 men and women over 65. Researchers, now analysing the results of data gathered in 1994, say arthritis, high blood pressure and circulation problems - the major medical complaints in this age group - are troubling a smaller proportion every year. And the data confirms that the rate at which these diseases are declining continues to accelerate. Other diseases of old age - dementia, stroke, arteriosclerosis and emphysema - are also troubling fewer and fewer people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lsquo;It really raises the question of what should be considered normal ageing,&amp;rsquo; says Kenneth Manton, a demographer from Duke University in North Carolina. He says the problems doctors accepted as normal in a 65-year-old in 1982 are often not appearing until people are 70 or 75.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clearly, certain diseases are beating a retreat in the face of medical advances. But there may be other contributing factors. Improvements in childhood nutrition in the first quarter of the twentieth century, for example, gave today&amp;rsquo;s elderly people a better start in life than their predecessors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the downside, the data also reveals failures in public health that have caused surges in some illnesses. An increase in some cancers and bronchitis may reflect changing smoking habits and poorer air quality, say the researchers. &amp;lsquo;These may be subtle influences,&amp;rsquo; says Manton, &amp;lsquo;but our subjects have been exposed to worse and worse pollution for over 60 years. It&amp;rsquo;s not surprising we see some effect.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One interesting correlation Manton uncovered is that better-educated people are likely to live longer. For example, 65-year-old women with fewer than eight years of schooling are expected, on average, to live to 82. Those who continued their education live an extra seven years. Although some of this can be attributed to a higher income, Manton believes it is mainly because educated people seek more medical attention.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The survey also assessed how independent people over 65 were, and again found a striking trend. Almost 80% of those in the 1994 survey could complete everyday activities ranging from eating and dressing unaided to complex tasks such as cooking and managing their finances. That represents a significant drop in the number of disabled old people in the population. If the trends apparent in the United States 14 years ago had continued, researchers calculate there would be an additional one million disabled elderly people in today&amp;rsquo;s population. According to Manton, slowing the trend has saved the United States government&amp;rsquo;s Medicare system more than $200 billion, suggesting that the greying of America&amp;rsquo;s population may prove less of a financial burden than expected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The increasing self-reliance of many elderly people is probably linked to a massive increase in the use of simple home medical aids. For instance, the use of raised toilet seats has more than doubled since the start of the study, and the use of bath seats has grown by more than 50%. These developments also bring some health benefits, according to a report from the MacArthur Foundation&amp;rsquo;s research group on successful ageing. The group found that those elderly people who were able to retain a sense of independence were more likely to stay healthy in old age.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maintaining a level of daily physical activity may help mental functioning, says Carl Cotman, a neuroscientist at the University of California at Irvine. He found that rats that exercise on a treadmill have raised levels of brain-derived neurotrophic factor coursing through their brains. Cotman believes this hormone, which keeps neurons functioning, may prevent the brains of active humans from deteriorating.
As part of the same study, Teresa Seeman, a social epidemiologist at the University of Southern California in Los Angeles, found a connection between self-esteem and stress in people over 70. In laboratory simulations of challenging activities such as driving, those who felt in control of their lives pumped out lower levels of stress hormones such as cortisol. Chronically high levels of these hormones have been linked to heart disease.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But independence can have drawbacks. Seeman found that elderly people who felt emotionally isolated maintained higher levels of stress hormones even when asleep. The research suggests that older people fare best when they feel independent but know they can get help when they need it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lsquo;Like much research into ageing, these results support common sense,&amp;rsquo; says Seeman. They also show that we may be underestimating the impact of these simple factors. &amp;lsquo;The sort of thing that your grandmother always told you turns out to be right on target,&amp;rsquo; she says.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R6.2.3 Numeration</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.2.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.2.3/</guid><description>
&lt;p>One of the first great intellectual feats of a young child is learning how to talk, closely followed by learning how to count. From earliest childhood we are so bound up with our system of numeration that it is a feat of imagination to consider the problems faced by early humans who had not yet developed this facility. Careful consideration of our system of numeration leads to the conviction that, rather than being a facility that comes naturally to a person, it is one of the great and remarkable achievements of the human race.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is impossible to learn the sequence of events that led to our developing the concept of number. Even the earliest of tribes had a system of numeration that, if not advanced, was sufficient for the tasks that they had to perform. Our ancestors had little use for actual numbers; instead their considerations would have been more of the kind Is this enough? rather than How many? when they were engaged in food gathering, for example. However, when early humans first began to reflect on the nature of things around them, they discovered that they needed an idea of number simply to keep their thoughts in order. As they began to settle, grow plants and herd animals, the need for a sophisticated number system became paramount. It will never be known how and when this numeration ability developed, but it is certain that numeration was well developed by the time humans had formed even semipermanent settlements.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Evidence of early stages of arithmetic and numeration can be readily found. The indigenous peoples of Tasmania were only able to count one, two, many; those of South Africa counted one, two, two and one, two twos, two twos and one, and so on. But in real situations the number and words are often accompanied by gestures to help resolve any confusion. For example, when using the one, two, many type of system, the word many would mean, Look at my hands and see how many fingers I am showing you. This basic approach is limited in the range of numbers that it can express, but this range will generally suffice when dealing with the simpler aspects of human existence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The lack of ability of some cultures to deal with large numbers is not really surprising. European languages, when traced back to their earlier version, are very poor in number words and expressions. The ancient Gothic word for ten, tachund, is used to express the number 100 as tachund tachund. By the seventh century, the word teon had become interchangeable with the tachund or hund of the Anglo-Saxon language, and so 100 was denoted as hund teontig, or ten times ten. The average person in the seventh century in Europe was not as familiar with numbers as we are today. In fact, to qualify as a witness in a court of law a man had to be able to count to nine!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perhaps the most fundamental step in developing a sense of number is not the ability to count, but rather to see that a number is really an abstract idea instead of a simple attachment to a group of particular objects. It must have been within the grasp of the earliest humans to conceive that four birds are distinct from two birds; however, it is not an elementary step to associate the number 4, as connected with four birds, to the number 4, as connected with four rocks. Associating a number as one of the qualities of a specific object is a great hindrance to the development of a true number sense. When the number 4 can be registered in the mind as a specific word, independent of the object being referenced, the individual is ready to take the first step toward the development of a notational system for numbers and, from there, to arithmetic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Traces of the very first stages in the development of numeration can be seen in several living languages today. The numeration system of the Tsimshian language in British Columbia contains seven distinct sets of words for numbers according to the class of the item being counted: for counting flat objects and animals, for round objects and time, for people, for long objects and trees, for canoes, for measures, and for counting when no particular object is being numerated. It seems that the last is a later development while the first six groups show the relics of an older system. This diversity of number names can also be found in some widely used languages such as Japanese.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Intermixed with the development of a number sense is the development of an ability to count. Counting is not directly related to the formation of a number concept because it is possible to count by matching the items being counted against a group of pebbles, grains of corn, or the counter&amp;rsquo;s fingers. These aids would have been indispensable to very early people who would have found the process impossible without some form of mechanical aid. Such aids, while different, are still used even by the most educated in today&amp;rsquo;s society due to their convenience. All counting ultimately involves reference to something other than the things being counted. At first it may have been grains or pebbles but now it is a memorised sequence of words that happen to be the names of the numbers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R6.3.1</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.3.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.3.1/</guid><description>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Lumière Brothers opened their Cinematographe, at 14 Boulevard des Capucines in Paris, to 100 paying customers over 100 years ago, on December 8, 1895. Before the eyes of the stunned, thrilled audience, photographs came to life and moved across a flat screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>So ordinary and routine has this become to us that it takes a determined leap of the imagination to grasp the impact of those first moving images. But it is worth trying, for to understand the initial shock of those images is to understand the extraordinary power and magic of cinema, the unique, hypnotic quality that has made film the most dynamic, effective art form of the 20th century.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>One of the Lumière Brothers&amp;rsquo; earliest films was a 30-second piece which showed a section of a railway platform flooded with sunshine. A train appears and heads straight for the camera. And that is all that happens. Yet the Russian director Andrei Tarkovsky, one of the greatest of all film artists, described the film as a &amp;lsquo;work of genius&amp;rsquo;. &amp;lsquo;As the train approached,&amp;rsquo; wrote Tarkovsky, &amp;lsquo;panic started in the theatre: people jumped and ran away. That was the moment when cinema was born. The frightened audience could not accept that they were watching a mere picture. Pictures were still, only reality moved; this must, therefore, be reality. In their confusion, they feared that a real train was about to crush them.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Early cinema audiences often experienced the same contusion. In time, the idea of film became familiar, the magic was accepted -but it never stopped being magic. Film has never lost its unique power to embrace its audiences and transport them to a different world. For Tarkovsky, the key to that magic was the way in which cinema created a dynamic image of the real flow of events. A still picture could only imply the existence of time, while time in a novel passed at the whim of the reader. But in cinema, the real, objective flow of time was captured.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>One effect of this realism was to educate the world about itself. For cinema makes the world smaller. Long before people travelled to America or anywhere else, they knew what other places looked like; they knew how other people worked and lived. Overwhelmingly, the lives recorded - at least in film fiction - have been American. From the earliest days of the industry, Hollywood has dominated the world film market. American imagery - the cars, the cities, the cowboys - became the primary imagery of film. Film carried American life and values around the globe.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>And, thanks to film, future generations will know the 20th century more intimately than any other period. We can only imagine what life was like in the 14th century or in classical Greece. But the life of the modern world has been recorded on film in massive, encyclopaedic detail. We shall be known better than any preceding generations.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="g">G&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The &amp;lsquo;star&amp;rsquo; was another natural consequence of cinema. The cinema star was effectively born in 1910. Film personalities have such an immediate presence that, inevitably, they become super-real. Because we watch them so closely and because everybody in the world seems to know who they are, they appear more real to us than we do ourselves. The star as magnified human self is one of cinema&amp;rsquo;s most strange and enduring legacies.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="h">H&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cinema has also given a new lease of life to the idea of the story. When the Lumière Brothers and other pioneers began showing off this new invention, it was by no means obvious how it would be used. All that mattered at first was the wonder of movement. Indeed, some said that, once this novelty had worn off, cinema would fade away. It was no more than a passing gimmick, a fairground attraction.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="i">I&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Cinema might, for example, have become primarily a documentary form. Or it might have developed like television - as a strange, noisy transfer of music, information and narrative. But what happened was that it became, overwhelmingly, a medium for telling stories. Originally these were conceived as short stories - early producers doubted the ability of audiences to concentrate for more than the length of a reel. Then, in 1912, an Italian 2-hour film was hugely successful, and Hollywood settled upon the novel-length narrative that remains the dominant cinematic convention of today.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="j">J&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>And it has all happened so quickly. Almost unbelievably, it is a mere 100 years since that train arrived and the audience screamed and fled, convinced by the dangerous reality of what they saw, and, perhaps, suddenly aware that the world could never be the same again - that, maybe, it could be better, brighter, more astonishing, more real than reality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R6.3.2 Motivating Employees under Adverse Conditions</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.3.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.3.2/</guid><description>
&lt;h4 id="the-challenge">THE CHALLENGE&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>It is a great deal easier to motivate employees in a growing organisation than a declining one. When organisations are expanding and adding personnel, promotional opportunities, pay rises, and the excitement of being associated with a dynamic organisation create feelings of optimism. Management is able to use the growth to entice and encourage employees. When an organisation is shrinking, the best and most mobile workers are prone to leave voluntarily. Unfortunately, they are the ones the organisation can least afford to lose - those with the highest skills and experience. The minor employees remain because their job options are limited.
Morale also suffers during decline. People fear they may be the next to be made redundant. Productivity often suffers, as employees spend their time sharing rumours and providing one another with moral support rather than focusing on their jobs. For those whose jobs are secure, pay increases are rarely possible. Pay cuts, unheard of during times of growth, may even be imposed. The challenge to management is how to motivate employees under such retrenchment conditions. The ways of meeting this challenge can be broadly divided into six Key Points, which are outlined below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="key-point-one">KEY POINT ONE&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>There is an abundance of evidence to support the motivational benefits that result from carefully matching people to jobs. For example, if the job is running a small business or an autonomous unit within a larger business, high achievers should be sought. However, if the job to be filled is a managerial post in a large bureaucratic organisation, a candidate who has a high need for power and a low need for affiliation should be selected. Accordingly, high achievers should not be put into jobs that are inconsistent with their needs. High achievers will do best when the job provides moderately challenging goals and where there is independence and feedback. However, it should be remembered that not everybody is motivated by jobs that are high in independence, variety and responsibility.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="key-point-two">KEY POINT TWO&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The literature on goal-setting theory suggests that managers should ensure that all employees have specific goals and receive comments on how well they are doing in those goals. For those with high achievement needs, typically a minority in any organisation, the existence of external goals is less important because high achievers are already internally motivated. The next factor to be determined is whether the goals should be assigned by a manager or collectively set in conjunction with the employees. The answer to that depends on perceptions of goal acceptance and the organisation&amp;rsquo;s culture. If resistance to goals is expected, the use of participation in goal-setting should increase acceptance. If participation is inconsistent with the culture, however, goals should be assigned. If participation and the culture are incongruous, employees are likely to perceive the participation process as manipulative and be negatively affected by it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="key-point-three">KEY POINT THREE&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Regardless of whether goals are achievable or well within management&amp;rsquo;s perceptions of the employee&amp;rsquo;s ability, if employees see them as unachievable they will reduce their effort. Managers must be sure, therefore, that employees feel confident that their efforts can lead to performance goals. For managers, this means that employees must have the capability of doing the job and must regard the appraisal process as valid.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="key-point-four">KEY POINT FOUR&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Since employees have different needs, what acts as a reinforcement for one may not for another. Managers could use their knowledge of each employee to personalise the rewards over which they have control. Some of the more obvious rewards that managers allocate include pay, promotions, autonomy, job scope and depth, and the opportunity to participate in goal-setting and decision-making.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="key-point-five">KEY POINT FIVE&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Managers need to make rewards contingent on performance. To reward factors other than performance will only reinforce those other factors. Key rewards such as pay increases and promotions or advancements should be allocated for the attainment of the employee&amp;rsquo;s specific goals. Consistent with maximising the impact of rewards, managers should look for ways to increase their visibility. Eliminating the secrecy surrounding pay by openly communicating everyone&amp;rsquo;s remuneration, publicising performance bonuses and allocating annual salary increases in a lump sum rather than spreading them out over an entire year are examples of actions that will make rewards more visible and potentially more motivating.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="key-point-six">KEY POINT SIX&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The way rewards are distributed should be transparent so that employees perceive that rewards or outcomes are equitable and equal to the inputs given. On a simplistic level, experience, abilities, effort and other obvious inputs should explain differences in pay, responsibility and other obvious outcomes. The problem, however, is complicated by the existence of dozens of inputs and outcomes and by the fact that employee groups place different degrees of importance on them. For instance, a study comparing clerical and production workers identified nearly twenty inputs and outcomes. The clerical workers considered factors such as quality of work performed and job knowledge near the top of their list, but these were at the bottom of the production workers&amp;rsquo; list. Similarly, production workers thought that the most important inputs were intelligence and personal involvement with task accomplishment, two factors that were quite low in the importance ratings of the clerks. There were also important, though less dramatic, differences on the outcome side. For example, production workers rated advancement very highly, whereas clerical workers rated advancement in the lower third of their list. Such findings suggest that one person&amp;rsquo;s equity is another&amp;rsquo;s inequity, so an ideal should probably weigh different inputs and outcomes according to employee group.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R6.3.3 The Search for the Anti-aging Pill</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.3.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.3.3/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>In government laboratories and elsewhere, scientists are seeking a drug able to prolonglife and youthful vigor. Studies of caloric restriction are showing the way&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>As researchers on aging noted recently, no treatment on the market today has been proved to slow human aging - the build-up of molecular and cellular damage that increases vulnerability to infirmity as we grow older. But one intervention, consumption of a low-calorie* yet nutritionally balanced diet, works incredibly well in a broad range of animals, increasing longevity and prolonging good health. Those findings suggest that caloric restriction could delay aging and increase longevity in humans, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, for maximum benefit, people would probably have to reduce their caloric intake by roughly thirty per cent, equivalent to dropping from 2,500 calories a day to 1,750. Few mortals could stick to that harsh a regimen, especially for years on end. But what if someone could create a pill that mimicked the physiological effects of eating less without actually forcing people to eat less? Could such a ‘caloric-restriction mimetic’, as we call it, enable people to stay healthy longer, postponing age-related disorders (such as diabetes, arteriosclerosis, heart disease and cancer) until very late in life? Scientists first posed this question in the mid-1990s, after researchers came upon a chemical agent that in rodents seemed to reproduce many of caloric restriction’s benefits. No compound that would safely achieve the same feat in people has been found yet, but the search has been informative and has fanned hope that caloric-restriction (CR) mimetics can indeed be developed eventually.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The benefits of caloric restriction
The hunt for CR mimetics grew out of a desire to better understand caloric restriction&amp;rsquo;s many effects on the body. Scientists first recognized the value of the practice more than 60 years ago, when they found that rats fed a low-calorie diet lived longer on average than free-feeding rats and also had a reduced incidence of conditions that become increasingly common in old age. What is more, some of the treated animals survived longer than the oldest-living animals in the control group, which means that the maximum lifespan (the oldest attainable age), not merely the normal lifespan, increased. Various interventions, such as infection-fighting drugs, can increase a population’s average survival time, but only approaches that slow the body’s rate of aging will increase the maximum lifespan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The rat findings have been replicated many times and extended to creatures ranging from yeast to fruit flies, worms, fish, spiders, mice and hamsters. Until fairly recently, the studies were limited to short-lived creatures genetically distant from humans. But caloric-restriction projects underway in two species more closely related to humans - rhesus and squirrel monkeys - have made scientists optimistic that CR mimetics could help people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The monkey projects demonstrate that, compared with control animals that eat normally, caloric-restricted monkeys have lower body temperatures and levels of the pancreatic hormone insulin, and they retain more youthful levels of certain hormones that tend to fall with age.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The caloric-restricted animals also look better on indicators of risk for age-related diseases. For example, they have lower blood pressure and triglyceride levels (signifying a decreased likelihood of heart disease), and they have more normal blood glucose levels (pointing to a reduced risk for diabetes, which is marked by unusually high blood glucose levels). Further, it has recently been shown that rhesus monkeys kept on caloric-restricted diets for an extended time (nearly IS years) have less chronic disease. They and the other monkeys must be followed still longer, however, to know whether low-calorie intake can increase both average and maximum lifespans in monkeys. Unlike the multitude of elixirs being touted as the latest anti-aging cure, CR mimetics would alter fundamental processes that underlie aging. We aim to develop compounds that fool cells into activating maintenance and repair.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How a prototype caloric-restriction mimetic works
The best-studied candidate for a caloric-restriction mimetic, 2DG (2-deoxy-D-glucose), works by interfering with the way cells process glucose. It has proved toxic at some doses in animals and so cannot be used in humans. But it has demonstrated that chemicals can replicate the effects of caloric restriction; the trick is finding the right one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cells use the glucose from food to generate ATP (adenosine triphosphate), the molecule that powers many activities in the body. By limiting food intake, caloric restriction minimizes the amount of glucose entering cells and decreases ATP generation. When 2DG is administered to animals that eat normally, glucose reaches cells in abundance but the drug prevents most of it from being processed and thus reduces ATP synthesis. Researchers have proposed several explanations for why interruption of glucose processing and ATP production might retard aging. One possibility relates to the ATP-making machinery’s emission of free radicals, which are thought to contribute to aging and to such age-related diseases as cancer by damaging cells. Reduced operation of the machinery should limit their production and thereby constrain the damage. Another hypothesis suggests that decreased processing of glucose could indicate to cells that food is scarce (even if it isn’t) and induce them to shift into an anti-aging mode that emphasizes preservation of the organism over such ‘luxuries’ as growth and reproduction.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R6.4.1 Doctoring sales</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.4.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.4.1/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Pharmaceuticals is one of the most profitable industries in North America. But do the drugs industry’s sales and marketing strategies go too far?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A few months ago Kim Schaefer, sales representative of a major global pharmaceutical company, walked into a medical center in New York to bring information and free samples of her company&amp;rsquo;s latest products. That day she was lucky - a doctor was available to see her. ‘The last rep offered me a trip to Florida. What do you have?’ the physician asked. He wets only half joking.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>What was on offer that day was a pair of tickets for a New York musical. But on any given day, what Schaefer can offer is typical for today’s drugs rep - a car trunk full of promotional gifts and gadgets, a budget that could buy lunches and dinners for a small country, hundreds of free drug samples and the freedom to give a physician $200 to prescribe her new product to the next six patients who fit the drug’s profile. And she also has a few $ 1,000 honoraria to offer in exchange for doctors’ attendance at her company’s next educational lecture.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Selling pharmaceuticals is a daily exercise in ethical judgement. Salespeople like Schaefer walk the line between the common practice of buying a prospect’s time with a free meal, and bribing doctors to prescribe their drugs. They work in an industry highly criticized for its sales and marketing practices, but find themselves in the middle of the age-old chicken-or-egg question - businesses won’t use strategies that don’t work, so are doctors to blame for the escalating extravagance of pharmaceutical marketing? Or is it the industry’s responsibility to decide the boundaries?&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The explosion in the sheer number of salespeople in the field - and the amount of funding used to promote their causes - forces close examination of the pressures, influences and relationships between drug reps and doctors. Salespeople provide much-needed information and education to physicians. In many cases the glossy brochures, article reprints and prescriptions they deliver are primary sources of drug education for healthcare givers. With the huge investment the industry has placed in face-to-face selling, salespeople have essentially become specialists in one drug or group of drugs - a tremendous advantage in getting the attention of busy doctors in need of quick information.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>But the sales push rarely stops in the office. The flashy brochures and pamphlets left by the sales reps are often followed up with meals at expensive restaurants, meetings in warm and sunny places, and an inundation of promotional gadgets. Rarely do patients watch a doctor write with a pen that isn’t emblazoned with a drug’s name, or see a nurse use a tablet not bearing a pharmaceutical company&amp;rsquo;s logo. Millions of dollars are spent by pharmaceutical companies on promotional products like coffee mugs, shirts, umbrellas, and golf balls. Money well spent? It’s hard to tell. ‘I&amp;rsquo;ve been the recipient of golf balls from one company and I use them, but it doesn’t make me prescribe their medicine,’ says one doctor. ‘I tend to think I’m not influenced by what they give me.’&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Free samples of new and expensive drugs might be the single most effective way of getting doctors and patients to become loyal to a product. Salespeople hand out hundreds of dollars’ worth of samples each week - $7.2 billion worth of them in one year. Though few comprehensive studies have been conducted, one by the University of Washington investigated how drug sample availability affected what physicians prescribe. A total of 131 doctors self-reported their prescribing patterns - the conclusion was that the availability of samples led them to dispense and prescribe drugs that differed from their preferred drug choice.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="g">G&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The bottom line is that pharmaceutical companies as a whole invest more in marketing than they do in research and development. And patients are the ones who pay - in the form of sky-rocketing prescription prices - for every pen that’s handed out, every free theatre ticket, and every steak dinner eaten. In the end the fact remains that pharmaceutical companies have every right to make a profit and will continue to find new ways to increase sales. But as the medical world continues to grapple with what&amp;rsquo;s acceptable and what’s not, it is clear that companies must continue to be heavily scrutinized for their sales and marketing strategies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R6.4.2 Do literate women make better mothers?</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.4.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.4.2/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Children in developing countries are healthier and more likely to survive past the age of five when their mothers can read and write. Experts in public health accepted this idea decades ago, but until now no one has been able to show that a woman’s ability to read in itself improves her children’s chances of survival.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most literate women learnt to read in primary school, and the fact that a woman has had an education may simply indicate her family&amp;rsquo;s wealth or that it values its children more highly. Now a long-term study carried out in Nicaragua has eliminated these factors by showing that teaching reading to poor adult women, who would otherwise have remained illiterate, has a direct effect on their children’s health and survival.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 1979, the government of Nicaragua established a number of social programmes, including a National Literacy Crusade. By 1985, about 300,000 illiterate adults from all over the country, many of whom had never attended primary school, had learnt how to read, write and use numbers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During this period, researchers from the Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine, the Central American Institute of Health in Nicaragua, the National Autonomous University of Nicaragua and the Costa Rican Institute of Health interviewed nearly 3,000 women, some of whom had learnt to read as children, some during the literacy crusade and some who had never learnt at all. The women were asked how many children they had given birth to and how many of them had died in infancy. The research teams also examined the surviving children to find out how well-nourished they were.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The investigators’ findings were striking. In the late 1970s, the infant mortality rate for the children of illiterate mothers was around 110 deaths per thousand live births. At this point in their lives, those mothers who later went on to learn to read had a similar level of child mortality (105/1000). For women educated in primary school, however, the infant mortality rate was significantly lower, at 80 per thousand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 1985, after the National Literacy Crusade had ended, the infant mortality figures for those who remained illiterate and for those educated in primary school remained more or less unchanged. For those women who learnt to read through the campaign, the infant mortality rate was 84 per thousand, an impressive 21 points lower than for those women who were still illiterate. The children of the newly-literate mothers were also better nourished than those of women who could not read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why are the children of literate mothers better off? According to Peter Sandiford of the Liverpool School of Tropical Medicine, no one knows for certain. Child health was not on the curriculum during the women’s lessons, so he and his colleagues are looking at other factors. They are working with the same group of 3,000 women, to try to find out whether reading mothers make better use of hospitals and clinics, opt for smaller families, exert more control at home, learn modern childcare techniques more quickly, or whether they merely have more respect for themselves and their children.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Nicaraguan study may have important implications for governments and aid agencies that need to know where to direct their resources. Sandiford says that there is increasing evidence that female education, at any age, is ‘an important health intervention in its own right’. The results of the study lend support to the World Bank’s recommendation that education budgets in developing countries should be increased, not just to help their economies, but also to improve child health.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>‘We’ve known for a long time that maternal education is important,’ says John Cleland of the London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine. ‘But we thought that even if we started educating girls today, we&amp;rsquo;d have to wait a generation for the pay-off. The Nicaraguan study suggests we may be able to bypass that.’&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cleland warns that the Nicaraguan crusade was special in many ways, and similar campaigns elsewhere might not work as well. It is notoriously difficult to teach adults skills that do not have an immediate impact on their everyday lives, and many literacy campaigns in other countries have been much less successful. ‘The crusade was part of a larger effort to bring a better life to the people,’ says Cleland. Replicating these conditions in other countries will be a major challenge for development workers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R6.4.3</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.4.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/r6.4.3/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Persistent bullying is one of the worst experiences a child can face. How can it be prevented?Peter Smith, Professor of Psychology at the University of Sheffield, directed the Sheffield Anti-Bullying Intervention Project, funded by the Department for Education.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Here he reports on his findings.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Bullying can take a variety of forms, from the verbal - being taunted or called hurtful names - to the physical - being kicked or shoved - as well as indirect forms, such as being excluded from social groups. A survey I conducted with Irene Whitney found that in British primary schools up to a quarter of pupils reported experience of bullying, which in about one in ten cases was persistent. There was less bullying in secondary schools, with about one in twenty-five suffering persistent bullying, but these cases may be particularly recalcitrant.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Bullying is clearly unpleasant, and can make the child experiencing it feel unworthy and depressed. In extreme cases it can even lead to suicide, though this is thankfully rare. Victimised pupils are more likely to experience difficulties with interpersonal relationships as adults, while children who persistently bully are more likely to grow up to be physically violent, and convicted of anti-social offences.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Until recently, not much was known about the topic, and little help was available to teachers to deal with bullying. Perhaps as a consequence, schools would often deny the problem. ‘There is no bullying at this school’ has been a common refrain, almost certainly untrue. Fortunately more schools are now saying: ‘There is not much bullying here, but when it occurs we have a clear policy for dealing with it.’&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Three factors are involved in this change. First is an awareness of the severity of the problem. Second, a number of resources to help tackle bullying have become available in Britain. For example, the Scottish Council for Research in Education produced a package of materials, Action Against Bullying, circulated to all schools in England and Wales as well as in Scotland in summer 1992, with a second pack, Supporting Schools Against Bullying, produced the following year. In Ireland, Guidelines on Countering Bullying Behaviour in Post-Primary Schools was published in 1993. Third, there is evidence that these materials work, and that schools can achieve something. This comes from carefully conducted ‘before and after’ evaluations of interventions in schools, monitored by a research team. In Norway, after an intervention campaign was introduced nationally, an evaluation of forty-two schools suggested that, over a two-year period, bullying was halved. The Sheffield investigation, which involved sixteen primary schools and seven secondary schools, found that most schools succeeded in reducing bullying.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="e">E&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Evidence suggests that a key step is to develop a policy on bullying, saying clearly what is meant by bullying, and giving explicit guidelines on what will be done if it occurs, what records will be kept, who will be informed, what sanctions will be employed. The policy should be developed through consultation, over a period of time - not just imposed from the head teacher’s office! Pupils, parents and staff should feel they have been involved in the policy, which needs to be disseminated and implemented effectively.
Other actions can be taken to back up the policy. There are ways of dealing with the topic through the curriculum, using video, drama and literature. These are useful for raising awareness, and can best be tied in to early phases of development, while the school is starting to discuss the issue of bullying. They are also useful in renewing the policy for new pupils, or revising it in the light of experience. But curriculum work alone may only have short-term effects; it should be an addition to policy work, not a substitute.
There are also ways of working with individual pupils, or in small groups. Assertiveness training for pupils who are liable to be victims is worthwhile, and certain approaches to group bullying such as ‘no blame’, can be useful in changing the behaviour of bullying pupils without confronting them directly, although other sanctions may be needed for those who continue with persistent bullying.
Work in the playground is important, too. One helpful step is to train lunchtime supervisors to distinguish bullying from playful fighting, and help them break up conflicts. Another possibility is to improve the playground environment, so that pupils are less likely to be led into bullying from boredom or frustration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="f">F&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>With these developments, schools can expect that at least the most serious kinds of bullying can largely be prevented. The more effort put in and the wider the whole school involvement, the more substantial the results are likely to be. The reduction in bullying - and the consequent improvement in pupil happiness - is surely a worthwhile objective.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>