<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notebook – Internet, Phones, Television</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/ielts/writing/internetphonestelevision/</link><description>Recent content in Internet, Phones, Television on Notebook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://note.codiy.net/docs/ielts/writing/internetphonestelevision/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Internet vs Newspaper</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/writing/internet/newspaper/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 10:01:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/writing/internet/newspaper/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Although more and more people read news on the Internet, newspapers will remain the most important source of news. Do you agree or disagree?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The Internet is beginning to rival newspapers as the best place to find information about what is happening in the world. I believe that this trend will continue, and the Internet will soon be just as important as the traditional press.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the one hand, I believe that newspapers will continue to be a vital source of information, even in the Internet age. Firstly, newspapers are the most traditional means of communicating the news, and not everyone wants to or is able to use the Internet instead. For example, old people or those in rural areas might not have the ability or opportunity to get online, while many of us simply prefer newspapers even if we do have Internet access. Secondly, newspapers can be trusted as reliable sources of news because they employ professional journalists and editors. Finally, many people like the experience of holding and reading a paper rather than looking at a computer screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, the Internet is likely to become just as popular as newspapers for a variety of reasons. The main reason is that it allows us much faster access to news in real time and wherever we are, on different gadgets and mobile devices. Another key benefit of online news compared to newspapers is the ability to share articles, discuss them with other people, give our views, and even contribute with our own updates on social media. For example, there has been an explosion in the use of platforms like Twitter and YouTube where anyone can share their news and views. A final point is that this source of news is less damaging to the environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In conclusion, I disagree with the view that newspapers will continue to be the main source of news, because I believe that the Internet will soon be equally important.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>