<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notebook – Traditional</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/ielts/writing/traditional/</link><description>Recent content in Traditional on Notebook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://note.codiy.net/docs/ielts/writing/traditional/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Traditional cultures vs technology develop</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/writing/traditional/technology/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 10:01:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/writing/traditional/technology/</guid><description>
&lt;h3 id="参考范文">参考范文&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It is inevitable that traditional cultures will be lost as technology develops. Technology and traditional cultures are incompatible. To what extent do you agree or disagree with this view?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Some people believe that technological developments lead to the loss of traditional cultures. I partly agree with this assertion;while it may be true in the case of some societies, others seem to be unaffected by technology and the modern world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the one hand, the advances in technology that have driven industrialisation in developed countries have certainly contributed to the disappearance of traditional ways of life. For example, in pre-industrial Britain, generations of families grew up in the same small village communities. These communities had a strong sense of identity, due to their shared customs and beliefs. However, developments in transport, communications and manufacturing led to the dispersal of families and village communities as people moved to the cities in search of work. Nowadays most British villages are inhabited by commuters, many of whom do not know their closest neighbours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, in some parts of the world traditional cultures still thrive. There are tribes in the Amazon Rainforest, for example, that have been completely untouched by the technological developments of the developed world. These tribal communities continue to hunt and gather food from the forest, and traditional skills are passed on to children by parents and elders. Other traditional cultures, such as farming communities in parts of Africa, are embracing communications technologies. Mobile phones give farmers access to information, from weather predictions to market prices, which helps them to prosper and therefore supports their culture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In conclusion, many traditional ways of life have been lost as a result of advances in technology, but other traditional communities have survived and even flourished.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Traditional festivals</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/writing/traditional/festivals/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 10:01:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/writing/traditional/festivals/</guid><description>
&lt;h3 id="参考范文">参考范文&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Most people have forgotten the meaning behind traditional or religious festivals; during festival periods, people nowadays only want to enjoy themselves. To what extent do you agree or disagree with this opinion?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Some people argue that we no longer remember the original meaning of festivals, and that most of us treat them as opportunities to have fun. While I agree that enjoyment seems to be the priority during festival times, I do not agree that people have forgotten what these festivals mean.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the one hand, religious and traditional festivals have certainly become times for celebration. In the UK, Christmas is a good example of a festival period when people are most concerned with shopping, giving and receiving presents, decorating their homes and enjoying traditional meals with their families. Most people look forward to Christmas as a holiday period, rather than a time to practise religion. Similar behaviour can be seen during non-religious festivals, such as Bonfire Night. People associate this occasion with making fires, watching firework displays, and perhaps going to large events in local parks; in other words, enjoyment is people’s primary goal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, I disagree with the idea that the underlying meaning of such festivals has been forgotten. In UK primary schools, children learn in detail about the religious reasons for celebrating Christmas, Easter and a variety of festivals in other religions. For example, in late December, children sing Christmas songs which have a religious content, and they may even perform nativity plays telling the story of Jesus’ birth. Families also play a role in passing knowledge of religious festivals’ deeper significance on to the next generation. The same is true for festivals that have a historical background, such as Bonfire Night or Halloween, in the sense that people generally learn the stories behind these occasions at an early age.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In conclusion, although people mainly want to enjoy themselves during festivals, I believe that they are still aware of the reasons for these celebrations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Traditional ideas and younger generations</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/writing/traditional/ideas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 10:01:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/writing/traditional/ideas/</guid><description>
&lt;h3 id="参考范文">参考范文&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The older generations tend to have very traditional ideas about how people should live, think and behave. However, some people believe that these ideas are not helpful in preparing younger generations for modern life. To what extent do you agree or disagree with this view?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It is true that many older people believe in traditional values that often seem incompatible with the needs of younger people. While I agree that some traditional ideas are outdated, I believe that others are still useful and should not be forgotten.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the one hand, many of the ideas that elderly people have about life are becoming less relevant for younger people. In the past, for example, people were advised to learn a profession and find a secure job for life, but today’s workers expect much more variety and diversity from their careers. At the same time, the ‘rules’ around relationships are being eroded as young adults make their own choices about who and when to marry. But perhaps the greatest disparity between the generations can be seen in their attitudes towards gender roles. The traditional roles of men and women, as breadwinners and housewives, are no longer accepted as necessary or appropriate by most younger people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, some traditional views and values are certainly applicable to the modern world. For example, older generations attach great importance to working hard, doing one’s best, and taking pride in one’s work, and these behaviours can surely benefit young people as they enter today’s competitive job market. Other characteristics that are perhaps seen as traditional are politeness and good manners. In our globalized world, young adults can expect to come into contact with people from a huge variety of backgrounds, and it is more important than ever to treat others with respect. Finally, I believe that young people would lead happier lives if they had a more “old-fashioned” sense of community and neighborliness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In conclusion, although the views of older people may sometimes seem unhelpful in today’s world, we should not dismiss all traditional ideas as irrelevant.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Traditional music vs international music</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/writing/traditional/music/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 10:01:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/writing/traditional/music/</guid><description>
&lt;h3 id="参考范文">参考范文&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>There are many different types of music in the world today. Why do we need music? Is the traditional music of a country more important than the international music that is heard everywhere nowadays?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It is true that a rich variety of musical styles can be found around the world. Music is a vital part of all human cultures for a range of reasons, and I would argue that traditional music is more important than modern, international music.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Music is something that accompanies all of us throughout our lives. As children, we are taught songs by our parents and teachers as a means of learning language, or simply as a form of enjoyment. Children delight in singing with others, and it would appear that the act of singing in a group creates a connection between participants, regardless of their age. Later in life, people’s musical preferences develop, and we come to see our favourite songs as part of our life stories. Music both expresses and arouses emotions in a way that words alone cannot. In short, it is difficult to imagine life without it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my opinion, traditional music should be valued over the international music that has become so popular. International pop music is often catchy and fun, but it is essentially a commercial product that is marketed and sold by business people. Traditional music, by contrast, expresses the culture, customs and history of a country. Traditional styles, such as …(example)…, connect us to the past and form part of our cultural identity. It would be a real pity if pop music became so predominant that these national styles disappeared.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In conclusion, music is a necessary part of human existence, and I believe that traditional music should be given more importance than international music.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>