<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notebook – IELTS Reading Articles</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/ielts/</link><description>Recent content in IELTS Reading Articles on Notebook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 13:11:52 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://note.codiy.net/docs/ielts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: R4.2.1 Lost for Words</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.2.1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 13:11:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.2.1/</guid><description>
&lt;h3 id="many-minority-languages-are-on-the-danger-lists">Many Minority Languages Are on the Danger Lists&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the Native American Navajo nation, which sprawls across four states in the American south-west, the native language is dying. Most of its speakers are middle-aged or elderly. Although many students take classes in Navajo, the schools are run in English. Street signs, supermarket goods and even their own newspaper are all in English. Not surprisingly, linguists doubt that any native speakers of Navajo will remain in a hundred years’ time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Navajo is far from alone. Half the world’s 6,800 languages are likely to vanish within two generations—that’s one language lost every ten days. Never before has the planet’s linguistic diversity shrunk at such a pace. ‘At the moment, we are heading for about three or four languages dominating the world,’ says Mark Pagel, an evolutionary biologist at the University of Reading. ‘It’s a mass extinction, and whether we will ever rebound from the loss is difficult to know.’&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Isolation breeds linguistic diversity: as a result, the world is peppered with languages spoken by only a few people. Only 250 languages have more than a million speakers, and at least 3,000 have fewer than 2,500. It is not necessarily these small languages that are about to disappear. Navajo is considered endangered despite having 150,000 speakers. What makes a language endangered is not just the number of speakers, but how old they are. If it is spoken by children it is relatively safe. The critically endangered languages are those that are only spoken by the elderly, according to Michael Krauss, director of the Alassk Native Language Center, in Fairbanks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why do people reject the language of their parents? It begins with a crisis of confidence, when a small community finds itself alongside a larger, wealthier society, says Nicholas Ostler, of Britain’s Foundation for Endangered Languages, in Bath. ‘People lose faith in their culture,’ he says. ‘When the next generation reaches their teens, they might not want to be induced into the old traditions.’&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The change is not always voluntary. Quite often, governments try to kill off a minority language by banning its use in public or discouraging its use in schools, all to promote national unity. The former US policy of running Indian reservation schools in English, for example, effectively put languages such as Navajo on the danger list. But Salikoko Mufwene, who chairs the Linguistics department at the University of Chicago, argues that the deadliest weapon is not government policy but economic globalization. ‘Native Americans have not lost pride in their language, but they have had to adapt to socio-economic pressures,’ he says. ‘They cannot refuse to speak English if most commercial activity is in English.’ But are languages worth saving? At the very least, there is a loss of data for the study of languages and their evolution, which relies on comparisons between languages, both living and dead. When an unwritten and unrecorded language disappears, it is lost to science.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Language is also intimately bound up with culture, so it may be difficult to preserve one without the other. ‘If a person shifts from Navajo to English, they lose something,’ Mufwene says. ‘Moreover, the loss of diversity may also deprive us of different ways of looking at the world.’ says Pagel. There is mounting evidence that learning a language produces physiological changes in the brain. ‘Your brain and mine are different from the brain of someone who speaks French, for instance,’ Pagel says, and this could affect our thoughts and perceptions. ‘The patterns and connections we make among various concepts may be structured by the linguistic habits of our community.’&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So despite linguists’ best efforts, many languages will disappear over the next century. But a growing interest in cultural identity may prevent the direst predictions from coming true. ‘The key to fostering diversity is for people to learn their ancestral tongue, as well as the dominant language,’ says Doug Whalen, founder and president of the Endangered Language Fund in New Haven, Connecticut . ‘Most of these languages will not survive without a large degree of bilingualism,’ he says. In New Zealand, classes for children have slowed the erosion of Maori and rekindled interest in the language. A similar approach in Hawaii has produced about 8,000 new speakers of Polynesian languages in the past few years. In California,‘apprentice’ programs have provided life support to several indigenous languages. Volunteer ‘apprentices’ pair up with one of the last living speakers of a Native American tongue to learn a traditional skill such as basket weaving, with instruction exclusively in the endangered language. After about 300 hours of training they are generally sufficiently fluent to transmit the language to the next generation. But Mufwene says that preventing a language dying out is not the same as giving it new life by using it every day. ‘Preserving a language is more like preserving fruits in a jar,’ he says.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, preservation can bring a language back from the dead. There are examples of languages that have survived in written form and then been revived by later generations. But a written form is essential for this, so the mere possibility of revival has led many speakers of endangered languages to develop systems of writing where none existed before.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R4.2.2 Alternative Medicine in Australia</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.2.2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 13:11:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.2.2/</guid><description>
&lt;p>  The first students to study alternative medicine at university level in Australia began their four-year, full-time course at the University of Technology Sydney, in early 1994. Their course covered, among other therapies, acupuncture. The theory they learnt is based on the traditional Chinese explanation of this ancient healing art that it can regulate the flow of‘Qi’ or energy through pathways in the body. This course reflects how far some alternative therapies have come in their struggle for acceptance by the medical establishment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Australia has been unusual in the Western world in having a very conservative attitude to natural or alternative therapies, according to Dr Paul Laver, a lecturer in Public Health at the University of Sydney.‘We’ve had a tradition of doctors being fairly powerful and I guess they are pretty loath to allow any pretenders to their position to come into it.’ In many other industrialized countries, orthodox and alternative medicine have worked‘hand in glove’ for years. In Europe, only orthodox doctors can prescribe herbal medicine. In Germany, plant remedies account for 10% of the national turnover of pharmaceuticals. Americans made more visits to alternative therapists than to orthodox doctors in 1990, and each year they spend about $US12 billion on therapies that have not been scientifically tested.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Disenchantment with orthodox medicine has seen the popularity of alternative therapies in Australia climb steadily during the past 20 years. In a 1983 national health survey, 1.9% of people said they had contacted a chiropractor, naturopath, osteopath, acupuncturist or herbalist in the two weeks prior to the survey. By 1990, this figure had risen to 2.6% of the population. The 550,000 consultations with alternative therapists reported in the 1990 survey represented about an eighth of the total number of consultations with medically qualified personnel covered by the survey, according to Dr Laver and colleagues writing in the Australian Journal of Public Health in 1993. ‘A better educated and less accepting public has become disillusioned with the experts in general, and increasingly skeptical about science and empirically based knowledge,’ they said.‘The high standing of professionals, including doctors, has been eroded as a consequence.’&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rather than resisting or criticizing this trend, increasing numbers of Australian doctors, particularly younger ones, are forming group practices with alternative therapists or taking courses themselves, particularly in acupuncture and herbalism. Part of the incentive was financial, Dr Laver said. ‘ The bottom line is that most general practitioners are business people. If they see potential clientele going elsewhere, they might want to be able to offer a similar service.'&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 1993, Dr Laver and his colleagues published a survey of 289 Sydney people who attended eight alternative therapists’ practices in Sydney. These practices offered a wide range of alternative therapies from 25 therapists. Those surveyed had experienced chronicillnesses, for which orthodox medicine had been able to provide little relief. They commented that they liked the holistic approach of their alternative therapists and the friendly, concerned and detailed attention they had received. The cold, impersonal manner of orthodox doctors featured in the survey. An increasing exodus from their clinics, coupled with this and a number of other relevant surveys carried out in Australia, all pointing to orthodox doctors’ inadequacies, have led mainstream doctors themselves to begin to admit they could learn from the personal style of alternative therapists. Dr Patrick Store, President of the Royal College of General Practitioners, concurs that orthodox doctors could learn a lot about bedside manner and advising patients on preventative health from alternative therapists.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to the Australian Journal of Public Health, 18% of patients visiting alternative therapists do so because they suffer from musculo-skeletal complaints, 12% suffer from digestive problems, which is only 1% more than those suffering from emotional problems. Those suffering from respiratory complaints represent 7% of their patients, and candida sufferers represent an equal percentage. Headache sufferers and those complaining of general ill health represent 6% and 5% of patients respectively and a further 4% see therapists for general health maintenance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The survey suggested that complementary medicine is probably a better term than alternative medicine. Alternative medicine appears to be an adjunct sought in times of disenchantment when conventional medicine seems not to offer the answer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R4.3.1 Micro-Enterprise Credit for Street Youth</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.3.1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 13:11:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.3.1/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;lsquo;I am from a large, poor family and for many years we have done without breakfast. Ever since I joined the Street Kids International program I have been able to buy my family sugar and buns for breakfast. I have also bought myself decent second-hand clothes and shoes.’&lt;br>
Doreen Soko&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;lsquo;We’ve had business experience. Now I’m confident to expand what we’ve been doing.I’ve learnt cash management, and the way of keeping money so we save for reinvestment.Now business is a part of our lives. As well, we didn’t know each other before—now we’ve made new friends.’&lt;br>
Fan Kaoma.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Participants in the Youth skills Enterprise Initiative Program, Zambia&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Introduction
Although small-scale business training and credit programs have become more common throughout the world, relatively little attention has been paid to the need to direct such opportunities to young people. Even less attention has been paid to children living on the street or in difficult circumstance. Over the past nine years, Street Kids International (S. K. I.) has been working with partnerorganizations in Africa, Latin America and India to support the economic lives of streetchildren. The purpose of this paper is to share some of the lessons S.K.I and our partnershave learned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Background
Typically, children do not end up on the streets due to a single cause, but to a combination of factors: a dearth of adequately funded schools, the demand for income at home, family breakdown and violence. The street may be attractive to children as a place to find adventurous play and money. However, it is also a place where some children are exposed, with little or no protection, to exploitative employment, urban crime, and abuse. Children who work on the streets are generally involved in unskilled, labor-intensive tasks which require long hours, such as shining shoes, carrying goods, guarding or washing cars, and informal trading. Some may also earn income through begging, or through theft and other illegal activities. At the same time, there are street children who take pride in supporting themselves and their families and who often enjoy their work.Many children may choose entrepreneurship because it allows them a degree of independence, is less exploitative than many forms of paid-employment, and is flexibleenough to allow them to participate in other activities such as education and domestic task.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Street Business Partnerships
S. K. I. has worked with partner organizations in Latin America, Africa and India to develop innovative opportunities for street children to earn income. ·The S. K. I. Bicycle Courier Service first started in the Sudan.Participants in this enterprise were supplied with bicycles, which they used to deliver parcels and messages, and which they were required to pay for gradually from their wages. A similar program was taken up in Bangalore, India. ·Another successful project, The Shoe Shine Collective, was a partnership program with the Y.W.C.A. in the Dominican Republic. In this project, participants were lent money to purchase shoe shine boxes. They were also given a safe place to store their equipment, and facilities for individual savings plans. ·The Youth Skills Enterprise Initiative in Zambia is a joint program with the Red Cross Society and the Y.W.C.A. Street youths are supported to start their own small business through business training, life skills training and access to credit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lessons learned
The following lessons have emerged from the programs that S. K. I. and partner organizations have created.·Being an entrepreneur is not for everyone, nor for every street child. Ideally, potential participants will have been involved in the organization’s programs for at least six months, and trust and relationship building will have already been established.·The involvement of the participants has been essential to the development of relevant programs. When children have had a major role in determining procedures, they are more likely to abide by and enforce them.·It is critical for all loans to be linked to training programs that include the development of basic business and life skills.·There are tremendous advantages to involving parents or guardians in the program,where such relationships exist. Home visits allow staff the opportunity to know where the participants live, and to understand more about each individual’s situation.·Small loans are provided initially for purchasing fixed assets such as bicycles, shoe shine kits and basic building materials for a market stall. As the entrepreneurs gain experience, the enterprises can be gradually expanded and consideration can be given to increasing loan amounts. The loan amount in S.K. I. programs have generally ranged from US$30-$100.·All S. K. I. programs have charged interest on the loans, primarily to get the entrepreneurs used to the concept of paying interest on borrowed money. Generally the rates have been modest (lower than bank rates.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Conclusion
There is a need to recognize the importance of access to credit for impoverished young people seeking to fulfill economic needs. The provision of small loans to support the entrepreneurial dreams and ambitions of youth can be an effective means to help them change their lives. However, we believe hat credit must be extended in association with other types of support that help participants develop critical life skills as well as productive businesses.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: R4.3.2 Volcanoes — Earth-Shattering News</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.3.2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 13:11:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.3.2/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When Mount Pinatubo suddenly erupted on 9 June 1991, the power of volcanoes past and present again hit the headlines.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h4 id="a">A&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Volcanoes are the ultimate earth-moving machinery. A violent eruption can blow the top few kilometers off a mountain, scatter fine ash practically all over the globe and hurl rock fragments into the stratosphere to darken the skies a continent away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But the classic eruption — cone-shaped mountain, big bang, mushroom cloud and surges of molten lava — is only a tiny part of a global story. Volcanism, the name givento volcanic processes, really has shaped the world. Eruptions have rifted continents,raised mountain chains, constructed islands and shaped the topography of the earth. The entire ocean floor has a basement of volcanic basalt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Volcanoes have not only made the continents, they are also thought to have made the world’s first stable atmosphere and provided all the water for the oceans, rivers and ice-caps. There are now about 600 active volcanoes. Every year they add two or three cubic kilometers of rock to the continents. Imagine a similar number of volcanoes smoking away for the last 3,500 million years. That is enough rock to explain the continental crust.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What comes out of volcanic craters is mostly gas. More than 90% of this gas is water vapor from the deep earth: enough to explain, over 3,500 million years, the water in the oceans. The rest of the gas is nitrogen, carbon dioxide, sulphur dioxide, methane,ammonia and hydrogen. The quantity of these gases, again multiplied over 3,500 million years, is enough to explain the mass of the world’s atmosphere. We are alive because volcanoes provided the soil, air and water we need.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="b">B&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Geologists consider the earth as having a molten core, surrounded by a semi-molten mantle and a brittle, outer skin. It helps to think of a soft-boiled egg with a runny yolk, a firm but squishy white and a hard shell. If the shell is even slightly cracked during boiling,the white material bubbles out and sets like a tiny mountain chain over the crack — like an archipelago of volcanic islands such as the Hawaiian Islands. But the earth is so much bigger and the mantle below is so much hotter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even though the mantle rocks are kept solid by overlying pressure, they can still slowly ‘flow’ like thick treacle. The flow, thought to be in the form of convection currents,is powerful enough to fracture the ‘eggshell’ of the crust into plates, and keep them bumping and grinding against each other, or even overlapping, at the rate of a few centimeters a year. These fracture zones, where the collisions occur, are where earthquakes happen. And, very often, volcanoes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="c">C&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>These zones are lines of weakness, or hot spots. Every eruption is different, but put at its simplest, where there are weaknesses, rocks deep in the mantle, heated to 1,350℃，will start to expand and rise. As they do so, the pressure drops, and they expand and become liquid and rise more swiftly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes it is slow: vast bubbles of magma — molten rock from the mantle —inch lowards the surface, cooling slowly, to show through as granite extrusions(as on Skye, or the Great Whin Sill, the lava dyke squeezed out like toothpaste that carries part of Hadrian’s Wall in northern England). Sometimes — as in Northern Ireland, Wales and the Karoo in South Africa — the magma rose faster, and then flowed out horizontally on to the surface in vast thick sheets. In the Deccan plateau in western India, there are more than two million cubic kilometers of lava, some of it 2,400 meters thick, formed over 500,000 years of slurping eruption.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes the magma moves very swiftly indeed. It does not have time to cool as it surges upwards. The gases trapped inside the boiling rock expand suddenly, the lava glows with heat, it begins to froth, and it explodes with tremendous force. Then the slightly cooler lava following it begins to flow over the lip of the crater. It happens on Mars, it happened on the moon, it even happens on some of the moons of Jupiter and Uranus. By studying the evidence, vulcanologists can read the force of the great blasts of the past. Is the pumice light and full of holes? The explosion was tremendous. Are the rocks heavy, with huge crystalline basalt shapes, like the Giant’s Causeway in Northern Ireland? It was a slow, gentle eruption.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The biggest eruptions are deep on the mid-ocean floor, where new lava is forcing the continents apart and widening the Atlantic by perhaps five centimeters a year. Look at maps of volcanoes, earthquakes and island chains like the Philippines and Japan, and you can see the rough outlines of what are called tectonic plates — the plates which make up the earth’s crust and mantel. The most dramatic of these is the Pacific ‘ring of fire’ where there have been the most violent explosions — Mount Pinatubo near Manila, Mount St Helen’s in the Rockies and El Chichón in Mexico about a decade ago, not to mention world-shaking blasts like Krakatoa in the Sunda Straits in 1883.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="d">D&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>But volcanoes are not very predictable. That is because geological time is not like human time. During quiet periods, volcanoes cap themselves with their own lava by forming a powerful cone from the molten rocks slopping over the rim of the crater; later the lava cools slowly into a huge, hard, stable plug which blocks one further eruption until the pressure below becomes irresistible. In the case of Mount Pinatubo, this took 600 years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, sometimes, with only a small warning, the mountain blows its top. It did this at Mont Pelée in Martinique at 7.49 a.m. on 8 May, 1902. Of a town of 28,000, only two people survived. In 1815, a sudden blast removed the top 1,280 meters of Mount Tambora in Indonesia. The eruption was so fierce that dust thrown into the stratosphere darkened the skies, cancelling the following summer in Europe and North America.Thousands starved as the harvests failed, after snow in June and frosts in August.Volcanoes are potentially world news, especially the quiet ones.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>