<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>IELTS Reading Articles on Notebook</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/ielts/</link><description>Recent content in IELTS Reading Articles on Notebook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://note.codiy.net/docs/ielts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>R5.2.1 BAKELITE</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r5.2.1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 19:17:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r5.2.1/</guid><description>The birth of modern plastics In 1907, Leo Hendrick Baekeland, a Belgian scientist working in New York, discovered and patented a revolutionary new synthetic material. His invention, which he named &amp;lsquo;Bakelite&amp;rsquo;, was of enormous technological importance, and effectively launched the modern plastics industry.
The term &amp;lsquo;plastic&amp;rsquo; comes from the Greek plassein, meaning &amp;rsquo;to mould&amp;rsquo;. Some plastics are derived from natural sources, some are semi-synthetic (the result of chemical action on a natural substance), and some are entirely synthetic, that is, chemically engineered from the constituents of coal or oil.</description></item><item><title>R5.2.2 What’s so funny?</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r5.2.2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 19:17:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r5.2.2/</guid><description>John McCrone reviews recent research on humour
The joke comes over the headphones: &amp;lsquo;Which side of a dog has the most hair? The left.&amp;rsquo; No, not funny. Try again. &amp;lsquo;Which side of a dog has the most hair? The outside.&amp;rsquo; Hah! The punchline is silly yet fitting, tempting a smile, even a laugh. Laughter has always struck people as deeply mysterious, perhaps pointless. The writer Arthur Koestler dubbed it the luxury reflex: &amp;lsquo;unique in that it serves no apparent biological purpose&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>R5.2.3 The Birth of Scientific English</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r5.2.3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 19:17:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r5.2.3/</guid><description>World science is dominated today by a small number of languages, including Japanese, German and French, but it is English which is probably the most popular global language of science. This is not just because of the importance of English-speaking countries such as the USA in scientific research; the scientists of many non-English-speaking countries find that they need to write their research papers in English to reach a wide international audience.</description></item><item><title>R5.1.1 Johnson's Dictionary</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r5.1.1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 13:17:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r5.1.1/</guid><description>For the century before Johnson&amp;rsquo;s Dictionary was published in 1775, there had been concern about the state of the English language. There was no standard way of speaking or writing and no agreement as to the best way of bringing some order to the chaos of English spelling. Dr Johnson provided the solution.
There had, of course, been dictionaries in the past, the first of these being a little book of some 120 pages, compiled by a certain Robert Cawdray, published in 1604 under the title A Table Alphabeticall &amp;lsquo;of hard usuall English wordes&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>R5.1.2 Nature or Nurture?</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r5.1.2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 13:17:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r5.1.2/</guid><description>A A few years ago, in one of the most fascinating and disturbing experiments in behavioural psychology, Stanley Milgram of Yale University tested 40 subjects from all walks of life for their willingness to obey instructions given by a &amp;rsquo;leader&amp;rsquo; in a situation in which the subjects might feel a personal distaste for the actions they were called upon to perform. Specifically, Milgram told each volunteer &amp;rsquo;teacher-subject&amp;rsquo; that the experiment was in the noble cause of education, and was designed to test whether or not punishing pupils for their mistakes would have a positive effect on the pupils&amp;rsquo; ability to learn.</description></item><item><title>R5.1.3 The Truth about the Environment</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r5.1.3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 13:17:12 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r5.1.3/</guid><description>For many environmentalists, the world seems to be getting worse. They have developed a hit-list of our main fears: that natural resources are running out; that the population is ever growing, leaving less and less to eat; that species are becoming extinct in vast numbers, and that the planet&amp;rsquo;s air and water are becoming ever more polluted.
But a quick look at the facts shows a different picture. First, energy and other natural resources have become more abundant, not less so, since the book &amp;lsquo;The Limits to Growth&amp;rsquo; was published in 1972 by a group of scientists.</description></item><item><title>R4.2.1 Lost for Words</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.2.1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 13:11:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.2.1/</guid><description>Many Minority Languages Are on the Danger Lists In the Native American Navajo nation, which sprawls across four states in the American south-west, the native language is dying. Most of its speakers are middle-aged or elderly. Although many students take classes in Navajo, the schools are run in English. Street signs, supermarket goods and even their own newspaper are all in English. Not surprisingly, linguists doubt that any native speakers of Navajo will remain in a hundred years’ time.</description></item><item><title>R4.2.2 Alternative Medicine in Australia</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.2.2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 13:11:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.2.2/</guid><description>The first students to study alternative medicine at university level in Australia began their four-year, full-time course at the University of Technology Sydney, in early 1994. Their course covered, among other therapies, acupuncture. The theory they learnt is based on the traditional Chinese explanation of this ancient healing art that it can regulate the flow of‘Qi’ or energy through pathways in the body. This course reflects how far some alternative therapies have come in their struggle for acceptance by the medical establishment.</description></item><item><title>R4.3.1 Micro-Enterprise Credit for Street Youth</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.3.1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 13:11:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.3.1/</guid><description>&amp;lsquo;I am from a large, poor family and for many years we have done without breakfast. Ever since I joined the Street Kids International program I have been able to buy my family sugar and buns for breakfast. I have also bought myself decent second-hand clothes and shoes.’
Doreen Soko
&amp;lsquo;We’ve had business experience. Now I’m confident to expand what we’ve been doing.I’ve learnt cash management, and the way of keeping money so we save for reinvestment.</description></item><item><title>R4.3.2 Volcanoes — Earth-Shattering News</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.3.2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 13:11:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.3.2/</guid><description>When Mount Pinatubo suddenly erupted on 9 June 1991, the power of volcanoes past and present again hit the headlines.
A Volcanoes are the ultimate earth-moving machinery. A violent eruption can blow the top few kilometers off a mountain, scatter fine ash practically all over the globe and hurl rock fragments into the stratosphere to darken the skies a continent away.
But the classic eruption — cone-shaped mountain, big bang, mushroom cloud and surges of molten lava — is only a tiny part of a global story.</description></item><item><title>R4.3.3 Obtaining Linguistic Data</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.3.3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 13:11:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.3.3/</guid><description>A Many procedures are available for obtaining data about a language. They range from a carefully planned, intensive field investigation in a foreign country to a casual intro-spection about one&amp;rsquo;s mother tongue carried out in an armchair at home.
B In all cases, someone has to act as a source of language data — an informant. Infor-mants are (ideally) native speakers of a language, who provide utterances for analysis and other kinds of information about the language (e.</description></item><item><title>R4.4.1 How Much Higher? How Much Faster?</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.4.1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 13:11:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.4.1/</guid><description>— Limits to Human Sporting Performance Are Not Yet in Sight — Since the early years of the twentieth century, when the International Athletic Federa-tion began keeping records, there has been a steady improvement in how fast athletes run,how high they jump and how far they are able to hurl massive objects, themselves included, through space. For the so-called power events — that require a relatively brief,explosive release of energy, like the 100-metre sprint and the long jump — times and distances have improved ten to twenty percent.</description></item><item><title>R4.4.2 The Nature and Aims of Archaeology</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.4.2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 13:11:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.4.2/</guid><description>Archaeology is partly the discovery of the treasures of the past, partly the careful work of the scientific analyst, partly the exercise of the creative imagination. It is toiling in the sun on an excavation in the Middle-East, it is working with living Inuit in the snows of Alaska, and it is investigating the sewers of Roman Britain. But it is also the painstaking task of interpretation, so that we come to understand what these things mean for the human story.</description></item><item><title>R4.4.3 The Problem of Scarce Resources</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.4.3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 13:11:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/docs/2022/08/ielts/r4.4.3/</guid><description>Section A The problem of how health-care resources should be allocated or apportioned, so that they are distributed in both the most just and most efficient way, is not a new one. Every health system in an economically developed society is faced with the need to decide(either formally or informally) what proportion of the community’s total resources should be spent on health-care; how resources are to be apportioned; what diseases and disabilities and which forms of treatment are to be given priority; which members of the community are to be given special consideration in respect of their health needs; and which forms of treatment are the most cost-effective.</description></item></channel></rss>