<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notebook – Listening</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/ielts/listening/</link><description>Recent content in Listening on Notebook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://note.codiy.net/docs/ielts/listening/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: 4.2.1</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.2.1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 23:01:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.2.1/</guid><description>
&lt;p>W: Oh, Peter, there you are. You&amp;rsquo;ve been ages. What kept you so long?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: I&amp;rsquo;m Sorry I&amp;rsquo;m so late, Sally. Have you been waiting long?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Oh, half an hour. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a coffee and I have been reading this guidebook for tourists.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sally has been waiting half an hour for Peter, so C has been circled.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now we shall begin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You should answer the questions as you listen, because you will not hear the recording a second time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Listen carefully and answer questions 1 to 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Oh, Peter, there you&amp;rsquo;re. You&amp;rsquo;ve been ages. What kept you so long?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: I&amp;rsquo;m Sorry, I&amp;rsquo;m so late, Sally. Have you been waiting long?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Oh, half an hour. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve had a coffee and I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading this guidebook for tourists. Sit down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: You look very hot and tired. What would you like to drink?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: I&amp;rsquo;d love a really chilled mineral water or something. Will you have another coffee?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Yes, I will. The waitress will be back in a moment. Why were you so late? Did something happen?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Yes. You know I went to the bank to cash some travellers cheques?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, the exchange rate was looking healthy, but when I went to the teller, they told me the computer system was temporarily down, so they couldn&amp;rsquo;t do any transactions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They said the problem would be fixed in a few minutes, so I waited.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then I started talking to another guy in the bank, and I forgot the time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Oh, really? Someone you met in the bank? Does he work there?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: No, he was a tourist, from New York. His name is Henry, and he&amp;rsquo;s been here for a week, but he&amp;rsquo;s moving on to Germany tomorrow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He&amp;rsquo;s an architect, and he&amp;rsquo;s spending four weeks travelling around Europe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Just like us!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Yeah, just like us. He told me the names of some places where we should eat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Great food, and not too expensive, he said.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, and he also gave me this map of the bus system. He said he didn&amp;rsquo;t need it anymore.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: That&amp;rsquo;s useful. Pity he&amp;rsquo;s moving on tomorrow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ah, here&amp;rsquo;s the waitress. Let&amp;rsquo;s order.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do you want anything to eat, or shall we just have a drink?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Well. I&amp;rsquo;m hungry, and we&amp;rsquo;ve got a lot of sightseeing to do, so let&amp;rsquo;s just have a snack and a drink.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Sounds good to me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you hear the rest of the conversation you&amp;rsquo;ll have some time to look at questions 6 to 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen, and answer questions 6 to 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Well. Let&amp;rsquo;s decide what we&amp;rsquo;ll see today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I guess the best place to start is the Cathedral, and then the Castle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What are the opening times for those two?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Well, according to this guidebook, the Cathedral is only open from 9.30 in the morning until midday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, no, hang on. That&amp;rsquo;s the Cathedral Museum.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Cathedral itself is open morning and afternoon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Castle is just open from 1 to 5, so we can&amp;rsquo;t go there until after lunch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really want to spend some time in the Art Gallery, because they&amp;rsquo;ve got this wonderful painting by Rembrandt that I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: What else should we see?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Well the guidebook says the Botanical Gardens are worth spending some time in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And they&amp;rsquo;re open all day from 8 to 6 so we can go there anytime.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d like to go to the Markets near the river too, but&amp;hellip;Oh&amp;hellip;no, wait, that&amp;rsquo;s only in the mornings, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: As well as today and tomorrow, we can see some other places on Monday you know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I don&amp;rsquo;t think the Markets will be open then; they only open on Thursdays, so we&amp;rsquo;ve missed them for this week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe we should go to the Cathedral today because it&amp;rsquo;s Sunday tomorrow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And even though it&amp;rsquo;s open every day, it might be more difficult to get in tomorrow because of the church services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Em, that&amp;rsquo;s true, but the Art Gallery isn&amp;rsquo;t open on Sundays at all, so we&amp;rsquo;ll have to go there today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Castle&amp;rsquo;s open every day except Monday, so we&amp;rsquo;re OK there, and the Gardens of course only close at night.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Are all these places free or do we have to pay to go in? What does the guidebook say?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: I think there&amp;rsquo;s a charge for all of them except the Botanical Gardens. Oh, and the markets, of course you don&amp;rsquo;t pay to go in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Okay, well, it looks like our plan is this: we&amp;rsquo;ll go to see the painting you like first, the Rembrandt, then have lunch and go on to the Castle after that, and then the Cathedral.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Okay. It says here that the roof of the Cathedral is really beautiful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Is that right? What I really want to do at the Cathedral is climb the tower.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The view is supposed to be spectacular!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Okay, well, that&amp;rsquo;ll be more than enough for today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, tomorrow, let&amp;rsquo;s go to the Botanical Gardens and have a picnic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want to sit by the river and watch the swans. This city&amp;rsquo;s famous for them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section one, you now have half a minute to check your answers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now turn to section two.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 4.2.2</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.2.2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 23:01:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.2.2/</guid><description>
&lt;p>So the counselling services we offer deal with any problems arising from your studies or in your life outside the university.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s take academic counselling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re confused about subjects or how to combine them in your degree, then we can advise you and discuss the career you are aiming for, so that you can see it all in context.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We can also chase up your tutor if you&amp;rsquo;re not getting proper feedback on how you are getting on in your subject.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Besides help with academic problems, you may also need personal counselling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you think you&amp;rsquo;re already under stress, well, just wait till classes begin next week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll have to start adjusting to teaching and learning methods that may be unfamiliar to you, as well as the mounting pressure as the deadline for that first assignment creeps up on you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to cope with all this without your usual social network, you know, the social contacts, family and friends you could normally rely on for help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All of this causes anxiety. Studying overseas can trigger a personal crisis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You may have left a lot of what you might call &amp;lsquo;unfinished business&amp;rsquo; back in your own country.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or you may have interrupted personal relationships or even sometimes broken them off to come overseas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And so the student often feels lonely, unhappy, unmotivated and unable to concentrate on studying. Or there may be other things bothering you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our resident chaplain can offer you spiritual guidance if that&amp;rsquo;s what you want or we can put you in touch with community groups that can provide you with social contacts and friendship.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you hear the rest of the talk, you have some time to look at questions 15 to 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen and answer questions 15 to 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What about exam stress?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It affects nearly everyone to some extent, but especially overseas students like yourselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There may be a huge amount of family pressure on you to succeed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And if you fail a subject or drop out of a course because it&amp;rsquo;s too difficult, then your self-esteem can suffer. But it&amp;rsquo;s not the end of the world if you don&amp;rsquo;t pass an exam.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had to resit First Year Anthropology, so I can certainly offer you a sympathetic ear!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway, exam failure can lead to worrying changes in the way you normally behave.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You may also be off your food, or you may have dietary problems because the local food is not to your liking and upsets you, and this can affect your health and studies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Glenda Roberts is our dietician in the Health Service and we can put you on to her.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And we all have money problems, don&amp;rsquo;t we?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But remember, full-time students can get a low-interest loan of up to six hundred dollars to buy books and for similar study-related expenses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s right, and you can get double that amount if you can&amp;rsquo;t afford an item of equipment you need for your course - a musical instrument, for example.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you move into a flat, starting-up expenses, including furniture for it, can be covered by a loan through the Welfare Service. See Jill Freeman for details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Can we help you? Well, last academic year in spite of staff cuts, we counselled two hundred and forty international students for a total of twenty-six hundred hours counselling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And finally we won all but just one of the twelve appeals that we launched on behalf of students.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not too bad for an understaffed service, don&amp;rsquo;t you think?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s all from me. Thank you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section two. You now have half a minute to check your answers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now turn to section three.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 4.2.3</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.2.3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 23:01:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.2.3/</guid><description>
&lt;p>W: Oh, there you are, good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sorry I&amp;rsquo;m a bit late. There was a long queue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So have you worked out how to deal with this assignment then?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M1: Not yet. We&amp;rsquo;ve only been here a couple of minutes ourselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Can you just remind me what the task is exactly?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M2: Well, there are two, err, no, three parts to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First we&amp;rsquo;ve got to write an essay about ways of collecting data. Then&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: What&amp;rsquo;s the title of the essay exactly?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M1: I&amp;rsquo;ve got it here: &amp;lsquo;Assess the two main methods of collecting data in social science research&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: And how much do we need to write?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M1: Fifteen hundred words. That&amp;rsquo;s for the essay.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then, for the second part of the assignment, we have to choose one method of data collection, and carry out a small-scale study, making appropriate use of the method chosen to gather data from at least five subjects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: And then we have to write a report on the study?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M2: That&amp;rsquo;s right, of three to four thousand words.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Did you get as far as discussing which form of data collection we should go for - questionnaire or interview, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M1: Yeah, I think we should use a questionnaire. It&amp;rsquo;ll be so much less time-consuming than organising interviews, I reckon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once we&amp;rsquo;ve agreed on the wording of it, we only have to send it out and wait for the responses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Yes, I think it probably would be quicker.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But what did that article he gave us last week say about the quality of data from questionnaires?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M1: I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure it recommended questionnaires as a source of &amp;lsquo;highly reliable data&amp;rsquo;. As long as you design the questionnaire properly in the first place, the data will be fine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: No. I&amp;rsquo;m sure it talked about drawbacks as well, didn&amp;rsquo;t it? something about the response rate and the problems you get if it&amp;rsquo;s too low.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M1: Yeah, but we only need data from five subjects, anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Oh, I suppose so. Another drawback I remember it mentioned was that questionnaire data tends not to reveal anything unexpected, because it is limited to the questions fixed in advance by the researcher.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M1: Come on, Rosa. This is only a practice. It&amp;rsquo;s not meant to be a real research, is it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Well, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure about that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you hear the rest of the conversation, you have some time to look at questions twenty-seven to thirty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen and answer questions twenty-seven to thirty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Maybe I&amp;rsquo;d better go through the article again, just to be sure. Can you remember what it was called?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: &amp;lsquo;Sample Surveys and Social Science Research&amp;rsquo;, I think. By Mehta.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: M-E-H-T-A?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Yeah. And he also recommended a more recent book called Survey Research by Bell, I think.It&amp;rsquo;s in that series published by London University.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M2: And if we tried to use interviews instead, I saw a book in the departmental library that will be helpful: it&amp;rsquo;s called &amp;lsquo;Interviews that work&amp;rsquo;, by Wilson, published in Oxford in nineteen eighty-eight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Right. Oh, I have got a tutorial now. Can we meet up again later this week?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What about Friday morning?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Suits me. Eleven o&amp;rsquo;clock?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Fine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Before Friday, I think we should all look through the reading list.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section three. You now have half a minute to check your answers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now turn to section four.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 4.2.4</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.2.4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 23:01:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.2.4/</guid><description>
&lt;p>So far, in these lectures, we&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at crimes like robbery and murder - both from a historical viewpoint and also in contemporary society.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And we&amp;rsquo;ve seen that the preoccupation in Western society with crime and with lawlessness is part of a long and continuous tradition, rather than something which is new and unique to modern society.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But over the past seventy years or so, there has been a massive increase in one type of crime which is what&amp;rsquo;s known as &amp;lsquo;corporate crime&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Corporate crime is crime which, as the name suggests, is connected with companies, with business organisations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It includes illegal acts of either individuals or a group within the company.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But what is important is that these acts are normally in accordance with the goals of the company.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They&amp;rsquo;re for the good of the company rather than the individual.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been defined as, quote, &amp;lsquo;crime which is committed for the corporate organization&amp;rsquo; - the company - &amp;rsquo;not against it&amp;rsquo;, unquote.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So crimes like theft by employees - things like&amp;hellip;err&amp;hellip;embezzlement or fraud against one&amp;rsquo;s actual employer are excluded according to this definition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The employees may be involved but they&amp;rsquo;re acting in the first place for the company.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They may not even realize that they are committing a crime, or they may realise but they feel it&amp;rsquo;s excusable because it&amp;rsquo;s policy, or because otherwise they may lose their jobs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So here, really, we&amp;rsquo;re talking about the links between power and crime.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, this is one area that much less is generally known about than conventional or traditional crime.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It has been relatively ignored by the mass media.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, it tends to be underreported in comparison with conventional crime in news broadcasts, and in crime serials and films and so on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They very rarely deal with corporate crime.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it also tends to be ignored in academic circles, there&amp;rsquo;s been far more research on conventional crime and far more data is available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are several reasons for this lack of interest in corporate crime, compared with other types of crime.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s often very complex, whereas with conventional crime, it&amp;rsquo;s usually possible to follow what&amp;rsquo;s going on without specialist knowledge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As well as this, whereas conventional crime usually has a lot of human interest, corporate crime often has much less.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The third reason, and possibly the most significant one, is that very often the victims are unaware.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They think their misfortune is an accident, or that is the fault of no-one in particular.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They&amp;rsquo;re unaware that they&amp;rsquo;ve been victims of a crime.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So when we look at the effects of corporate crime, we may find it&amp;rsquo;s very difficult to assess the costs, but these costs can be very considerable in both their economic and social aspects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the economic costs first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, if a company is producing fruit juice, and it dilutes its product, so that it&amp;rsquo;s just a little below the concentration it should be, many millions of people may be paying a small amount extra​ for their carton of orange juice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now small amounts like this may seem insignificant for individual customers, too small to worry about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But for the company, this deception might result in massive illegal profit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, all studies of corporate crime agree that the individuals are in fact deprived of far more money by such crime than they are by conventional crime like robbery and theft.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to this we have to consider the social costs of corporate crime, and these are again very difficult to assess, but they are considerable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They&amp;rsquo;re important because they can undermine the faith of the public in the business world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And also, more importantly, because the main group of people they affect are, in fact, not the richer sections of the society but the poorer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So here, companies are robbing the poor to benefit the rich.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are two more points to do with corporate crime that I&amp;rsquo;d like to illustrate with the reference to a specific event which occurred several years ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was an explosion of a large oil tanker which caused the loss of more than fifty lives of the crew.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was an explosion which never should have happened, and a subsequent inquiry laid the blame not on anyone who had actually been on the tanker at the time, but on the owners of the tanker.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They had deliberately decided not to carry out necessary repair work on the tanker as it was due to be sold.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it was this lack of repair work which was directly responsible for the explosion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now this illustrates two points to do with corporate crime.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First of all, that it does not have to be intentional.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The owners of the tanker certainly did not intend it to explode but very serious consequences can result from people or organisations not considering the possible results of their actions seriously enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main crime here was indifference to the human results rather than actual intention to harm anyone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But that didn&amp;rsquo;t make the results any less tragic. And this leads me to my second point that corporate crime can have very severe consequences.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not just a matter of companies making bigger profits than they should do, but of events which may affect the lives of innocent people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet very often companies, because they say they didn&amp;rsquo;t intend to harm anyone, can avoid taking responsibility for the results of their actions, and that has been a very dangerous loophole in the law.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A further example of corporate crime was fade out&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section four, you now have half a minute to check your answers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of the listening test.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the IELTS test, you would now have ten minutes to transfer your answers to the listening answer sheet.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 4.3.1</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.3.1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 23:01:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.3.1/</guid><description>
&lt;p>W: Sara, I&amp;rsquo;ve heard that you want to move into a home-stay family, is that correct?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S: Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s right. I&amp;rsquo;ve been staying with my aunt and now my cousin is arriving from Singapore and my aunt needs the room for him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s bad luck. Well, I&amp;rsquo;ll need to get some particulars first. Err, Sara, what&amp;rsquo;s your full name?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S: Sara Lim, and that&amp;rsquo;s Sarah without the h at the end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Linda asks for Sara&amp;rsquo;s full name Sara Lim, so this has been written in the notes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now we shall begin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You should answer the questions as you listen, because you will not hear the recording a second time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Listen carefully and answer questions 1 to 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Sara, I&amp;rsquo;ve heard that you want to move into a home-stay family, is that correct?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S: Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s right. I&amp;rsquo;ve been staying with my aunt and now my cousin is arriving from Singapore and my aunt needs the room for him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s bad luck. Well I&amp;rsquo;ll need to get some particulars first. Err, Sara, what&amp;rsquo;s your full name?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S: Sara Lim, and that&amp;rsquo;s Sara without the h at the end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: En, how old are you Sara?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S: 23, only just. It was my birthday on the 21st of August.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Ah, happy birthday for yesterday. How long have you been in Australia?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S: A year in Adelaide and 6 months in Sydney. I prefer Sydney. I&amp;rsquo;ve got more friends here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: What&amp;rsquo;s your address at your aunt&amp;rsquo;s house?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S: Flat 1,539 Forest Rd. Canterbury and the post code is 2036.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Okay. What are you studying now?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S: I was studying general English in Adelaide. And now I&amp;rsquo;m doing academic English because I&amp;rsquo;m trying to get into medicine next year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: That sounds good, but it&amp;rsquo;ll take you a long time. When would you like to move out from your aunt&amp;rsquo;s?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S: My cousin arrives on Friday morning. So I&amp;rsquo;d better be out on Thursday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: What&amp;hellip;the 7th of September.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S: Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: That doesn&amp;rsquo;t leave us much time. Right, okay.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I need to know what kind of accommodation you&amp;rsquo;d like, so I can get you something suitable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S: Can I share a room with someone else.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been alone in my room at my aunt&amp;rsquo;s and I&amp;rsquo;ve always shared with my sister and I like that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Yes. Fine. That&amp;rsquo;ll save you money too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Would you like to live with the family or do you think that a single person will be better for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have lots of very nice single people on my books.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S: Do you have any women living alone, retired women?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Yes, I have quite a few whose children have grown up and left home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In fact, I have some really lovely retired ladies living by themselves who just love the company of students.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most of them live in flats but that&amp;rsquo;s not a problem for you, is it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S: Not at all. I&amp;rsquo;m used to that. My aunt lives in a flat too, remember?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not used to a big house with a garden, swimming pool, pets and all that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Okay fine. I know quite a bit about what you want now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I should let you know that your rent will be 160 dollars per week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll have to pay me 320 dollars as a deposit before you move in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The deposit is as insurance in case you break something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You need to pay monthly to me by cash or cheque, I don&amp;rsquo;t mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You don&amp;rsquo;t need to pay for gas, electricity or water. But you&amp;rsquo;ll need to pay your proportion of the phone bill.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most families do that on an honor system but you&amp;rsquo;ll have to wait and see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>En, Have you got any more questions for me?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S: When will you know where I can go?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: I&amp;rsquo;ll work on it now. So come and see me tomorrow and I should have some news for you then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S: Thanks a lot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Goodbye, see you tomorrow. After lunch will be better for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>S: Okay, see you then. Bye.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section one, you now have half a minute to check your answers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now turn to section two.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 4.3.2</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.3.2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 23:01:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.3.2/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;code>good evening! ending this week's dictional focus on the arts 'Jxxxx' going to f what's on store first this year's summer festival. over to you J.&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>GEOFFREY: Good evening, and in this week&amp;rsquo;s edition of &amp;lsquo;Focus on the Arts&amp;rsquo;, Jane Hemmington is going to fill us in on what&amp;rsquo;s in store for us at this year&amp;rsquo;s Summer Festival. Over to you, Jane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>this year's the summer festival is the biggest we've ever seen. so there should be something for everybody.&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jane: Thank you, Geoffrey. This year, the Summer Festival is the biggest we&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen, so there should be something for everybody.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>this is the third year they run it. and the timing slightly different. for the last couple of years, it's been around the fifth to seventeen, but this year, the want it to allow everyone enough time to recover from the 1st January cerebrations. and they put it at the end of the month.&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the third year they&amp;rsquo;ve run it and the timing&amp;rsquo;s slightly different: for the last couple of years it&amp;rsquo;s been around the fifth to seventeenth, but this year they wanted to allow everyone enough time to recover from the first of January celebrations and they&amp;rsquo;ve put it at the end of the month.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>the programme had sensational theater and dance and also had a large number of art xxxx. but the think festival is the most famous for its great street music.&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The programme has sensational theatre, dance and also a large number of art exhibitions, but the thing the Festival is most famous for is its great street music.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>for today's report xxx, I'm looking at some xxxx inventions you might like to see. in particular, in this year&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For today&amp;rsquo;s report though, Geoffrey, I&amp;rsquo;m looking at some of the theatrical events that you might like to see; in particular, at this year&amp;rsquo;s theme - circuses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>i am going to tell you about two circuse performances, but there're plenty of others in the programme&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you about two circus performances, but there&amp;rsquo;re plenty of others in the program.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>i've chosen nise because they are present to stain the movements within circuse preformances&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen these because they represent distinct movements within circus performance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first is the Circus Romano from Italy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As this is a traveling circus, it follows a long tradition by performing in a marquee, which is really like a canvas portable building, usually put up in a green space or car park, rather than in a theatre or stadium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In spite of this, Circus Romano isn&amp;rsquo;t at all like the traditional circuses I grew up with.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are no animals, just very talented clown and acrobatic routines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The show has a lot of very funny moments, especially at the beginning, but the best part is the music and lighting. They&amp;rsquo;re magical.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At forty-five dollars it&amp;rsquo;s very expensive anyway. It&amp;rsquo;s really for adult tastes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In fact, much of it would be wasted on children, so I suggest you leave them at home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second circus performance is Circus Electrica at the Studio Theatre.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The purists are suggesting that this isn&amp;rsquo;t a circus at all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a showcase for skills in dance and magic, rather than the usual ones you expect in a circus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With only six performers, it&amp;rsquo;s a small production, which suits the venue well - the Studio only seats about two hundred people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For my money it&amp;rsquo;s the aerial displays which are outstanding as well as the magical tricks - features which are missing from Circus Romano.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An interesting feature of the show is the performers are so young - the youngest is only fourteen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But it&amp;rsquo;s still well worth seeing, a good one for the whole family.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And finally, as it&amp;rsquo;s summer, you may wish to see some of the Festival performances that are being presented outdoors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like the famous Mekong Water Puppet Troupe, performing in the City Gardens this week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now water puppetry is amazing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s large puppets on long sticks, controlled by puppeteers standing waist deep in the lake.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The puppets do comedy routines and there is some terrific formation dancing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a fantastic show and the best moment comes at the end -seeing the puppeteers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When the troupe walks up out of water, you get this amazing feeling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s really hard to believe that what you&amp;rsquo;ve been watching is lifeless wood and cloth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an adult, I had a great time, but I did note that other older people in the audience weren&amp;rsquo;t quite as taken with it as I was.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a must for young children though, and that&amp;rsquo;s the audience it&amp;rsquo;s really aimed at.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, that&amp;rsquo;s all I&amp;rsquo;ve time for today, but I&amp;rsquo;ll be back next week with more news of what&amp;rsquo;s worth seeing and what is best to miss.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section two. You now have half a minute to check your answers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now turn to section three.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 4.3.3</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.3.3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 23:01:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.3.3/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Officer: Hello. Er, I&amp;rsquo;m Dawn Matthews.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Student: Yes, hello. I&amp;rsquo;ve been referred to you because I&amp;rsquo;m enquiring about the refresher courses that you run. I&amp;rsquo;d like to find out a bit more about them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Officer: OK. Well, we run quite a few different short courses for students who are either returning to study or studying part-time. Um, tell me about your situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Student: Well, I think that I really need some help in preparing for the coming semester, especially to build up my confidence a bit and help me study effectively because you see, I&amp;rsquo;ve been out in the work-force for nearly twelve years now, so it really is a long time since I was last a student.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Officer: Yes, it can seem like a long time, can&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Um, well, let me start by telling you what courses we have that might suit you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Are you an undergraduate or a postgraduate? Arts or Sciences?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Student: Undergraduate, and I&amp;rsquo;m in the business faculty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Officer: Right then. First of all, there&amp;rsquo;s our intensive &amp;lsquo;Study for Success&amp;rsquo; seminar on the first and second of February.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s aimed at students like you who are uncertain about what to expect at college, and looks at a fairly wide range of approaches to university learning, to motivate you to begin your study and build on your own learning strategies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Student: Mm, that sounds good. Um, what&amp;rsquo;re some of the strategies that are presented?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Officer: Well, we try to cover all aspects of study.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some of the strategies in writing, for example, would be improving your planning for writing, organizing your thinking and building some techniques to help you write more clearly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With reading, there will be sessions aimed at getting into the habit of analysing material as you read it, and tips to help you record and remember what you&amp;rsquo;ve read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It really is very important to begin reading confidently right from the beginning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Officer: There&amp;rsquo;s also advice on how to get the most from your lectures and practice in giving confident presentations as well as how to prepare for exams.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Student: What about the motivational side of things?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Officer: Ah, well, there&amp;rsquo;s a range of motivational exercises that we do to help the students feel positive and enthusiastic about their study.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The process of learning and exploring a subject can lead to a whole new way of looking at the world and the study skills and techniques you build up can be applied in all sorts of different ways.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Student: Actually, I&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;m very excited about the whole thing of taking up study again but, you know, I&amp;rsquo;m a little nervous about whether I&amp;rsquo;ll manage to get everything done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Er, I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s the same for all mature students?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Officer: Of course, it is. Two of the key components of the course are time management and overcoming procrastination.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People discover that, once they learn to plan their days, all the work can be accomplished and there&amp;rsquo;ll still be time for leisure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Student: Is there an enrolment fee?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Officer: Well, er, oh, just a minute, let&amp;rsquo;s see&amp;hellip;Ah, the cost is 30 pounds, which includes all course materials and morning tea. You have to arrange your own lunch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Student: Em, that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a problem. Er, I already make sandwiches for my three kids and my wife and myself everyday. I won&amp;rsquo;t have to change my routine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Officer: No. Now, I need to tell you that this is a very popular course and it&amp;rsquo;s essential that you book well ahead of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In fact, the Course Convenor tells me that there&amp;rsquo;re only five places left.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Student: Er, what other course might be good for me?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Officer: There&amp;rsquo;s one other that you could benefit from. It&amp;rsquo;s simply called &amp;lsquo;Learning Skills for University Study&amp;rsquo; and is on three consecutive mornings starting on a Monday from 9 to 12 and costs 25 pounds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is aimed at upgrading the study skills most school-leavers have and help them cope with the increased demands of university study.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It focuses mainly on making students more responsible for their own success.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Student: What sort of things are covered in this course?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Officer: Well, basically, it&amp;rsquo;s more advanced thinking, note taking, reading and writing strategies but also some input about stress management.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Student: Um, I think I&amp;rsquo;d be better off starting from the basics and looking at all the strategies, don&amp;rsquo;t you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Officer: Yes, from what you&amp;rsquo;ve told me, I think that&amp;rsquo;s more in line with your situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Student: All right then, um, can I book a place on the &amp;lsquo;Study for Success&amp;rsquo; seminar course now?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Officer: Yes, let me just get out a registration form and take down your details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section three. You now have half a minute to check your answers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now turn to section four.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 4.3.4</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.3.4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 23:01:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.3.4/</guid><description>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re very grateful that the Committee has agreed that a representative for the Students&amp;rsquo; Union can present students&amp;rsquo; suggestions about the design for the proposed new Union Building.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We appreciate that some of our ideas may not be feasible in the circumstances.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But we do feel that it is important that the ultimate beneficiaries of the facilities should have some say in its design.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I could start by briefly explaining what steps were taken to find out student opinion, and how we have arrived at conclusions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Firstly, a meeting was held in the current Union for our SU committee to explain the options.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then we invited all students to submit written suggestions for the design, placing cards in a suggestion box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These suggestions then provided the basis for the design of a questionnaire which was completed by approximately two thousand of the College students over a period of three weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, the SU Committee collated the results and drew up a report.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I can just hand around the copy of that report.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This presentation is essentially a summary and discussion of the key points of this report.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, in broad terms, the consensus was as follows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Firstly, regarding the crucial matter of the site, we presented the three options that you have proposed. One: in the city centre, near the Faculty of Education; two: on the outskirts of the city, near the park, and three: out of town, near the halls of residence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We ask students to cite reasons for and against these sites, and&amp;hellip;. and there was remarkable agreement on all three.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Site One was unpopular because of traffic and parking problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Site Two had a number of supporters, mainly because it was close to most lecture rooms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And Site Three, out of town, near the halls of residence, was clearly the most popular because of access from living quarters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was clear that the Union was mainly to be used after lectures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was also felt the larger site would allow more room for a choice of facilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our second area of interest was obviously the facilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There was minimal interest in having a library on the premises. But one option seemed to be a reading room instead, more useful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We would like the current table games room to be replaced with a small gym and if possible, small swimming pool, not, of course, Olympic size.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There was a large number of respondents in favour of a travel agent&amp;rsquo;s and insurance centre.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also request that there be the offices of the Student Counselling Centre, moving this from the Refectory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There was however much disagreement about whether to build a drama theatre.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just over forty percent of the respondents were in favour, but a largish minority were strongly against it, claiming that it is elitist and a waste of funds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Essentially the jury is out on that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, given the number of unfortunate incidents in the current Union over the past few months, a strong point was repeatedly made about security.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The recommendations would be at least video surveillance and security personnel who would check Student Union cards on request.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We doubt if it would be feasible to have a check at reception of all people coming in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, this is the summary of the views of the student population.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I say, fuller details are given in our report but I&amp;rsquo;m happy to take any questions if you have them&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section four, you now have half a minute to check your answers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of the listening test.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the IELTS test, you would now have ten minutes to transfer your answers to the listening answer sheet.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 4.4.1</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.4.1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 23:01:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.4.1/</guid><description>
&lt;p>W: Hi, Tony. Thanks ever so much for coming. You know we&amp;rsquo;ve been asked to organise something for John&amp;rsquo;s farewell?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Yeah, sure. It&amp;rsquo;s about time we started working out details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Exactly. We don&amp;rsquo;t want to leave it so late that it&amp;rsquo;s double the work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Mmm, mm, right, do you want me to take notes?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: That&amp;rsquo;d be great, thanks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Right, first thing is when is the best time to hold it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Well, he leaves on the twenty-fourth of December. -M: So what about the twenty-second?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Yeah, I think that&amp;rsquo;s about right. We want it quite near the time, don&amp;rsquo;t we?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The date of the goodbye party is the 22nd of December, so 22nd December has been written in the space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now we shall begin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You should answer the questions as you listen, because you will not hear the recording a second time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Listen carefully and answer questions 1 to 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Hi, Tony. Thanks ever so much for coming. You know we&amp;rsquo;ve been asked to organise something for John&amp;rsquo;s farewell?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Yes, sure. It&amp;rsquo;s about time we started working out details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Exactly, We don&amp;rsquo;t want to leave it so late that it&amp;rsquo;s double the work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Em, right. Do you want me to take notes? -W: That will be great. Thanks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Right, first thing is when is the best time to hold it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Well, he leaves on the twenty-fourth of December. -M: So what about the twenty-second?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Yeah, I think that&amp;rsquo;s about right. We want it quite near the time, don&amp;rsquo;t we?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Sure, and what about a venue? In college? A hotel?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: I think a hotel will probably work out rather expensive and I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at the College Dining Room: that seems pretty reasonable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Fine, yeah, why not?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: And then we ought to be thinking about invitations&amp;hellip;Who mustn&amp;rsquo;t we forget to invite?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Well, obviously, John and his wife.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: And the Director. The office staff. -W: Ah ha. Yep, and all the teachers and all the students?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Anyone else?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Faculty Heads?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: No, better draw the line, I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s necessary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Yeah, you&amp;rsquo;re right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: I don&amp;rsquo;t mind writing the invitations. When shall we get them out for?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Em, enough time, but not too early. What about the fifteenth of December?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Well, there are exams on the sixteenth, better avoid them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Em, tenth?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Yeah, that should do it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you hear the rest of the conversation you&amp;rsquo;ll have some time to look at questions 5 to 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen, and answer questions 5 to 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: So, what does that leave? Oh, yes, a present.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Em, would you mind doing that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: No, not at all; we usually go round with an envelope during coffee break, don&amp;rsquo;t we?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Yeah, coffee break&amp;rsquo;s always the best time, cos people have got their money handy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Yeah, exactly. Do we suggest an amount? Or does it seem a bit unfair?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: No, I think people welcome it. We suggested six dollars last time. Is that Ok?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Yeah, plenty I would have thought, which should leave us with about ninety dollars?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Em, have you any ideas for presents?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve been having a little think. I thought, you know, he loves music.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Em, yeah, and books.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: So, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d check on prices for, well, perhaps CD players?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Em, yeah. That&amp;rsquo;s a good idea and also I thought maybe, you know, a set of dictionaries. I heard him say he needed a good one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: The other thing he was saying last week was that his computer printer had broken.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Umm. No, I&amp;rsquo;d be really frightened about getting the wrong type.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Ok, yeah.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: The other thing is something for the home. Jill suggested a coffee maker.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Oh, yeah, I&amp;rsquo;ll certainly find out what they cost. Ok, have you got all that down?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Yes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Now, we need to think a little more about the money. I know we&amp;rsquo;ve got a set amount from the Social Fund.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Right, what does that cover?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: It&amp;rsquo;s meant to cover the cost of the room.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Yeah.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: And a certain amount for food.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: And also drinks?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Oh yeah, certainly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: But will it be enough?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: What we&amp;rsquo;ve done in the past is to ask guests to bring some snacks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: We don&amp;rsquo;t ask them to bring more drinks, because we figure that&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip;that should come from the Social Fund.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Ok. Anything else for the guests to bring?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Well, oh some music, because there&amp;rsquo;ll be a tape deck there in the room, and we can have some dancing later on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Anything else?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Well, it&amp;rsquo;s just a thought, but a couple of years ago, that we had a really good party where we set up, you know, some simple games.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Yeah, great. Wasn&amp;rsquo;t it based on photos from the students and teachers?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: That&amp;rsquo;s right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: So we should ask the guests to bring photos. Ok, I&amp;rsquo;ll put it on the invitations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Now the last thing is, who shall we ask to do the speech?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Don&amp;rsquo;t you think it might be nice to have one of the students?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Well then, the Student Leader?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Yeah, much better than the Director giving speeches again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Ok then, I&amp;rsquo;ll ask her. Lovely, so is that all?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>M: Looks like it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>W: Great. Thanks ever so much.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section one, you now have half a minute to check your answers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now turn to section two.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 4.4.2</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.4.2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 23:01:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.4.2/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Speaker 1: Thank you for calling the free Travelite Travel Agency Information Line. You will not be charged for this call.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to deal with all calls effectively, we offer you a number of options.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please listen carefully and press your required number at the appropriate time, or dial a new number.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to hear about special offers, please press one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to hear our latest price lists, please press two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to make a complaint, please press three.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want information about our new walking holidays, please press four now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Speaker 2: Thank you for calling our Travelite Walking Holidays Line.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have been offering a wide variety of walking holidays to suit all tastes for just three years, but already we have won two awards for excellence in this field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We offer guided walking tours to suit the discerning traveller in twelve different centres throughout the whole of Western Europe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are planning to open our first centre outside this area in the coming year, so watch out for developments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But the pride of Travelite is the level of guidance and support we offer on our walks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All are planned in detail by our highly trained guides, who all work in a variety of different Travelite locations, so we can guarantee standards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each day we offer three separate walks catering for all skills and fitness levels.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also pride ourselves on our friendly service, particularly important for the increasing numbers of people who choose to holiday alone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unlike almost all travel operators who happily charge large supplements for single rooms, we guarantee that no single client will pay more, even when only double rooms are available for them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the day doesn&amp;rsquo;t end with the return to base&amp;hellip;after our dinner at communal tables designed to make all our guests feel part of a family atmosphere&amp;hellip;Entertainment is laid on nearly every night with tour leaders on hand to organise lectures, games, quizzes and respond to any special requests from guests.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you hear the rest of the message, you have some time to look at questions 16 to 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen and answer questions 16 to 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following is a summary of costs and special inclusive offers on holidays for the coming summer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have three lengths of holiday: three-day, seven-day and fourteen-day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The three-day holiday costs one hundred and eighty dollars for all accommodation, food and walking, and for the first time this year we are including in that price&amp;hellip;the cost of picking you up from the nearest station.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The seven-day holiday costs three hundred and fifty dollars per person and, as well as including the offers of the three-day holiday, also includes a magnificent book giving the local history.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that, we are able to include free maps&amp;hellip;for you to better enjoy the walking and even plan in advance, if you wish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the fourteen-day holiday, our special price is six hundred and ninety dollars per person and that includes all the offers for the three and seven-day holidays plus&amp;hellip;membership of a local walking club&amp;hellip;so you can better enjoy the full flavour of the local life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For further information, please contact your local travel agent. Thank you for calling the Travelite Travel Agency Information Line&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section two. You now have half a minute to check your answers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now turn to section three.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 4.4.3</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.4.3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 23:01:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.4.3/</guid><description>
&lt;p>MIKE: Hi Sue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: Hi Mike, so what happened to you last week?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: Oh, I was sick with the flu. What&amp;rsquo;s this I hear about a big assignment we&amp;rsquo;ve got to do?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: Well, basically, we&amp;rsquo;ve got to find two science experiments to do with a group of eight-year-old children at the local primary school, and we&amp;rsquo;ve got to complete it by the end of the week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: Oh, that sounds like hard work. Where are we supposed to get the ideas for these experiments from?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: Well, I managed to get hold of two books from the library.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: Oh, well done!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: How about if we take a look at the experiments in this book first and see if anything looks suitable?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can make notes as we go, about equipment and the purpose of the experiments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: OK, let&amp;rsquo;s see, um, the first experiment is called &amp;lsquo;Make your own hovercraft &amp;lsquo;, which sounds very ambitious!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mind you, you only need twenty balloons and a table-you don&amp;rsquo;t need any special engines or anything like that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: What do you do with it all?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: Er, you blow up the balloons and you balance the table on them, upside down of course, and the kids get to ride around on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You know, the other kids sort of push them around the room.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main purpose is to show how hovercrafts work, and how things hover around on just a cushion of air.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: OK, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound too bad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: OK, ready for number two?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: Uh-huh.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: Now this one is called &amp;lsquo;Unusual Measures of Lengths&amp;rsquo;, and you basically use lots of paperclips.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The kids go around the class measuring things - you know, how long the desk is, and that sort of thing, um, and then they all compare their answers, Er, and, basically, because not all paperclips are the same lengths, they should come up with some strange answers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s supposed to demonstrate the importance of having fixed units of measurement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: Hmm, yes, that&amp;rsquo;s not bad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: OK, now for number three you need rock salt or copper sulphate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: Oh, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure about that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: Well, just put down the rock salt then. Um, apart from that you only need a jar of water.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Um, and basically you dissolve lots of salt into the water and watch the crystals form, so it basically teaches the kids about growing crystals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: Yeah, I suppose it would be nice to grow something. Hmm, let&amp;rsquo;s move on and have a look at number four.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: OK, this one is called &amp;lsquo;Spinning colour wheel&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It looks like you get some cardboard and draw a circle on it, divide it into six equal segments and colour each one in using different colours, then you thread a piece of string through the middle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: So we&amp;rsquo;d need some string as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: Yes, sorry&amp;hellip;um&amp;hellip;and you spin the wheel around and if you can get it spinning fast enough, hopefully the colours all merge and show up as white.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: Oh, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that. What&amp;rsquo;s the principle behind it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: Well it&amp;rsquo;s pretty elementary physics, really. It teaches them about how white light or ordinary light is made up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: Hmm, well that doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound too bad. Now there&amp;rsquo;s only one more left in this book, isn&amp;rsquo;t there? What does that one say?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: Um, well it&amp;rsquo;s another one where they&amp;rsquo;d get to make something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: Sounds very interesting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: You need quite a lot of equipment actually -a hand drill, an old record, a pin or needle, some paper and a bolt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: Hmm, go on, what do they have to do?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: Well, they basically make a record player. The main idea is to teach them about recording sound, but hopefully they&amp;rsquo;d also see that you need motion and an amplifier to make the sound heard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: OK, well it does sound interesting. Shall we go through all of those again and decide if any of them are going to be suitable?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you hear the rest of the conversation, you have some time to look at questions 27 to 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen and answer questions 27 to 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: Right, number one. I thought this one sounded nice: there&amp;rsquo;d be lots of activity and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need too much in the way of equipment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s true. But don&amp;rsquo;t you think it&amp;rsquo;s a bit risky to get a group of eight-year-olds pushing each other around a classroom like that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Someone could get hurt. Now I don&amp;rsquo;t like the sound of that one at all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: What about number two, with the paperclips? It sounds tame enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: Yes, a bit too tame if you ask me. I think it needs to be something a bit more active and interesting than that, don&amp;rsquo;t you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: Yes, I suppose you&amp;rsquo;re right. We won&amp;rsquo;t get a very good mark if the children don&amp;rsquo;t actually enjoy the experiments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I suppose we could turn them off science for good! Well, what about the next one, number three?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: Now, I quite like the idea of this one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: Yes, so do I, but I seem to remember when we did it at high school we had to wait up to a fortnight before we saw any halfway decent results.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: Oh, yes. Well, that won&amp;rsquo;t be any good then. We&amp;rsquo;ll only see the kids for one or two hours at the most.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: Yes, and we have to do the experiments and write up our results within a week, so that one won&amp;rsquo;t do at all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: OK, well, what did you think of number four?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: I like the idea of it. But do you think it will be a bit elementary for them?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: Well, they are only eight you know!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: I know, but you know what I mean. Don&amp;rsquo;t you think the activity itself is a bit babyish?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: Hmm, maybe you&amp;rsquo;re right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: They might have fun but, I mean, cutting out a circle and colouring it in?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: OK, well, what about number five?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: I thought this one sounded a bit too good to be true-great equipment!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: Yeah.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: But don&amp;rsquo;t you think it&amp;rsquo;s a bit ambitious for this age group?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I mean, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to start off something and then have to abandon it if they just can&amp;rsquo;t cope with it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I could see us ending up doing just about all of the work for them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIKE: I guess you&amp;rsquo;re right. Oh well, maybe we could store that idea away for later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SUE: Yep, let&amp;rsquo;s hope this second book has something better!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section three. You now have half a minute to check your answers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now turn to section four.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 4.4.4</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.4.4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 23:01:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.4.4/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Today we are going to look at one of my favourite fish -the shark.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As you know, sharks have a reputation for being very dangerous creatures capable of injuring or killing humans, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk about sharks in Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sharks are rather large fish, often growing to over ten metres and the longest sharks caught in Australia have reached sixteen metres.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sharks vary in weight with size and breed, of course, but the heaviest shark caught in Australia was a White Pointer -that weighed seven hundred and ninety-five kilograms-quite a size!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sharks have a different structure to most fish: instead of skeleton made of bone, they have a tough elastic skeleton of cartilage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unlike bone, this firm, pliable material is rather like your nose, and allows the shark to bend easily as it swims.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The shark&amp;rsquo;s skin isn&amp;rsquo;t covered with scales, like other fish: instead the skin&amp;rsquo;s covered with barbs, giving it a rough texture like sandpaper.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As you know​, sharks are very quick swimmers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is made possible by their fins, one set at the side and another set underneath the body, and the tail also helps the shark move forward quickly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unlike other fish, sharks have to keep swimming if they want to stay at a particular depth, and they rarely swim at the surface.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mostly, they swim at the bottom of the ocean, scavenging and picking up food that&amp;rsquo;s lying on the ocean floor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While most other animals, including fish, hunt their prey by means of their eyesight, sharks hunt essentially by smell.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They have a very acute sense of smell-and can sense the presence of food long before they can see it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Australia, where people spend a lot of time at the beach, the government has realised that it must prevent sharks from swimming near its beaches.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a result, they have introduced a beach-netting program.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Beach-netting, or meshing, involves setting large nets parallel to the shore; this means that the nets on New South Wale beaches are set on one day, and then lifted and taken out to sea on the next day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When shark-netting first began in 1939, only the sydney metropolitan beaches were meshed, these beaches were chosen because beaches near the city are usually the most crowded with swimmers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ten years later, in 1949, systematic meshing was extended to include the beaches to the south of Sydney.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a result of the general success of the program in Sydney, shark-meshing was introduced to the state of Queensland around 1970.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The New Zealand authorities also looked at it, but considered meshing uneconomical - as did Tahiti in the Pacific.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At around the same time, South Africa introduced meshing to some of its most popular swimming beaches.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When meshing began, approximately fifteen hundred sharks were caught in the first year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, this declined in the year that followed, and since that time, the average annual catch has been only about a hundred and fifty a year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The majority of sharks are caught during the warmest months, from November to February, when sharks are most active and when both the air and the ocean are at their maximum temperature.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Despite quite large catches, some people believe that the shark meshing is not the best way to catch sharks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not that they think sharks are afraid of nets, or because they eat holes in them, because neither of these is true.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But meshing does appear to be less effective than some other methods, especially when there are big seas with high rolling waves and strong currents and anything that lets the sand move - the sand that&amp;rsquo;s holding the nets down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When this moves the nets will also become less effective.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section four, you now have half a minute to check your answers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of the listening test.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the IELTS test, you would now have ten minutes to transfer your answers to the listening answer sheet.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 4.1.1</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.1.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 21:01:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.1.1/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Good Morning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good Morning. How can I help you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I understand that the school organizes umm, trips to different&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, we run five every month: three during weekends and two Wednesday afternoon trips.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What sort of places?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, obviously it varies, but always places of historical interest and also which offer a variety of shopping, because our students always ask about that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then we go for ones where we know there are guided tours, because this gives a good focus for the visit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do you travel far?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, we are lucky here, obviously, because we&amp;rsquo;re able to say that all our visits are less than three hours&amp;rsquo; drive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How much do they cost?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Again, it varies-between five and fifteen pounds a head, depending on distance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ah ha&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, and we do offer to arrange special trips if, you know, there are more than twelve people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, right, I&amp;rsquo;ll keep that in mind. And what are the times normally?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We try to keep it pretty fixed so that&amp;hellip;that students get to know the pattern.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We leave at eight-thirty a. m. and return at six p. m.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We figure it&amp;rsquo;s best to keep the day fairly short.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, yes, and how do we reserve a place?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You sign your name on the notice board. Do you know where it is?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ah, ha, I saw it this morning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And we do ask that you sign up three days in advance, so we know we&amp;rsquo;ve got enough people interested to run it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And we can cancel if necessary, with full refund of course. -That&amp;rsquo;s fine. Thanks!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you hear the rest of the conversation, you&amp;rsquo;ll have some time to look at questions five to ten.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, listen and answer questions five to ten.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And what visits are planned for this term?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, well&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;m afraid the schedule hasn&amp;rsquo;t been printed out yet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But we have confirmed the dates and planned the optional extra visits which you can also book in advance if you want to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s all right. If you can just give some idea of the weekend ones, so I can, you know, work out when to see friends, etcetera.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh sure. Well, the first one is St Ives. That&amp;rsquo;s on the thirteenth of February and we&amp;rsquo;ll have only sixteen places available &amp;lsquo;cause we&amp;rsquo;re going by minibus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that&amp;rsquo;s a day in town with the optional extra of visiting the Hepworth Museum.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh right&amp;hellip;yeah&amp;hellip;that sounds good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Umm, then there&amp;rsquo;s a London trip on the sixteenth of February and we&amp;rsquo;ll be taking a medium-sized coach so there&amp;rsquo;ll be forty-five places on that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And let&amp;rsquo;s see, the optional extra is the Tower of London.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, I&amp;rsquo;ve already been there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Err, after that there&amp;rsquo;s Bristol on the third of March. -Where?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bristol&amp;hellip;B-R-I-S-T-O-L.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s in a different minibus with eighteen places available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, and the optional extra is a visit to the S.S.Great Britain. -OK&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re going to Salisbury on the eighteenth of March, and that&amp;rsquo;s always a popular one because the optional extra is Stonehenge, so we&amp;rsquo;re taking the large coach with fifty seats. -Oh good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then the last one is to Bath on the twenty-third of March.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh yes. Is Bath the Roman city?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s right, and that&amp;rsquo;s in the 16-seater minibus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And where&amp;rsquo;s the optional visit?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s to the American Museum - well worth a visit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, well that&amp;rsquo;s great, thanks for all that&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My pleasure. By the way, if you want more information about any of the trips, have a look in the student newspaper. -Ok.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or, have a word with my assistant; her name is Jane Yentob - that&amp;rsquo;s Y-E-N-T-O-B.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, I&amp;rsquo;ve got that. Thank you very much for all your help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;re very welcome. I hope you enjoy the trips.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 4.1.2</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.1.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 21:01:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.1.2/</guid><description>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll hear a tour guide giving a talk about a museum center called Riverside Industrial Village.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, you have some time to look at questions eleven to thirteen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen carefully and answer questions eleven to thirteen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good afternoon everybody and welcome to Riverside Industrial Village.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To start your visit, I&amp;rsquo;m just going to give you a brief account of the history of the museum before letting you roam about on your own. I won&amp;rsquo;t keep you long. OK?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, from where we&amp;rsquo;re standing you&amp;rsquo;ve got a good view of the river over there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it was because of this fast-flowing water that this site was a natural place for manufacturing works.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The water and the availability of raw materials in the area, like minerals and iron ore, and also the abundance of local fuels, like coal and firewood, all made this site suitable for industry from a very early time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Water was the main source of power for the early industries and some of the water wheels were first established in the twelfth century would you believe?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At that time, local craftsmen first built an iron forge just behind the village here, on the bend in the river.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By the seventeenth and eighteenth centuries, the region&amp;rsquo;s rivers supported more than a hundred and sixty water mills, and many of these continued to operate well into the nineteenth century.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But then the steam engine was invented and then the railways came and the centres of industry were able to move away from the rivers and the countryside and into the towns. So, industrial villages like this one became very rare.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So that&amp;rsquo;s the history for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;d like any more information, you can ask me some questions, or you can read further in our excellent guide book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you hear the rest of the talk you&amp;rsquo;ll have some time to look at questions fourteen to twenty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen, and answer questions fourteen to twenty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, I&amp;rsquo;m going to give you a plan of the site and I&amp;rsquo;d just like to point out where everything is and then you can take a look at everything for yourself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve already pointed out the river, which is on the left.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course running along the bottom is Woodside Road.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Got it? OK. Now we&amp;rsquo;re standing at the entrance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See it at the bottom, and immediately to our right is the Ticket Office.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You won&amp;rsquo;t need that because you&amp;rsquo;ve got your group booking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But just past it are the toilets - always good to know where they are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In front of us is the car park, as you can see, and to the left, by the entry gate is the Gift Shop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s where you can get copies of the guide, like this one here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, beyond the car park, all the buildings are arranged in a half circle with a yard in the middle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The big stone building at the top is the main Workshop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s where the furnace is and where all the metal was smelted and the tools were cast, as you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, in the top right-hand corner, that building with bigger windows is the Showroom, where samples of all the tools that were made through the ages are on display.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the top left corner is the Grinding Shop, where the tools were sharpened and finished.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And on one side of that you can see the Engine Room, and on the other, is the Cafe, which isn&amp;rsquo;t an antique, you&amp;rsquo;ll be pleased to know, though they do serve very nice old-fashioned teas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The row of buildings you can see on the left are the cottages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These were built for the workers towards the end of the eighteenth century and they&amp;rsquo;re still furnished from that period, so you can get a good idea of ordinary people&amp;rsquo;s living conditions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Across the yard from them, you can see the stables where the horses were kept for transporting the products.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the separate building in front of them is the Works Office, and that still has some of the old accounts on display.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, if anyone wants a guided tour then I&amp;rsquo;m starting at the Engine Room. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to come along, this way please, ladies and gentlemen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section two, you now have half a minute to check your answers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now turn to section three.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 4.1.3</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.1.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 21:01:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.1.3/</guid><description>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll hear Melanie a student, talking to one of her lecturers about her studies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, you have some time to look at questions twenty-one to twenty-seven.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen carefully, and answer questions twenty-one to twenty-seven.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Excuse me, Dr Johnson.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>May I speak to you for a minute?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sure, come in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m Melanie Griffin. I&amp;rsquo;m taking your course in population studies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, well, Melanie, How can I help you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m having a bit of trouble with the second assignment, and it&amp;rsquo;s due in twelve days.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What sort of trouble are you having?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is the assignment question a problem?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, that&amp;rsquo;s part of the problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m also having - been having - trouble getting hold of the books.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been to the library several times and all the books were out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sounds like you should have started borrowing books a bit earlier.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, I had a really big assignment due in for another course, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending all my time on that, and I thought&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You might get an extension of time to finish your assignment for me?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If that&amp;rsquo;s possible. But I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, yes, it is possible, but extensions are normally given only for medical or compassionate reasons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Otherwise, it&amp;rsquo;s really a question of organizing your study, and we don&amp;rsquo;t like giving extensions to students who simply didn&amp;rsquo;t plan their work properly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What did you get for your first assignment?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I got eighty-seven percent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mmm, yes, you did very well indeed. So obviously you can produce good work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll need too much extra time, as long as I can get hold of some of the important references.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, since you did so well in your first assignment, I&amp;rsquo;m prepared to give you an extra two weeks for this one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So that&amp;rsquo;ll mean you need to submit it about a month from now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, thank you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, what about the reading materials. Have you checked out the journal articles in the list?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Umm, no, not yet. There were about twenty of them and&amp;hellip;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure which ones would be most useful or important.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, they are all useful. But I don&amp;rsquo;t expect anyone to read them all, because a number of them deal with the same issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And let me give you some suggestions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The article by Anderson and Hawker is really worth reading.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, I&amp;rsquo;ll read that one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You should also read the article by Jackson, but just look at the part on the research methodology — how they did it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, Jackson, got that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And if you have time, the one by Roberts says very relevant things, although it&amp;rsquo;s not essential.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So&amp;hellip;OK, if it&amp;rsquo;s useful I&amp;rsquo;ll try to read that one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, the one by Morris. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t​ bother with that at this stage if I were you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, I won&amp;rsquo;t bother with Morris.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh now, someone told me the article by Cooper is important.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, yes, in a way, but just look at the last part, where he discusses the research results.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And lastly, there is Forster. I can&amp;rsquo;t think why I included that one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not bad, and could be of some help, but not that much.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you hear the rest of the conversation, you have some time to look at questions twenty-eight to thirty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen and answer questions twenty-eight to thirty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, let&amp;rsquo;s deal with the assignment question.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s the problem there?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s the graph from page two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What seems to be the problem? It&amp;rsquo;s just the bar graph, showing reasons why people change where they live.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve got the photocopy, but the reasons at the bottom are missing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ah, Ok, look at the first bar on the graph.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that indicates the number of people who move because they want more space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, I see, bar one, ok, now what about the next bar?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bar two is to do with people living nearby disturbing them, so they chose to move away to somewhere quieter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now let&amp;rsquo;s look at bar number three, another reason people change their place of living is because they want to be closer to the city.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, proximity to the city is an issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, bar number four refers to problems when the owner of the property won&amp;rsquo;t help fix things that go wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In other words, the owner is not helpful, and so the tenants move out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, now what about bar five?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ah, bar five is about those people who move because they need a bus or train to get them into the city or to go to work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK. And bar six?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bar number six is interesting, that reason was given quite a lot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People moving because they want to be in a more attractive neighbourhood.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, yes, thank you very much.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section three. You now have half a minute to check your answers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now turn to section four.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 4.1.4</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.1.4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 21:01:52 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l4.1.4/</guid><description>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll hear a talk on the subject of the urban landscape.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, you have some time to look at questions thirty-one to forty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen carefully and answer questions thirty-one to forty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been asked today to talk to you about the urban landscape.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are two major areas that I will focus on in my talk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How vegetation can have a significant effect on urban climate?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And how we can better plan our cities using trees to provide a more comfortable environment for us to live in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Trees can have a significant impact on our cities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They can make a city, as a whole, a bit less windy or a bit more windy, if that&amp;rsquo;s what you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They can make it a bit cooler if it&amp;rsquo;s a hot summer day in an Australian city, or they can make it a bit more humid if it&amp;rsquo;s a dry inland city.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the local scale - that is, in particular areas within the city - trees can make the local area more shady, cooler, more humid and much less windy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In fact trees and planting of various kinds can be used to make city streets actually less dangerous in particular areas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How do trees do all that, you ask?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, the main difference between a tree and a building is a tree has got an internal mechanism to keep the temperature regulated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It evaporates water through its leaves and that means that the temperature of the leaves is never very far from our own body temperature.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The temperature of a building surface on a hot sunny day can easily be twenty degrees more than our temperature.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Trees, on the other hand, remain cooler than buildings because they sweat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This means that they can humidify the air and cool it- a property which can be exploited to improve the local climate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Trees can also help break the force of winds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The reason that high buildings make it windier at ground level is that, as the wind goes higher and higher, it goes faster and faster.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When the wind hits the building, it has to go somewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some of it goes over the top and some goes around the sides of the building, forcing those high level winds down to ground level.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen when you have trees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Trees filter the wind and considerably reduce it, preventing those very large strong gusts that you so often find around tall buildings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another problem in built-up areas is that traffic noise is intensified by tall buildings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By planting a belt of trees at the side of the road, you can make things a little quieter, but much of the vehicle noise still goes through the trees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Trees can also help reduce the amount of noise in the surroundings, although the effect is not as large as people like to think.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Low-frequency noise, in particular, just goes through the trees as though they aren&amp;rsquo;t there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although trees can significantly improve the local climate, they do however take up a lot of space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are root systems to consider and branches blocking windows and so on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It may therefore be difficult to fit trees into the local landscape.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is not a great deal you can do if you have what we call a street canyon - a whole set of high-rises enclosed in a narrow street.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Trees need water to grow. They also need some sunlight to grow and you need room to put them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have the chance of knocking buildings down and replacing them, then suddenly you can start looking at different ways to design the streets and to introduce&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section four, you now have half a minute to check your answers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of the listening test.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the IELTS test, you would now have ten minutes to transfer your answers to the listening answer sheet.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>