<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notebook – C6</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/ielts/listening/c6/</link><description>Recent content in C6 on Notebook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://note.codiy.net/docs/ielts/listening/c6/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: 6.1.1</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.1.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.1.1/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll hear a man telephoning a sports club to ask about membership and facilities. First, you have some time to look at questions 1 to 4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. . . . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>※You&amp;rsquo;ll see that there&amp;rsquo;s an example that has been done for you. On this occasion only, the conversation relating to this will be played first. ※&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good morning, oh, sorry, it&amp;rsquo;s gone twelve. I&amp;rsquo;ll start again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good afternoon, Kingswell Sports Club, how can I help you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, good afternoon. I was wondering if you could give me some information about membership and facilities?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>※The name of the sports club is Kingswell. So Kingswell has been written in the space. ※&lt;/p>
&lt;p>※Now we should begin. You should answer the questions as you listen because you&amp;rsquo;ll not hear the recording a second time. Listen carefully and answer questions 1 to 4. ※&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good morning, oh, sorry, it&amp;rsquo;s gone twelve. I&amp;rsquo;ll start again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good afternoon, Kingswell Sports Club, how can I help you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, good afternoon. I was wondering if you could give me some information about membership and facilities?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course. what would you like to know?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do you have tennis courts, for example?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>NO, I&amp;rsquo;m afraid we don&amp;rsquo;t. We are primarily a golf club.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s about football? I heard you had a team.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>NO, I&amp;rsquo;m sorry. Perhaps you&amp;rsquo;re thinking about Fresham Sports Centre.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, right. I Know it, I&amp;rsquo;ve played badminton there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have you? They&amp;rsquo;ve got a lot of facilities we don&amp;rsquo;t have and vice versa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We do have a keep-fit studio, which is very popular with members, and then as well as that there a swimming, of course.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s good. I like to swim every day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have a range of classes too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do you have judo classes? I&amp;rsquo;m keen to learn.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, at the moment, we offer kick-boxing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are planning to add judo and stretch classes soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are currently running a range of Yoga classes too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What about relaxing after exercise? I assume you have a restaurant or something?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the moment, we&amp;rsquo;ve got a salad bar which is very popular.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ll also have a fully-licensed restaurant by the end of the year. -Sounds good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>※Before you hear the rest of the conversation, you have some time to look at questions 5 to 10. ※&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. . . . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>※Now listen and answer questions 5 to 10. ※&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What kind of membership are you interesting in?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Umm, I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure. What are the options?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, there are three different membership schemes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I see. What&amp;rsquo;s the difference?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, the first one&amp;rsquo;s called Gold, and you can use all the facilities at any time of day or week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can also join in as many classes as you like for free.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That sounds good. Is it very expensive?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, you pay a ￡250 joining fee and then is ￡450. . . oh, no, I&amp;rsquo;m sorry, It&amp;rsquo;s just gone up by fifty pounds, Sorry about that - It&amp;rsquo;s now ￡500 for the annual subscription fee.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, got that. And what&amp;rsquo;s the next type?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, that&amp;rsquo;s Silver- it&amp;rsquo;s the same as Gold except you have to pay a small fee of ￡1 per lesson for any you do and you can only use the centre at a certain times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I see, so when exactly?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can only use the facilities between 10am. and 4.30pm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I couldn&amp;rsquo;t use the pool at 8 in the morning or evening, then? -That&amp;rsquo;s right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, and the price for that? is the joining fee the same as for Gold?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Actually, it&amp;rsquo;s slightly less than the ￡250. - It&amp;rsquo;s ￡225, but the annual fee is only ￡300. Does that sound more like what you want?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, it&amp;rsquo;s still rather more expensive than I thought.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m a student here in England and I&amp;rsquo;m only here for six months.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ah, then the bronze scheme would probably suit you best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And how is that different?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, some of the facilities have restricted use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And do I have to pay for classes?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, It&amp;rsquo;s ￡3 for each class you join.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I see. And what are the Hours then?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Between 10.30 and 3.30 weekdays only, and you pay a ￡50 joining fee.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The annual fee is ￡180 -It works out at ￡15 a month so that would be quite a lot cheaper.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, that should be all right. I could come in my free periods.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What do I have to do if I want to join?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well we book you in for an assessment with an instructor who will show you how to use all the equipment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you want to organise a trial session and look around the centre you&amp;rsquo;ll need to speak to David Kynchley.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hmm. Could you spell that please?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, David K-Y-N-C-H-L-E-Y.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll give you his direct line number.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s O-four-five-eight, nine -five- three- double one.0458 95311。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks. -Thank you for calling Kingswell Club.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>※That is the end of section 1. You now have half of a minute to check your answers. Now turn to section 2. ※&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 6.1.2</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.1.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.1.2/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll hear a local radio broadcast about Rivendon city theatre. First, you have some time to look at questions 11 to 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen carefully and answer questions 11 to 16.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And here on Radio Rivendon we have Lynne Rawley, the Public Relation Officer of our Rivendon City Theatre. Hello Lynne. -Hello.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, the theatre is reopening soon after its three-years redevelopment programme, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s right, and there are a lot of improvements.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first thing people will see when they go in, is that the foyer has been repainted in the original green and gold.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then the box office has been reoriented with its own access from the side of the building instead of through the foyer, which means it can be open longer hours, and has more space too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The shop that used to be in the foyer which sold books and CDs, is the one part of the redevelopment which isn&amp;rsquo;t yet complete.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The plan is to find new premises for it near the theatre, and we&amp;rsquo;ve had difficulty finding somewhere suitable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We hope to reopen the shop in the next few month.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Will audiences find any difference in the auditorium?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, we&amp;rsquo;ve increased the leg-room between the rows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This means that there are now fewer seats but we are sure audiences will be much happier.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And we&amp;rsquo;ve installed air conditioning, so it won&amp;rsquo;t get hot and stuffy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We already had a few seats which were suitable for wheelchair users, and now there are twice as many, which we hope will meet demand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Something else that will benefit the audiences is the new lifts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The two we used to have were very small and slow, They&amp;rsquo;re now gone, and we&amp;rsquo;ve got much more efficient ones.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anything for the performers?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, we&amp;rsquo;ve made a number of improvements backstage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The small dark dressing rooms we used to have been converted into two large airy rooms, so they are much more comfortable now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the state-of -the-art electronic sound and lighting systems has been installed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you hear the rest of the talk, you have some time to look at questions 17 to 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen and answer questions 17 to 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, so what&amp;rsquo;s the first play that the audiences can see when the theatre reopens?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve got a very exciting production of Peter Shaffer&amp;rsquo;s Royal Hunt of the Sun, which is currently touring the country.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That starts on October the 13th and running till the 19th.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re experimenting a bit with the time the curtain goes up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We used to start all our performances at 7.30, but that made it difficult for people to go home by public transport, so instead, we&amp;rsquo;re beginning at 7.00, because at 9.45 when it finishes, there&amp;rsquo;re still buses running.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tickets are already selling fast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Friday and Saturday performances sold out immediately and, in fact, now there are only tickets for Monday and Thursday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How much are they?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve introduced a simpler price structure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ticket prices used to range from ￡6 to ￡30 but now they are all ￡18.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are available from the box office, in person, by phone, fax or post, or on line.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, Lynne, now if you&amp;rsquo;d like to give the contact details for the theatre&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section 2. You now have half of a minute to check your answers. Now turn to section 3.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 6.1.3</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.1.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.1.3/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll hear a man inquiring about college courses. First, you have some time to look at questions 21 to 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen carefully and answer questions 21 to 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hi, can I help you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was told to come here, because I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk to someone about taking a management course.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, I&amp;rsquo;m one of the tutors, so I should be able to help you. -Oh, good. My name is Brian Ardley, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to enroll on a part-time management course.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A friend of mine took one last year and recommended it to me. -Right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is there anything I should do before the course, like reading or anything?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We prefer to integrate reading with the course, so we don&amp;rsquo;t give out a reading list in advance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But we like people to write a case study, describing an organisation they know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve ready done that, as my friends told me you wanted one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But would it be possible to sit in on a teaching session, to see what it&amp;rsquo;s like?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I haven&amp;rsquo;t been a student for quite a while.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fine, just let me know which date, and I&amp;rsquo;ll arrange it with the tutor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now could I ask you about the college facilities, please?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anything in particular?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, the course is one day a week, all days, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? so presumably it&amp;rsquo;s possible to buy food?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, the refectory&amp;rsquo;s open all day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Does it cater for special diets? I have some food allergies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Provided you warn the refectory in advance, it won&amp;rsquo;t be problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good, what about facilities for young children?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I would like to bring my daughter here while I&amp;rsquo;m studying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How old is she? -Three.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then she is eligible to join the Nursery, which is supervised by qualified Nursery Nurse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The waiting list for a place is quite long though, so you ought to apply now. -OK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t know if our career advice service would be of any interest to you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, it might help me to decide how to develop my career after the course.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The centre has a lot of reference materials and staff qualified to give guidance on a one-to-one basis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a fitness centre next to the college, Is that for students?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s open to everyone, but students pay an annual fee that&amp;rsquo;s much less than the general public pay.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And presumably the college library stocks newspapers and journals as well as books?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, and there&amp;rsquo;s also an audio-visual room for viewing and listening to videos, cassettes and so on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is there also access computers?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, your tutor will need to arrange with the technical support team for you to get password, so ask him or her about it when you start the course. -OK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you hear the rest of the conversation, you have some time to look at questions 26 to 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen and answer questions 26 to 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By the way, do you know about our Business Center?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No, what&amp;rsquo;s that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a training resource, a collection of materials for people studying on their own, or use in their own organisations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Uhuh, you mean books and videos?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, and manual for self-study.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plus a lot of computer base materials so people can work through them at their own speeds, and repeat anything they aren&amp;rsquo;t sure about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And you can hire laptops to use in your own home or workplace as well as printers that you can take away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Does it have anything that I could use to improve my study skills?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t have much idea about report writing, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll need it on the course.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh yes, there are plenty of useful materials just ask one of the staff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Does the center cover all of the main areas of business? -Yes, topics like finance, and of course marketing - that&amp;rsquo;s a popular one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Local manager seems to queue up to borrow the videos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it isn&amp;rsquo;t just for students, then?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No, it&amp;rsquo;s for members only, but anyone can join.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How much does they cost?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>￡100 a year for a company and ￡50 for an individual, with no discount for students, I&amp;rsquo;m afraid.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s very helpful. Well, I think that&amp;rsquo;s all. I&amp;rsquo;d better go home and fill in the enrollment form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks for your help. -You are welcome. Goodbye. -Goodbye.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section 3. You now have half of a minute to check your answers. Now turn to section 4.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 6.1.4</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.1.4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.1.4/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll hear a talk on the social history of the East End of London. First, you&amp;rsquo;ll have some time to look at the questions 31 to 40.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. . . . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, listen carefully and answer questions 31 to 40.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the last few weeks, we&amp;rsquo;ve been looked at various aspects of the social history of London.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And this morning we&amp;rsquo;ll continue with a look at life in the area called the East End.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll start with a brief history of the district, and then focus on life in the first half of the twentieth century.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Back in the first to the fourth centuries AD, when the Romans controlled England, London grew into a town of 45,000 people, and what&amp;rsquo;s now the East End - the area by the River Thames, and along the road heading north-east from London to the coast - consisted of farmland with crops and livestock, which helped to feed that population.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Romans left in 410, at the beginning of the fifth century, and from then onwards the country suffered a series of invasions by tribes from present-day Germany and Danmark, the Angles, Saxons and Jutes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many of whom settled in the East End.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The technology they introduced meant that metal and leather goods were produced there for the first time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And as the East End was by the river, ships could transport goods between there and foreign markets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the 11th century, in 1066 to be precise, the Normans conquered England, and during the next few centuries London became one of the most powerful and prosperous cities in Europe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The East End benefited from this, and because there were fewer restrictions there than in the city itself, plenty of newcomers settled there from abroad, bringing their skills as workers, merchants or money-lenders during the next few hundred years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the sixteenth century, the first dock was dug where ships were constructed, eventually making the East End the focus of massive international trade.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And in the late sixteenth century, when much of the rest England were suffering economically, a lot of agriculture workers came to the East End to look for alternative work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the seventeenth century, the East End was still a series of separate, Semi-rural settlements.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There was a shortage of accommodation, so marshland was drained and built on to house the large numbers of people now living there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By the nineteenth century, London was the busiest port in the world, and this became the main source of employment in the East End.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those who could afford to live in more pleasant surroundings moved out, and the area became one where the vast majority people lived in extreme poverty, and suffered from appalling sanitary conditions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That brief outline takes us to the beginning of twentieth century, and now we&amp;rsquo;ll turn to housing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the beginning of the century, living conditions for the majority working people in East London were very basic indeed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Houses were crowded closely together and usually very badly built, because there was no regulation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But the poor and needy were attracted by the possibility of work, and they had to be housed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was the availability, rather than the conditions, of the housing that was the major concern for tenants and landlords alike.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Few houses had electricity at this time, so other sources of power were used, like coal for the fires which heated perhaps just one room.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course, the smoke from these contributed a great deal to the air pollution for which London used to be famous.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A tiny, damp, unhealthy house like this might well be occupied by two full families, possibly including several children, grandparents, aunts and uncles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, before I go on to health implications of this way of life, I&amp;rsquo;ll say something about food and nutrition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s the end of section 4, you now have half a minute to check your answers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. . . . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s the end of listening test. In the IELTS test, you will now have ten minutes to transfer your answers to the listening answer sheet.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 6.2.1</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.2.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.2.1/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll hear a woman calling a local museum about children&amp;rsquo;s Art and Craft Workshops. First, you have some time to look at questions 1 to 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. . . . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll see that there&amp;rsquo;s an example that has been done for you. On this occasion only, the conversation relating to this will be played first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good morning, Synmouth Museum, can I help you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, yes, good morning. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in the children&amp;rsquo;s workshops and I&amp;rsquo;d like a little more information, please?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do you mean the Art and Craft Workshops?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, a friend of a friends mentioned them - the children do painting or making models and so forth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, of course. Umm, where to begin? First of all, as you probably known they run every Saturday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The workshops are organized every Saturday, so Saturday has been written in the space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now we should begin. You should answer the questions as you listen because you&amp;rsquo;ll not hear the recording a second time. Listen carefully and answer questions 1 to 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good morning, Synmouth Museum, can I help you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, yes, good morning. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in the children&amp;rsquo;s workshops and I&amp;rsquo;d like a little more information, please?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do you mean the Art and Craft Workshops?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, a friend of a friends mentioned them - the children do painting or making models and so forth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, of course. Umm, where to begin? First of all, as you probably known they run every saturday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fine, and what about ages?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, all ages from five upwards are welcome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Though we do ask the that children below eight years of age are accompanied by an adult.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fine, that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a problem. What about cost?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, I think that you will find them very reasonable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s ￡2.50 a child, with 80 pence off for two or more children from the same family.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, yes, very reasonable. And are they held in the main museum?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not exactly, they are nearby.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Could you give me the full address? I don&amp;rsquo;t know the area very well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, It&amp;rsquo;s Winter House. -Right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that&amp;rsquo;s in Tamer Street.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Could you spell that please?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, T-A-M-E-R, street. -Lovely.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I do need to tell you that there&amp;rsquo;s a security entrance, so you need to press the green button for someone to let you in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t press the red button please, But don&amp;rsquo;t worry, it&amp;rsquo;s all clearly labeled.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, and one more question, is parking available nearby? We&amp;rsquo;re driving in from out of town.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your best bet is to leave your car at the back of library - on a Saturday morning there are plenty of space there. It&amp;rsquo;s right next door to the museum.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And can I ask about booking places?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, and I must tell you, you really should book by calling the Education Department here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, I&amp;rsquo;m sorry. Should I have rung them instead of the main museum number?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No, that&amp;rsquo;s fine this time, Please don&amp;rsquo;t worry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But for future reference, I&amp;rsquo;ll give you the direct number. It&amp;rsquo;s two hundred-seven-six-five.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Great, I&amp;rsquo;ve got that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you hear the rest of the conversation, you have some time to look at questions 6 to 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. . . . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen and answer questions 6 to 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I&amp;rsquo;m very happy to give you information about the next two workshops. On Saturday the sixteenth, there&amp;rsquo;s Building Castles. -Oh, sounds great!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This involves quite a bit of glue, so just make sure the kids are in old clothes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know, ones I don&amp;rsquo;t mind getting mucky.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Exactly, and if possible, could you bring along bottle tops which the children might be able to use in models, you know, as decoration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ll certainly try to find some for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then the following week. . . -That will be the twenty-third (23rd) , won&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s right. On that day, it&amp;rsquo;s what we call Undersea Worlds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is where they make scenes with fishes, underground caverns and so on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is that likely to get very dirty? lots of paint splashes?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not really, so we don&amp;rsquo;t recommend any special clothes for that one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But if you could search out some silver paper to bring along to use in the sessions, you know, It&amp;rsquo;s shiny - it looks like water, that would be great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, of course. we&amp;rsquo;ll see what we can come up with.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, thank you ever so much for all your help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The sessions sound really good, and I&amp;rsquo;ll certainly book up for the next two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lovely, thanks very much for ringing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bye. -Bye-bye.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section one. You now have half of a minute to check your answers. Now turn to section two.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 6.2.2</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.2.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.2.2/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll hear a customer services official giving information to a passenger at a railway station in a town called Trebirch . First, you have some time to look at questions 11 to 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. . . . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen carefully and answer questions 11 to 17.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hello. Um my family and I are staying here in Trebirch for a week or two, and we wanted to know about the train services, we&amp;rsquo;re hoping to do a few local trips.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, well, I can give you lots of details about all the trains going from Trebirch in the south west.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This leaflet will be very helpful but I can tell you some of the main things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve got two main train stations in this town, King Street is for local commuter lines and regional services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What about trains to London? I&amp;rsquo;ll need to go there on business for one day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then you need to go to Central Station, that&amp;rsquo;s for all the national services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are regular trains to London. They leave Trebirch every half hour on weekdays and every hour at weekends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It takes about two hours, a bit longer on Sundays.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ve got a choice of first and second class and there&amp;rsquo;s a buffet car-though refreshments are included in the cost of a first class ticket.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ah, right. Um, and have you got any information on different ticket types?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, there&amp;rsquo;s a range of ticket prices depending on when you travel and when you buy your ticket.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a standard open ticket which doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any restrictions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This can be bought in advance or on the day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You could also get various discounted tickets. A popular one is called the Supersave, and, er, this is OK for travel after 8.45.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then there&amp;rsquo;s the Special ticket, which is valid for travel after 10.15.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Special tickets are also valid for travel at weekends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The cheapest tickets are called Advance, and you have to to buy them at least six days ahead.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Only a certain number are available and you have to make seat reservations for these.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you hear the rest of the conversation, you have some time to look at questions 18 to 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. . . . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen and answer questions 18 to 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks, and are there lots of places to go to around here?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, yes. you could enjoy many days out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Um, there&amp;rsquo;s the Merthyr Mining Museum, which is only half an hour from Trebirch by train.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your children will find it just as fascinating as any theme park and they can ride in the regional miners&amp;rsquo; lifts and on the coal trains.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are special excursion tickets which include entrance fees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mainline trains also offer direct services to Bristol, where you can visit the docks or spend a great day out with the children in the Zoo, which is set in the parkland that used to surround the old castle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Er, special family awayday fares are available for the service now during the school holidays.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Er, alternatively you can be in Birmingham in only an hour and a half, where there is lots to see and do including the new and internationally-acclaimed Climbing Wall built on the site of the old aquarium.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We will also be running a special service to Newport, when the new science museum opens next year, as we anticipate a lot of visitors in the opening weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d advise you to call early to book your ticket. Is that OK? -Yes, thanks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section 2. You now have half of a minute to check your answers. Now turn to section 3.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 6.2.3</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.2.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.2.3/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll hear a discussion between a tutor and an Education student called Sandy about the student&amp;rsquo;s dissertation. First, you have some time to look at questions 21 to 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. . . . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen carefully and answer questions 21 to 25.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hello, Sandy. How have you been getting on with your dissertation?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fine, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been working hard on the various action points we agreed on our last tutorial.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do you want to talk me though what you have done?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yeah, sure. Well, we agree on three main targets for me to aim for.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first one was to find out about suitable data analysis software. -Yes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And what I decide to do was to look through catalogues specialising in IT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a good idea, what did your come up with?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I find the names of two promising ones. -Right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I also thought it&amp;rsquo;d be worthwhile talking to a lecturer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, right. Who did you say?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jane Prince. Do you know her? She is in the Computer Center?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, of course. She is the new head.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, well. She was very helpful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s good. Did she suggest anything in particular?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, she recommended software called Vivat and said I should book up for a couple of practice sessions using Vivat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Great, I&amp;rsquo;m sure you&amp;rsquo;ll find them useful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course the second target was to draw up survey checklist which I. . . -Yes, you&amp;rsquo;ve email me it last week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>have you had a chance to look. . . ? -Of course.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Um I think it&amp;rsquo;s good. Very much on the right lines. I&amp;rsquo;d say your first two sections are spot on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t suggest that you change anything there, but in section three you really do need to have questions on teaching experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yeah, I was thinking that section looked a bit short. -Right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And my third target was, do further reading on discipline.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, yes. I mentioned a couple of writers, didn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, well I got hold of the Banerjee, and I thought that was excellent. But I&amp;rsquo;m afraid I didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to get hold of the essays about classroom management-you know the ones by Simon Ericsson.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The bookshop said it was out of print and the library doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a copy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, right, and I&amp;rsquo;m afraid I have lent my copy to another student.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I suggest you do is try the library again-This time apply for it through the service called special loans.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have you done that before? You are entitled to six books a year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, no problem, That&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ll do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, lots of useful work done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you hear the rest of the conversation, you have some time to look at questions 26 to 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. . . . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen and answer questions 26 to 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So let&amp;rsquo;s look at some new targets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ll start by having a chat about your chapter one. I very much enjoyed reading it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You Written style is very clear and you&amp;rsquo;ve included lots of interesting descriptions of educations in your target area.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve just got a couple of suggestions for some additional work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course, could I just ask- what do you think I should call it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, I&amp;rsquo;d go for something like context Review, what do you think?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, short and to the point. -Exactly, now, as regard specific areas to work on, I&amp;rsquo;d be quite interest to have a few more statistics about the schools in the different zones.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a problem. I can get them from internet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Great, and although you did make a reference to quite a few different writers, I think you should aim to cite more works written from later than 2000.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ok, that&amp;rsquo;s more difficult, but I can try.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When do you want that done by?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, it&amp;rsquo;s not urgent. Um, I should aim for the end of term.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But in the meantime, I think you should also be thinking about Chapter Two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Should I be drafting it already?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No, but I think you should note down its the main section.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, you know, I always find that the hardest part. -I always find it helpful to put some ideas on index card. -Yeah.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Um. . . and then you can sort them, and even lay them out on floor. It&amp;rsquo;s a real help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, I&amp;rsquo;ll certainly try it!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When would the deadline be for that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My advice would be to get it done before you embark upon the research.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can always change it later if you need to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, I&amp;rsquo;ll get going on that then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section 3. You now have half of a minute to check your answers. Now turn to section 4.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 6.2.4</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.2.4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.2.4/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll hear a part of lecture about the history of moving pictures. First, you&amp;rsquo;ll have some time to look at the questions 31 to 40.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, listen carefully and answer questions 31 to 40.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many believe that the story first began in America in 1877, when two friends were arguing over whether a horse ever had all four feet or hooves off the ground when it galloped.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To settle the bet, a photographer was asked to photograph a horse galloping and the bet was settled, because you could see that all the hooves were off the ground in some of the photos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What was even more interesting, was that if the photos were shown in quick succession, the horse looked like it was running - - in other words, &amp;quot; moving pictures'.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The person who became interested in taking the moving pictures to its next step was the famous American inventer Thomas Edison.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Actually, he didn&amp;rsquo;t do the work himself, but rather asked a young Scotsman in his employ to design the system, which he did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, this young fellow was clever, because the first thing he did was study other systems-primitive as they were - of moving pictures. And then, put all existing technologies together to make the first entire motion picture system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He designed a camera, a projection device and the film.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The system was first shown in New york in 1894 and was really very popular.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apparently people lined up around the block to see the wonderful new invention.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There were, however, a couple of problems with the system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The camera weighed over two hundreds kilograms and only one person at a time could see the film.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well now, news of the new system in America travelled fast. And a number of rival European systems started to appear once people had heard about that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The single problem with all the systems, was they couldn&amp;rsquo;t really project the film onto a screen-you know, so more than one person could see it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then in 1895, three systems were all developed, more or less at the same time and independently of each other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I guess the most famous of these was by the Lumere Brothers from France, and they called their system the &amp;lsquo;cinematographe&amp;rsquo;, which of course is where the word &amp;lsquo;cinema&amp;rsquo; comes from.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There were also two brothers in Germany who developed a successful system and they called it &amp;lsquo;Bioskop&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well now, once the problem of projection had been solved, the next challenge for this inventors was to make the films longer and more interesting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A continuing problem at the time was the film had a tendency to break when they were being played - a problem which was caused by the tension between the two wheels, or &amp;lsquo;reels&amp;rsquo; as they are called, which hold the film.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now this problem was solved by two American brothers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They developed the &amp;lsquo;Lantham Loop&amp;rsquo;, which was the simple addition of a third reel between the two main reels, and this took all the tension away with the result that the films stopped snapping.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So now there was a real possibility of having films of more than two or three minutes, and this led to the making of &amp;lsquo;Great Train Robbery&amp;rsquo;- the very first movie made.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It only lasted eleven minutes but was absolute sensation, and there were cases of people watching the movie and actually fainting when the character fired a gun at the camera!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Almost overnight movies became craze. And by 1905 people in America were lining up to see movies in &amp;lsquo;store theatre&amp;rsquo;, as they were called them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I guess the next big step in terms of development of technology, was to have people actually talking on the film, and first step towards this was in 1926, when sound effects were first used on a film.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until the follow years however that the first &amp;rsquo;talkie&amp;rsquo;, as they were called then, was made.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This film featured actors speaking only during parts of the film and was called The Jazz Singer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until in 1928 that the first all-talking film was produced, and this was called The Lights of New York.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, the sound on this early film was not very good and I believe they put subtitles on the film- that is, they printed the dialogue along the bottom of the film to compensate for this poor sound quality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, with the addition of sound, moving pictures became far more difficult to make.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s the end of section 4, you now have half of a minute to check your answers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s the end of listening test. In the IELTS test, you will now have ten minutes to transfer your answers to the listening answer sheet.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 6.3.1</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.3.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.3.1/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll hear a man talking to the customer services manager of a bank. First, you have some time to look at questions 1 to 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll see that there&amp;rsquo;s an example that has been done for you. On this occasion only, the conversation relating to this will be played first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good morning. I&amp;rsquo;d like to open a bank account, please?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Certainly, if you like to take a seat, I&amp;rsquo;ll just get some details from you. It won&amp;rsquo;t take long. -Thanks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is it a current account or a deposit Account you wanted?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A current account.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The man wishes to apply for a current account. So current has been written in the space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now we should begin. You should answer the questions as you listen because you&amp;rsquo;ll not hear the recording a second time. Listen carefully and answer questions 1 to 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good morning. I&amp;rsquo;d like to open a bank account, please?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Certainly, if you like to take a seat, I&amp;rsquo;ll just get some details from you. It won&amp;rsquo;t take long. -Thanks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is it a current account or a deposit Account you wanted?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A current account.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, I&amp;rsquo;ve got the application from here then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have different types- I see you&amp;rsquo;ve got our leaflet there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided on the one called &amp;lsquo;Select&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, that&amp;rsquo; fine, so, first of all, can I have you full name please?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s Pieter Henes. That&amp;rsquo;s P-I-E-T-E-R.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is it H-E-double N-E-S?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Uh, only one N actually, It&amp;rsquo;s a less commonly spelling of the name.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, right. OK. And what&amp;rsquo;s your date birth please?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The twenty-seventh of the first nineteen seventy-three.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, and will it be a joint account? -No, just myself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, fine. And where are you living, Mr. Henes? -Fifteen Riverside.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is that all one word? -Yes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Exeter? Yes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How long have you been at the present address? Er is it more than two years?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ah, just two weeks actually. I only arrived in the country a month ago. I&amp;rsquo;m from Holland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s fine. But we normally ask for a previous address in that case.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh yes, well, It&amp;rsquo;s Rielsdorf 2, that&amp;rsquo;s R-i-e-l-s-d-o-r-f 2, Utrecht.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Holland, OK. Thank you. Do you have day-time telephone number?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, I think the number in my office is six-oh-six-two-nine-five, Um, just a minute. I&amp;rsquo;d better check.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, no sorry, six-one-six. I&amp;rsquo;m not used to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Would you like my home number too? -Yes, please.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s seven-nine-six-four-three-one.796431。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Are they both local numbers? -Yes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you hear the rest of the conversation, you have some time to look at questions 6 to 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. . . . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen and answer questions 6 to 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, and your occupation?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, I&amp;rsquo;m in Britain as a project manager, but that&amp;rsquo;s not my main job. I&amp;rsquo;m a engineer by profession.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I see. I think I&amp;rsquo;ll put that then. It&amp;rsquo;s shorter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now we usually ask for a piece information which we can used to check your identity, for security reasons. you know, if you phone us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like, erm, , my wife&amp;rsquo;s first name?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mother&amp;rsquo;s might be better, it&amp;rsquo;s less likely to be known.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, hers is Siti. -Siti?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, S-I-T-I, it&amp;rsquo;s Indonesian.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fine, and how much would you like to open your account with? We usually ask for a minimum sum of fifty pounds. That&amp;rsquo;s about seventy-five euros.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, I&amp;rsquo;m going to transfer 2000 euros from my Dutch account, just till I get paid.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In fact, I want to ask you about that. What&amp;rsquo;s the best way to do it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It depends which bank you&amp;rsquo;re with.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s the France Bank in Utrecht.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ok, fine. I&amp;rsquo;ll check that in a minute. If you have a link with them, we can do a direct transfer, but it&amp;rsquo;s not a big problem either way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Em, Let&amp;rsquo;s see. How often would you like to receive statement?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I haven&amp;rsquo;t really thought. Um, What&amp;rsquo;s the usually thing?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s up to you. some people like them weekly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, no, that&amp;rsquo;s too often. Can I have them sent, um, once a month?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s fine. Is there anything else?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was thinking of registering for your internet service at some stage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, yes. Would you like me to send you information about that? -Please, yes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And would you like to receive information about bank&amp;rsquo;s other services- insurance, loans, anything like that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hmm, I don&amp;rsquo;t think so, thanks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s OK, then, and one last thing if you agree. . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section 1. You now have half of a minute to check your answers. Now turn to section 2.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 6.3.2</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.3.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.3.2/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll hear a guide giving visitors to a country house information about the house and gardens. First, you have some time to look at questions 11 to 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen carefully and answer questions 11 to 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Welcome, everybody, to the lovely house and gardens of Rosewood, once the home of the famous writer, Sebastian George.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He bought the house in 1902 although he had first seen it two years early.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At that time the owners let it out to a tenant, because George was too slow making up his mind to buy it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When it came back on the market, there was no hesitation and he bought it immediately.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For nine thousands three hundreds pounds, even though the house had no bathroom, no running water upstairs, and no electricity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When he came here, he&amp;rsquo;d been married for ten years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During that time, he had became one of the most famous writers in the English-speaking world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>His professional success was enormous, but his personal life wasn&amp;rsquo;t as successful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He was no longer on speaking terms with his brother and he had been devastated by the death at the age seven of his elder daughter, Josephine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moving to Rosewood allowed the family to start a new life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>George regarded the Rosewood as a pure example of traditional country house of this part of England and did some of his most successful writing here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The house and its grounds became the family haven and their escape to privacy and quite.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The walls, and the mullioned windows, were built of the local sandstone, the tiles on the roofs and the bricks of the chimney stack, were baked from local clay, and the wooden structures inside, came from oak trees which grow around here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you hear the rest of the talk, you have some time to look at questions 14 to 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen and answer questions 14 to 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, please look at the map I&amp;rsquo;ve given you of the house and gardens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are here at the Information Center.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Follow the path marked with arrow and the first area you come to is the orchard on your left.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As you go further down the path, there&amp;rsquo;s the Kitchen Garden on the right, and as you go round the first sharp corner, you will find, to your left an area where different types of pear trees have been planted as well as some lovely flowers, and this is known as Pear Alley- designed by George himself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next to this is the Greenhouse, where some exotic plants and fruits are grown.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Followed the path on the second corner and on your right you will see the entrance to the Mulberry Garden with its five hundred years old tree.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Past the Mulberry Garden, follow the path until you reach the front of the house.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I suggest you spend a good hour wandering around the lovely building.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A guider takes visitor groups round every two hours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you would like to purchase any of George&amp;rsquo;s books or other souvenirs, then leave the house by the side entrance, where you will find our shop, which is situated between the house and the garage which contains the magnificent Rolls-Royce car which used to belong to George.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I expect by this time you may also be in need a rest and some refreshment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most visitor are, so why don&amp;rsquo;t you visit the tea room on far side of the garage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have time, there&amp;rsquo;s a lovely walk down towards the River Dudwell. For me, this is the best part of the estate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This isn&amp;rsquo;t on the map, but it&amp;rsquo;s all clearly signposted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You cross the field which spreads along the bank of the river. In spring, this area is well worth a visit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Spend a minute or two watching in the water pass by underneath as you across the footbridge, and then continue along the River Walk through the woodland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On a hot summer&amp;rsquo;s day the trees along this path provide welcome shade.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eventually, you come to the water mill which used to provide electricity for the house- only about four hours every evening- in George&amp;rsquo;s time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And, finally, for those of you who would like to see the stunning views of the surrounding countryside, and who are a little bit more energetic, when you return from the mill take the first turning on your left and climb up to the viewpoint.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You won&amp;rsquo;t regret it. Enjoy your visit!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section 2. You now have half of a minute to check your answers. Now turn to section 3.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 6.3.3</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.3.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.3.3/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll hear two students Jack and Lucy discussing a marketing assessment they are working on together. First, you have some time to look at questions 21 to 24.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. . . . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen carefully and answer questions 21 to 24.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lucy, we really need to get working on this marketing assignment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve only got five weeks left to end of the term to design it, carry it out and then write up the result.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sure, well, let&amp;rsquo;s get started right now. Let&amp;rsquo;s go over the instructions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What exactly do we have to do?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, it says here we have to look at one area of the entertainment industry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a list of different types.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What are they?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Music, cinema, theatre, sport, and eating out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is that all? -Looks like it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So we choose one branch of the industry and then we look at how two different groups of people use it? Is that right? -Yes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And do we have to use any particular method to get our data?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Can we use mail out a questionnaire, or do face to face interviews or maybe even observation?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, actually, it looks like we don&amp;rsquo;t have a choice. We have to do telephone interviews.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ok, so at least we don&amp;rsquo;t have to waste time deciding between the different methods.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s right. Oh, and the other requirement is the number of interviewees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not too many I hope, ten, twenty?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, we have to do two groups, remember, and it looks like we have to interview fifteen for each group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s thirty altogether then. It&amp;rsquo;s going to take ages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, but remember we&amp;rsquo;re working on this together, so we&amp;rsquo;ll only have to do fifteen each.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, so those are all the requirements?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, looks like it. So, first, which area are we going to choose?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My preference would be cinema, since that&amp;rsquo;s where I spend most of my money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hmm, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that&amp;rsquo;s such a good idea. I don&amp;rsquo;t think there are huge differences in the market there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I mean you get young and old, male and female, rich and poor all going to the same movies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yeah, maybe you are right. let&amp;rsquo;s make it music then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right. So, what two groups will we compare and contrast?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Male and female?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No. Most of my female friends like the same music as me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Different age groups would much more likely to show up differences, I think.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you hear the rest of the discussion, you have some time to look at questions 25 to 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. . . . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen and answer questions 25 to 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yeah, I suppose you are right again. I&amp;rsquo;ll take some note, shall I? So. . . , Age Groups.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well. what do you think? Maybe twenty-five or under for one group, and forty-five or over for the other group?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That should show up differences. -Right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK. Next. How about the kind of the music they like? let&amp;rsquo;s give them some choices and then we can just tick boxes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, let&amp;rsquo;s have pop, jazz, folk, easy listening. . . what else?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, we should include classical. Some people like it, you know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ok. OK. And then we should have how they listen to music.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The medium. Right. Let&amp;rsquo;s include radio, CD- and then I guess there&amp;rsquo;s TV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What about concerts? you know, pubs and halls.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, yeah, we should include live music of course.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, we are on a roll now. Next point could be about where they get about the music.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You mean like, do they buy it in music shops or department stores?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, or download it from Internet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, that could be for recorded music.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then we need another section for live music. Where do they go for that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, let&amp;rsquo;s say disco, pub, club, concert hall?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or opera house? And I guess we should include karaoke bar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not many of them in the city.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, we&amp;rsquo;ll leave that out then. So. . . what left to do?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s it. Well, now we can make a time-scale for doing it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section 3. You now have half of a minute to check your answers. Now turn to section 4.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 6.3.4</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.3.4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.3.4/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll hear a lecture talking about farming in ancient Ireland. First, you&amp;rsquo;ll have some time to look at the questions 31 to 40.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. . . . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, listen carefully and answer questions 31 to 40.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good morning everyone. Last week, we were looking at the hunter-gatherers in Ireland, across the Irish Sea from England.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, we are going to move on to the period between the four and six thousand years ago, known as the Neolithic period, Which is when a total farming economy was introduced in Ireland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, there are several hypotheses about the origins of the first Neolithic settlers in Ireland, but most of these contain problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For instance, there are considerable archaeological difficulties about the theory that they came from England.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The evidence doesn&amp;rsquo;t really add up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But there are even greater practical problems about the theory they came directly from continental Europe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For one thing, It&amp;rsquo;s not clear just how sufficient numbers of men and women could have been transported to Ireland to establish a viable population.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As you know, the hunter-gatherer economy which existed beforehand was based on small scattered groups.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The farming economy would almost certainly have required much larger communities to do all the work needed plant and tend sufficient crops to sustain them through the year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The early farmers kept various animals, including cattle and sheep.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s also evidence of pigs, but it is possible that these could have been descended from the native wild species.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, we know from modern farming that if the level of breeding stock falls below about three hundred females, the future of species of locally is at risk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So we must assume that from the beginnings of Neolithic farming the number of breeding sheep would have considerably exceeded three hundred, and the national cattle herd must have been of a similar size.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The question is how these was brought to the area and where they came from?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s usually suggested that the Neolithic settles use skin-covered boats to transport livestock.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But this method would severely restricted the range of the colonising fleets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The sheer volume of animal transport necessary means it&amp;rsquo;s unlikely that this livestock could have been brought from anywhere further than England.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What about crops?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, two main cereal crops were introduced to Ireland during this time: wheat and barley, both in several varieties.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main evidence for their presence consists of impression on pottery, where a cereal grain accidentally became embedded in surface of a pot before it was fired.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The grain itself was destroyed by the firing, but left an impression of the pot which could be studied and identified by botanists.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s turn our attention now to the farming technology available at that time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before the cereal crops could be planted, it would have been necessary to clear the forest, and to break the ground by ploughing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The stone blade of a plough has been discovered during excavation in County Mayo in western Ireland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The body of the plough would have been of wood, and could have been drawn by people, but it&amp;rsquo;s also likely that cattle were used.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, the cultivation of crops and the husbandry of livestock brought about changes in people&amp;rsquo;s lifestyle such as the type of shelters they made.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For one thing, instead of moving from place to place they needed permanent dwellings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The stone axes used to chop down trees to make these dwellings were far superior to any of that the Stone Age hunter-gatherers used.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To make the axes, sources of suitable stone had to be found and systematically exploited.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These so-called &amp;lsquo;axes factories&amp;rsquo; were really quarries rather than factories, as the manufacture of the axes wasn&amp;rsquo;t regularly performed on the quarry site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, after the axes had been chipped into shape, they needed water and sand for grinding and polishing, so a high mountainside wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been an appropriate place for this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So this final stage of this manufacture must have been carried out close to water and sure enough, there&amp;rsquo;s ample evidence of this at coastal sites.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now It&amp;rsquo;s clear that these Neolithic axes was transported all over the Ireland, as well as the Scotland and south of England.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not really surprising that axes from &amp;lsquo;axes factories&amp;rsquo; in England have also been found in Ireland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the very least, these indicates that there was a link between the two islands during that period.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the most useful innovation of the colonisers was pottery making, which was quite unknown to Irish hunter-gatherers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The pottery was probably made by shaping clay into a ball with the hand, and then hollowing it until the walls were right thickness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After firing, the outside was often polished.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This would have helped the pots to retain water, as they were glazed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now we know that the clay used usually came from the local sources, which suggests that the manufacture was on a fairly small scale, even though thousands of fragments are usually found at Neolithic sites.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the course of time decoration began to appear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At first this looked like a series of stitches and was just around tops of the pots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This could have been imitation of earlier vessels which were made of leather sewn onto wood.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then eventually pots with decoration all over. . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s the end of section 4, you now have half of a minute to check your answers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. . . . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s the end of listening test. In the IELTS test, you will now have ten minutes to transfer your answers to the listening answer sheet.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 6.4.1</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.4.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.4.1/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 1&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll hear a telephone conversation between a woman and a reservation&amp;rsquo;s clerk at a Conference Centre. First, you have some time to look at questions 1 to 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. . . . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll see that there&amp;rsquo;s an example that has been done for you. On this occasion only, the conversation relating to this will be played first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Conference Centre Reservations. Good morning!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hi. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in the computer conference next month.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Future Directions in Computing?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The title of the course is Future Directions in Computing. So Future Directions has been written in the space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now we should begin. You should answer the questions as you listen because you&amp;rsquo;ll not hear the recording a second time. Listen carefully and answer questions 1 to 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Conference Centre Reservations. Good morning!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hi. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in the computing conference next month.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Future Directions in Computing?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Could I ask you a few questions about it? -Of course.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK. I know the conference is for three days. But actually I want to attend on the Friday and Saturday only.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Will that work out to be any cheaper?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s me have a look.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>well, you can register for the two day separately, but that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t actually save you very much, as it&amp;rsquo;s still cost thirty-five pounds for each day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In fact, if you could register for the three days, you also get an invitation to a free dinner on the Saturday night, so that probably the better option.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, I&amp;rsquo;ll do that. How much would the fees be in that case? -It&amp;rsquo;s seventy five pounds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, right. I&amp;rsquo;d like to register for the full three days.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, can I pay that by credit card?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m afraid not. You have to send a cheque to us, or you can pay at the conference office.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fine, so it&amp;rsquo;s probably easiest if I pay by cheque.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, then, what else do I need to arrange? Right, How about the accommodation?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I guess that&amp;rsquo;s not included in the price.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No, I&amp;rsquo;m sorry, it&amp;rsquo;s not, but we do have a few rooms available for delegates in the conference centre if you&amp;rsquo;d like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those are very cheap but, if you are interested you&amp;rsquo;ll need to book soon, because there&amp;rsquo;s always a heavy demand for them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They are only fifteen pounds per night, but they are very basic, and you&amp;rsquo;d have to get your own breakfast, because they don&amp;rsquo;t provide you with that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But It&amp;rsquo;s very convenient, because it&amp;rsquo;s in the same building as the conference rooms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Uh uh. Or there&amp;rsquo;s a very reasonable guest house which is twenty five pounds per night. And I think that&amp;rsquo;s includes breakfast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is it close to the conference centre?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It would be about a ten-minute walk away from here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I see, that sounds quite reasonable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you hear the rest of the conversation, you have some time to look at questions 6 to 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. . . . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen and answer questions 6 to 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The details are all in our conference pack, which I&amp;rsquo;ll send you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Great, thanks. That&amp;rsquo;ll be very useful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, and can you also send me a application form?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course. I&amp;rsquo;ll get that in the post to you straight away. Is there any thing else?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, actually. Can you tell me where exactly the Conference Centre is?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, it&amp;rsquo;s on South Park Road and it&amp;rsquo;s right at the end of the road next to the library.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a ten-minute taxi ride from station and will cost you five pounds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Otherwise you can take the bus which runs every half an hour from the station- that&amp;rsquo;s 21A- and it brings you straight to the conference centre. -Right, got that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section 1. You now have half of a minute to check your answers. Now turn to section 2.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 6.4.2</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.4.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.4.2/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 2&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll hear an introductory talk to a group of temporary workers at an international travel exhibition. First, you have some time to look at questions 11 to 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. . . . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen carefully and answer questions 11 to 13.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good morning and welcome, everybody. I&amp;rsquo;m Jenny Stewart and I&amp;rsquo;m the Staff Manager here at the exhibition centre.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re expecting this year&amp;rsquo;s International Travel Exhibition to attract over ten thousands visitors a day, ladies and Gentlemen, and you are among the two hundred extra staff recruited to help look after them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, to help things run smoothly, we have divided you into four teams- the blue team, the green team, the red team and the yellow team.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So first, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how the teams divided up, and then we will be given you colour-coded T-shirts so we can identify you more easily.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First of all, those who will be looking after the phones and handling all calls regarding the exhibition. You will be on the red team.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, we also put the entrance staff on the red team and you will be stamping the entrance tickets and giving out the publicity leaflets, OK?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those of you involved in distributing entrance tickets will be on the yellow team and we&amp;rsquo;ve also put those of you who will be the staffing the information booths around the conference centre on the yellow team, so you will be given a yellow T-shirt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now most of the hospitality staff have been put in the blue team, so the chefs among you and kitchen hands will all need a blue T-shirt, but, because of the sheer numbers, all waiting staff will be on the yellow team, and this includes the bar staff among you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those who will be monitoring and directing the traffic in the car parks are on the green team. So you&amp;rsquo;ll need to get a green T-shirt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This year, we&amp;rsquo;ve also employed a considerable numbers of attendants to direct he human traffic around the conference centre.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, you&amp;rsquo;ll be working in the exhibition halls at all times, giving directions and generally helping people whenever you can, and you will be in red team, so please collect a red T-shirt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you hear the rest of the talk, you have some time to look at questions 14 to 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. . . . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen and answer questions 14 to 20.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, now everyone knows what team they&amp;rsquo;re in, we&amp;rsquo;ll get on with the orientation and training programme and first I&amp;rsquo;ll run through the rest of today&amp;rsquo;s programme which you should have in front of you, so that you can get a general idea what of else in store today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This introduction finishes at nine thirty, and then you will be hearing from Anne Smith.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anne works in the accounts department on level two and she looks up all temporary staff, and so, she is the person to see if you have any problems regarding pay.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anne will be explaining when and how you get this, she would also be handing out your tax forms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I will just stress that all tax forms must be completed and return to Anne before your pay can be processed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following Anne&amp;rsquo;s talk you will hear from Peter Chen, our Conference Manager, and he will be going over a plan of the conference centre with you, which will help you to orient yourselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He will also go through the security arrangements with you, and show you the fire exits.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then at 10.30, there will be a coffee break in the staff canteen which is located down on the ground floor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, after the break we will be moving to a different location for a video presentation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So instead of coming back here, we&amp;rsquo;d like you all to go to Lecture Room three-one-one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll find it on this same level, just down the hall, and there you&amp;rsquo;ll be shown a video about important safety issues in the workplace, called &amp;quot; Safety at Work'.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We will finish off the morning with a lunch, which should give everyone a chance to meet and get to know each other, and we&amp;rsquo;ll be serving you a buffet lunch in the Main Hall, which on the first floor, from 12.00 clock.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After lunch, you&amp;rsquo;ll be divided up into your teams to meet your team leaders and we&amp;rsquo;re hoping to be all finished by 3.00 so I won&amp;rsquo;t delay you any longer and I&amp;rsquo;ll. . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section 2. You now have half of a minute to check your answers. Now turn to section 3.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 6.4.3</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.4.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.4.3/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 3&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll hear a conversation between a librarian and an Education student. First, you have some time to look at questions 21 to 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. . . . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen carefully and answer questions 21 to 27.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good afternoon. Can I help you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good afternoon. Yes, I&amp;rsquo;ve just transferred to the School of Education, and I&amp;rsquo;d like information about joining the library.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, the School of Education has libraries on two sites, as I&amp;rsquo;m sure you know. This one here is the Fordham site, and the other is on Castle Road.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And is there any difference between the two libraries?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not in terms of their facilities. Access to online Databases and the Internet is available at both sites and each site has a range of reference materials on education.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, yes, I see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But the Castle Road site has books on the sociology of education, and a collection of textbooks and teaching resources covering most of the subject taught in secondary schools.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ah, right, but I&amp;rsquo;m training to be a primary teacher, so I need to look up material for the five to eleven age group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then you&amp;rsquo;ve come to the right place. At Fordham we hold material relating to primary education as well as special needs, but of course you&amp;rsquo;ll need to familiarise yourself with both sites to make the most of our resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You haven&amp;rsquo;t mentioned periodicals. Are they held at both sites?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Current issues, yes but if you want to look at back issues you need to use the CD-rom databases which are held here at Fordham.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I see, now about borrowing books. I&amp;rsquo;m living out of towns, so I&amp;rsquo;m hoping I can borrow quite a few items, and cut down on the number of trips I have to make.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, well members can borrow two books at a time from each site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Only two books?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Only two from each site, but that&amp;rsquo;s four altogether.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, I see, and how long can I hang on to them for?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The borrowing period is one months but of course the books can be renewed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can renew any item a maximum of three times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do I have to come to the library to do that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No, you can do it by telephone or email, but you can&amp;rsquo;t renew overdue books this way, and only before or on the due date stamped in the book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ll need your full name, Your borrower number and the name of the site library you borrow the items from.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So theoretically I can borrow books for up to three month- is that what you&amp;rsquo;re saying?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, provided they&amp;rsquo;re not recalled.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, what happens then?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, sometimes an item is quested by another borrower, in which case we&amp;rsquo;d send you a letter, and you&amp;rsquo;d have to return the book within seven working days.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t forget we&amp;rsquo;re closed on Sundays. -OK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before you hear the rest of the conversation, you have some time to look at questions 28 to 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. . . . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now listen and answer questions 28 to 30.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I expect it&amp;rsquo;ll take me a while to find out what I need. There&amp;rsquo;s a such a lot here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, there is. but if you need help getting your started, this term we&amp;rsquo;re running three study skills workshops.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh? What are they on?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Er, let me see. The first one&amp;rsquo;s on resources, - yes, here it is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How to use the library&amp;rsquo;s resources. That includes everything, not just the print and technical resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That sounds useful. Is there anything on using the internet?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Er, let&amp;rsquo;s see. The one on the internet for beginners was last term.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This term it&amp;rsquo;s finding research materials online.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That sounds interesting too. What&amp;rsquo;s the last one? - It&amp;rsquo;s a workshop on dissertations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What do you mean- How to write one?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Er, no. It&amp;rsquo;s more to do with academic writing conventions, you know, writing a bibliography and how to refer to sources in your text. That sort of thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway, here is the leaflet with information about all three.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks a lot. They&amp;rsquo;ll be very useful. -You&amp;rsquo;re welcome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is the end of section 3. You now have half of a minute to check your answers. Now turn to section 4.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 6.4.4</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.4.4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l6.4.4/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 4&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll hear a part of lecture given by a conservationist on the subject to lions. First, you&amp;rsquo;ll have some time to look at the questions 31 to 40.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. . . . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, listen carefully and answer questions 31 to 40.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, most people think that lions only come from Africa. And you will be forgiven for thinking this because in fact that most lions do come from Africa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But this hasn&amp;rsquo;t always been the case.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we go back ten thousand years we would find there were lions roaming vast sections of the globe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But now, unfortunately, only very small sections of the lions&amp;rsquo; former habitat remain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My particular interest is Asiatic lions, which are a sub-species of African lions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s almost a hundred thousand years since the Asiatic lions split off and developed as a sub-species.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At one time Asiatic lions was living as far west as Greece and they were found from there, in a band that spread east through various countries of the Middle East, all the way to India.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In museums, you can now see Greek coins that have clear images of the Asiatic lion on them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most of them are dated at around 500 B. C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, Europe saw it&amp;rsquo;s last Asiatic lion roaming free two thousand years ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the next nineteen hundred years the numbers of Asiatic lions in the other areas declined steadily, but it was only in the nineteenth century that they disappeared from everywhere but India.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, how can you tell an Asiatic lion from an Africa lion, with which you&amp;rsquo;re probably more familiar?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, in general, Asiatic lions are not as big as Africa lions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The colour is more or less the same, but the appearance of the mane is different, that&amp;rsquo;s the hair around lion&amp;rsquo;s face and neck.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Asiatic lions mane is noticeably shorter than the Africa lion&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Asiatic lions also have a long fold of skin on their undersides, whereas not many Africa lions have this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk to you now about the Gir Sanctuary in India. That&amp;rsquo;s where I&amp;rsquo;ve just come back from.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The sanctuary was established specifically to protect the Asiatic lions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s 1,450 square kilometers in area and most of it is forest.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are now around three hundred Asiatic lions in India and almost all of them are in this sanctuary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But despite living in the sanctuary, which make them safe from hunters, they still faced a number of problems that threaten their survival.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of these is the ever-present danger of disease.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is what killed more than a third of Africa&amp;rsquo;s Serengeti lions in 1994, and people are fearful that something similar could happen in the Gir Sanctuary and kill off many of the Asiatic lions there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>India&amp;rsquo;s lions are particularly vulnerable because they have a limited gene pool.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The reason for this is interesting- it&amp;rsquo;s because all of them are descended from a few dozen lions that were saved by a prince who took particular interest in them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He was very wealthy, and he managed to protect them- otherwise they&amp;rsquo;d probably have died out completely.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you see the Asiatic lions in India, what you sense is enormous vitality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They are very impressive beasts and you will never guess that they had this vulnerability when you look at them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Asiatic lions don&amp;rsquo;t have the Gir sanctuary to themselves, I should add.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They actually share it with about 2,000 farmers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A significant proportion of the lions&amp;rsquo; diet is made up of the livestock of these farmers- goats, chickens and so on- as much as a third in fact.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And they&amp;rsquo;ve even be known to attack humans, especially in times of drought.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One final piece of interesting information- in ancient India one of the greatest tests of leadership for a man was to fight a lion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now it seems, in modern India it would be a great test to see if the lion can be saved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m sure this is something that all of you will share concern for too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s the end of section 4, you now have half of a minute to check your answers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>. . . . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s the end of listening test. In the IELTS test, you will now have ten minutes to transfer your answers to the listening answer sheet.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>