<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notebook – C7</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/ielts/listening/c7/</link><description>Recent content in C7 on Notebook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://note.codiy.net/docs/ielts/listening/c7/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: 7.1.1</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.1.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.1.1/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Hello, this is Land Transport Information at Toronto Airport. How may I help you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, Good morning. Um, I&amp;rsquo;am fly to Toronto Airport next week, and I need to get to a town called Uu, milton.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Could you tell me How I can get there?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Milton, did you say? Let me see. I think that&amp;rsquo;s about 150 miles southwest of here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In fact it&amp;rsquo;s 147 miles to be exact, so it will take you at least - say, three or four hours by road.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wow, is it as far as that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, I &amp;lsquo;am afraid so. But you have a number of options to get you there, and you can always rent a car right here at the airport, of course.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, well, I don&amp;rsquo;t really want to drive myself, so I&amp;rsquo;d like more information about public transport.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ok, in that case the quickest and most comfortable is a cab and of course there always plenty available. But it cost you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can also take a greyhound bus or there&amp;rsquo;s an Airport Shuttle service to Milton.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hmmm, I think for that kind of distance a cab would be way beyond my budget. But the bus sound OK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Can you tell me how much that would cost?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sure, Let&amp;rsquo;s see. that would be $15 one way, or $27. 50 return, that on the Greyhound.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s quite cheap- great! But whereabouts does it stop in Milton?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It goes directly from the airport here to the city centre and it&amp;rsquo;s pretty fast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But you have to bear in mind that there is only one departure a day, so it depends what time your flight gets in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, of course. Hang on, we&amp;rsquo;re due to get there at 11. 30 am?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hmmm, too bad. And the bus leave at 3. 45, so you would have quite a wait - more than 4 hours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, I see. well, what about the shuttle in mentioned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ok, that&amp;rsquo;s the Airport Shuttle that will take you from the airport right to your hotel or private address, it&amp;rsquo;s a door-to -door service and it would suit you much better, because there&amp;rsquo;s one every two hours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So how much does that cost?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s see. Yeah, That&amp;rsquo;s $35 one way, $65 return. So I guess it&amp;rsquo;s a bit more expensive than the Greyhound.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound too bad. especially if it&amp;rsquo;ll take me straight to the hotel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But you do need to reserve a seat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ok, Is it possible to make a booking right now, through you? Sure. . . . . . . . . . . . . Ok, I just have to fill this form out for you, so what date do you want to book this for?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The 16th of October, -oh, no, sorry, that&amp;rsquo;s my departure date. I arrive on the 17th, so book it for then, please.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So that the Toronto Airport Shuttle to Milton, and this is for just one person or. . . . . Yeah, yeah, just me, please.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, and you said your expected time of arrival was 11. 30?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, If I book your shuttle for after 12. 00, let&amp;rsquo;s say, 12. 30, that should give you plenty of time to, you know, collect baggage, maybe grab a coffee?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yeah, that sound fine, as long as we land on time!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, we&amp;rsquo;ll take your flight details so you don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry too much about that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, what about the fare? what sort of ticket do you want? One way or. . . . . . Yes, that will be fine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Provided I can book the return trip once I&amp;rsquo;m there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No problem, Just allow a couple of days to in advance to make sure you get a seat, and what&amp;rsquo;s your name, please?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Janet, Janet Thomson.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is that Thomson spelt with a &amp;lsquo;P&amp;rsquo;?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No, It&amp;rsquo;s T-H-O-M-S-O-N.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ok, and you will be coming from UK? What flight will you be travelling on?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, it&amp;rsquo;s Air Canada flight Number AC936 from London Heathrow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, now, do you know where you will be staying, we need to give the driver an address.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s called the Vacation Motel, And I think it near the town center.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway, the address is 24, Kitchener Street, That&amp;rsquo;s K_I_T_C_H_E_N_E_R Street.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s fine. Right, so that&amp;rsquo;s $35 to pay please. Have you got your credit card number there?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, It&amp;rsquo;s a VISA card, and the number is 3303 8450 2045 6837.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ok, well that seems to be everything. Have a good trip and we&amp;rsquo;ll see you in Toronto next week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, Bye-oh, thanks for your help.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 7.1.2</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.1.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.1.2/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Thank you all for coming to my talk this evening. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to see so many people in the audience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For those of you who don&amp;rsquo;t know very much about PS Camping, let me start by giving you some background information about the company.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The company start at 25 years ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It actually open as a retail chain selling camping equipment, and then 20 years ago, it bought a small number of campsites in the UK, and began offering camping holidays.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The company grew rapidly, and have been providing holidays in continental Europe for the last 15 years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you book a camping holiday with us, you&amp;rsquo;ll have a choice of over 300 sites.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Italy, we now have some 64 sites, that we either own, or have exclusive use of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>France, is where we have the majority of sites, and we currently have a project to expand into Switzerland.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also have a number of sites in northern Spain, particularly in the mountainous region of Picos de Europa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve upgraded all these spanish sites, and improved them considerably from there original three-star rating.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We believe our holidays offer superb facilities for the whole family.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Parents who want their children to be fully occupied for all or part of the day can take the advantage of our children&amp;rsquo;s activities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These are organized by our well-qualified and enthusiastic staff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each day kicks off with a sports match, perhaps football, or volleyball, followed by an hour of drama for everyone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These may include singing or dancing, mime or other activities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the afternoon, there&amp;rsquo;s a different art activities for each day of the week including a poster competition or model making.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s more, our sites are truly child-friendly, and, with this in mind, we operate a no-noise rule in the evenings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Children&amp;rsquo;s evening activities usually finish at 9. 30 or occasionally 10. 00, and from 10. 30 holiday-makers are expected to be quite in the areas where there are tents.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We want nothing to go wrong on a PS Camping holidays, but if it does, we also want all customers must be insured.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t organised an annually insurance policy of your own, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to take out the low-cost cover we offer and we require that you arrange this when you make your holiday reservation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are many advantages to choosing PS camping, and to recommending it to others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a regular customer, you will be kept informed special offers, and your friends can benefit from 10% off their holiday, or book a luxury tent for the price of standard one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In return, we will send you a thank-you present, which you can choose from a list of high-quality items. . . . . . . . . . . . . When it comes to our tents, these are equipped to the highest standard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We really do think of every essential detail, from an oven and cooking rings fuelled by bottled gas, to mirrors in the bedroom areas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you don&amp;rsquo;t want to cook indoors, you can borrow a barbeque, if you ask in advance for one to be made available, and there&amp;rsquo;s even a picnic blanket to sit on outside your tent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Inside, a box of games and toys can be found, and children&amp;rsquo;s tents can be hired if required.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All tents have a fridge, and if you want to spend the day on the beach, for example, ask for a specially designed PS Camping cool box, which would keep your food and drinks chilled.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are excellent washing facilities at all our sites, with washing machines and clothes lines in the central areas, along with mops and buckets, in case your tent needs cleaning during in your stay.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All sites have a cafe and/or a shop, for those who&amp;rsquo;d rather &amp;rsquo;eat in&amp;rsquo; than dine at a local restaurant.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 7.1.3</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.1.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.1.3/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Well, you&amp;rsquo;ve both been looking in different styles of managing individual in companies and the workplace, how&amp;rsquo;s the research going, Philip?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, I&amp;rsquo;m been looking at why individualism, I mean individual differences, are such an important areas of management studies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you think about any organisation, be it a family business or a multinational company, they&amp;rsquo;re all fundamentally a group of people working together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But it&amp;rsquo;s what these individuals contribute to their places of work that make you realize how important they are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course they bring different ideas, but it&amp;rsquo;s also their attitudes, and their experiences of learning. diversity is important in these areas too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So why do people behave so differently from one another at work?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are lots of reasons but research have shown a lot of it comes down to personality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the other factor is gender. It&amp;rsquo;s well know fact that men and women do lots of things in different ways, and workplace is no different.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Did you look at the effects of this variation on companies?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, I did. On the positive side, exposure to such diversity helps encourage creativity which is generally an asset on a company.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But unfortunately, individual differences are also the root of conflict between staff and they can lead to difficulties for management, which can sometimes be serious.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks Philip. So now I guess the two main things to remember here are to identify individual talent and then to utilize it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So Janice you were looking at identifying different talent in workers. Do you think this is easy for managers to do?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, currently teamwork is the fashion in the workplace an in my opinion the importance of the individual is generally neglected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What managers should be targeting is those employees who can take the lead in the situation, and are not afraid to accept the idea of responsibility.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Umm, that&amp;rsquo;s true Janice, but unfortunately many managers think the entire notion of encouraging individuality amongst the staff is far too hard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, that maybe true but I think one of the most important tasks of managers is to consider the needs of the individual on one hand and group co-operation and conformity on the other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s requires creative thinking on the part of management to avoid tension.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So Janice, what kind of people do you think companies should be looking for?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, it has to start from the very beginning when companies are looking for new employees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When a personal department is choosing between applicants they need to look for someone who&amp;rsquo;s broken the mould and can think for themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead, people make these decision often use a range of sychological tests to see if a person is a problem solver or will do as they&amp;rsquo;re told.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not convinced these qualities are actually the most important.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So do you think being a good team player is overrated?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No, it&amp;rsquo;s not overrated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You do need to learned the rules and learn fast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No individual can get around this if you&amp;rsquo;re working in an organisation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So how should managers deal with this?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rewards, when an individual demonstrates the behaviour the organisation expects, some kind of incentive can be given.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What important here is that this happens right at beginning so new recruit learn the rules of the system immediately.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also the incentive should be something the individual actually wants, and this isn&amp;rsquo;t always just money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To come back to you, Philip. you were saying that recognition of good performers is essential.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What else should managers be looking for?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, managing people means you not only have an understanding of employees, but you also recognise the culture of the organisation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In fact, for some organisations creativity and individuality may be the last thing they want to see during work hours. Very true.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, but managing people isn&amp;rsquo;t as easy as it looks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, change in the workplace can be quite tricky, especially there is a need to increase profit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And times like these managers may have to give priority to profit rather than individual staff needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, that creates difficult situations for people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, but what&amp;rsquo;s important is that managers are able to deal with quite high level of personal stress.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During times of change, they should be thinking not only about the strain on their staff but take time out to think of themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Absolutely, so what are the application of that for. . . .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 7.1.4</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.1.4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.1.4/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Good afternoon, every one. This is the first seminar in preparation for our archaeological fieldwork in Namibia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are fantastically luck to have received partial research funding for this trip from my Institute, so I shall expect 200% attention and participation from you all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First in this seminar, I&amp;rsquo;m going to give a brief introduction to contemporary research on rock art, and in the second part, I&amp;rsquo;m going to give you some do&amp;rsquo;s and don&amp;rsquo;ts for our fieldwork trip in April - so, please, listen very carefully.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m first going to focus on the interpretation of rock art on Namibia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are very fortunate to be going to an areas where you can find some of the most important sites in the entire world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I hope to show you how easy it is everyone to make mistakes in looking at cultures which are different from our own&amp;ndash; the first and most important lesson we have to learn.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Namibia, there both paintings and engravings, that&amp;rsquo;s where the surfaces of the rocks is cut out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many of the engraving show footprint of animals and most scholars used to think that the purpose of these was simple and obvious:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These rock art was like a school book with pictures to teach children about tracks: which tracks belonged to which animal -giraffe, lion and so on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But there were some mysteries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, when you look at a typical Namibia painting or engraving, you see the tracks are repeated, there are dozens of the tracks for the same animal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;d expect just one clear illustration of the reason - the aim - was to teach tracking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, there were two more problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why are some of engravings animals very accurate as you&amp;rsquo;d expect - all clearly you identifiable, and others quite unrealistic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And another mysteries, some of these unrealistic animals - that&amp;rsquo;s engravings- seem to be half human.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some, for example, have got human faces.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many researchers now think that these were pictures the wise men engraved of themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They believed they could use magic to control the animals they had drawn, so the hunters could then catch them for food.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These shows you some of dangers of coming from one culture to another, as we&amp;rsquo;ll be doing, without understanding it fully.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scholars imagined the children looked at rock art pictures to learn to track - just because they themselves had learnt skill from pictures;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many researchers now believe that rock art had a much more complex purpose.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And we&amp;rsquo;ll talk more about that next week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, before I invite you to join in a discussion in this second part of the seminar, I&amp;rsquo;d like to make some very important point about our fieldwork- and in fact any field trip to look at rock art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are going to a number of sites, and we won&amp;rsquo;t always be together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The single largest problem faced by people who manage the sites is- yes, I sure you&amp;rsquo;ve guessed - damage caused by visitors, even though it&amp;rsquo;s usually unintentional.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whenever you do go to a site, don&amp;rsquo;t forget you can learn many things from observing at a distance, instead of walking all over it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This can really help to reduce visitor pressure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People often say &amp;lsquo;well, there&amp;rsquo;s only two of us and just this one time&amp;rsquo;, but maybe thousands of people are saying the same things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then, some basic rules to guide you- we&amp;rsquo;ll have our own camp near a village, but remember never to camp on a site if you go on your own.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It maybe disrespectful to people of that culture, and certainly don&amp;rsquo;t make a fires, however romantic it may seem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s really dangerous in dry areas, and you can easily burn priceless undiscovered material by doing so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, how are we going to enjoy the rock art on our field trip?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By looking at it, drawing it and photographing it- never by touching it or even tracing it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rock art is fragile and precious.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Remember that climbing on rocks and in caves can destroy in a moment what has lasted for centuries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, no heroics in Namibia, please.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Try to be extra careful and help others to be too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And lastly, please don&amp;rsquo;t even move rocks or branches to take photographs -you should leave the site intact- I&amp;rsquo;m sure I can rely on you to do that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, that&amp;rsquo;s about all I want to say before today&amp;rsquo;s first discussion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But if you have any questions please ask now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And don&amp;rsquo;t forget you&amp;rsquo;ll find some fascinating information about world-wide sites on the Internet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, first question then?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 7.2.1</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.2.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.2.1/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Hello, motor insurance department. . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh hello. . . I&amp;rsquo;d like to ask about insurance for my car.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, of course, I&amp;rsquo;ll Just take a few details. What&amp;rsquo;s your name? Patrick Jones.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And your address? It&amp;rsquo;s 27 Bank Road. 27 Bank Road. Is that in Greendale? Yes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And what&amp;rsquo;s your daytime phone number?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My work Number is 730 453.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And could I ask what your occupation is? Dentist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK. . . Now a few details about your car. . . What&amp;rsquo;s size is the engine? It&amp;rsquo;s 1200cc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thank you. . . and the Make and model?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a Hewton Sable. Hewton Sable. Could you spell the model name please? Yes, S-A-B-L-E.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ah yes. . . thanks. And when was it made? 1997.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lovely. . . right. . . I presume you&amp;rsquo;ve had a previous insurer? Yes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, we need to know the name of the company.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes. . . it was Northern Star.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thank you, and have you made any insurance claims in last five years? Yes. . . one in 1999.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And what was the problem?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was stolen. . . but. . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s fine, Mr Jones. That&amp;rsquo;s all we need to know the moment. . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And will there be any other named drivers? Just one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And his name? Simon Payntor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Could spell the surname please? P-A-Y-N-T-E-R.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK thank you. . . And what relationship is he to you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He&amp;rsquo;s my brother-in-law.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And what will you or Mr Paynton be using the car for? Well. . . Mainly for social use. . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Social use. Will you be using it to travel to work? Yes. . . sometimes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Travel to work. Anything else? No, that&amp;rsquo;s it. .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And finally, when would you like to start the insurance?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll need it from the 31th of January.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right. . . Mr. Jones. . . I&amp;rsquo;m getting a couple of quotes coming up on the computer now, and the best bet looks like being with a company called Red Flag. Yeah.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that comes out at $450 per year. . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well. . . that seems OK. . . It&amp;rsquo;s quite a bit lower than I&amp;rsquo;ve been paying up to now. . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Great. . . so would you like me to go ahead with that? Sure, why not?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How would you like to pay?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 7.2.2</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.2.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.2.2/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Thank you for calling the Tourist Line.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are many different way of getting around the city and we&amp;rsquo;d like to suggest some you may not have thought of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How about city trip by boat?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There four main stoping points-from west to east:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stop A, Green Banks, stop B, City Bridge, stop C, Roman Landing and stop D Newtown.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can find the main booking office in stop A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first boat leaves at 8 a. m. and the last one at 6. 30 p. m.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are also many of attractions you can visit along the river.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At stop A, if you have time, you can visit the fine 16th century palace here build for the king with its beautiful formal gardens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s very near the booking office.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now you can enjoy every corner of this superb residence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stop B why don&amp;rsquo;t you visit the Tower Restaurant with its wide range of refreshments?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a place where you can sit and enjoy the wonderful views over the old commercial and banking centre of the city.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stop C, It&amp;rsquo;s the area where, in the first century AD, invading soldiers crossed the river; This is much shallower than it is now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s why this area is called Roman Landing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is an interactive Museum to visit here with a large shop which has a good range of local history books.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the furthest point of the trip, stop D, the most exciting place to visit is the new entertainment complex with seven-screen cinema, bowling alley and video games arcade.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Beside the boat tours, there city buses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two companies offer special services: The Top Bus Company runs all it&amp;rsquo;s tours with a live commentary of English.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tours leave from 8. 30a. m. every 20 minutes, there are departures from Central Station, Castle Hill and Long Walk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a hop-on hop-off service and tickets are valid for 24hours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For further details call Top Bus on 0208 944 7810.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Number One Sightseeing Tour is available with commentary in eight languages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Buses depart from Central station every five to six minutes from about 9 a. m. with the last bus at around 7 p. m.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There also Number One services with an English-speaking guide. . .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 7.2.3</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.2.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.2.3/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 3 We are pleased to welcome Dr. Martin Merrywhether of the Antarctic centre in Christchurch, New Zealand who has come along to talk to us today about the role of the centre and the Antarctic treaty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now my first question, is about the choice of location for the centre.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why Christchurch, was it because of the climate?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well actually New Zealand is the second closest country to Antarctica and Christchurch often used on Antarctic expeditions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, so it&amp;rsquo;s because of where we are. . . coupled with our historical role.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, Tell us, what is the main purpose of the centre?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well. . . we have two complementary roles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One is as a scientific base for expeditions and research and the other is for information centre.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tell us something about the roles as a scientific base?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re able to provide information bout what scientist should take with them to the South Pole - for example, the centre contains a clothing warehouse where expeditions are supplied with suitable clothing for the extreme conditions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I suppose you need a bit more than your normal winter coat!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, exactly. And then there&amp;rsquo;s also the specialist of library and mapping services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, and which countries are actually located at the centre?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well. . . the centre houses research programmes for New Zealand, for the United States as well as Italy. . . there&amp;rsquo;s even a US post office at the American airforce base here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Really? And what does the Visitor&amp;rsquo;s centre offer?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well since very few people will ever experience the Antarctic first hand, the visitor&amp;rsquo;s centre aims to recreate the atmosphere of Antarctic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s a mock camp site where you can see inside an Antarctic tent and imagine yourself sleeping there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the centre also acts as a showcase for the unique international co-operation which exists in Antarctic today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is it actually likely the South Pole?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know you&amp;rsquo;ve been there on a number of occasions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, I have and each time I&amp;rsquo;m struck by the awesome beauty of the place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s magnificent but you can really only the visit it in the summer months.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>October to March.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, because it&amp;rsquo;s completely dark for four months of the year. . . and in addition it has to be the coldest place on earth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Colder than the North pole, why&amp;rsquo;s that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, unlike the North Pole which is actually a frozen sea, Antarctica is a land mass shaped like a dome, with a result that the winds blow down the slopes at speeds of up to 150 kilometers an hour and that&amp;rsquo;s what makes it so cold.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And one other interesting thing is that Antarctica is the driest continent on earth, surprisingly, and so you have to drink large amounts of water when you&amp;rsquo;re there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How old does the Antarctica?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re pretty sure it was part of a large land mass but it broke away from a rest continent 170 million years ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How can you be certain of this?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because fossils and rocks have been discovered in Antarctic which are the same as those found in places such as Africa and Australia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amazing. . . to think that it was once attached to Africa. . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, let&amp;rsquo;s just have a look at the Antarctic Treaty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How far back does the idea of an international treaty go?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well as far back as the 19th century, when eleven nations organised an international event.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When was that actually?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 1870. And it was called the Polar Research Meeting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then, not long after that, they organised something called the First International Polar Year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that took place when exactly?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over two year from 1882 to 1883.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until the 1950s that the idea of an international treaty was proposed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And in 1959 the Treaty was actually signed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What do you see as the main achievement of the treaty?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, firstly it means that the continent is reserved for peaceful use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s Article one, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? Yes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s important since the territory belongs to everyone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, but not as important as Article five, which prohibits any nuclear explosions or waste disposal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which is marvellous.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, I&amp;rsquo;m afraid we&amp;rsquo;re going to have to stop there because I&amp;rsquo;m afraid we&amp;rsquo;ve run out of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks for coming along today and telling us all about the center and its work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 7.2.4</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.2.4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.2.4/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 4 My topic is handedness- whether in different sports it is better to be left - or right-sided or whether a more balanced approach is more successful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m left-handed myself and I actually didn&amp;rsquo;t see any relevance to my own life when I happened to start reading an article by a sports psychologist called Peter Matthews.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He spent the first part of the article talking about handedness in music instead of sports, which I have to say almost put me off from reading further.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But what I soon became struck by was the sheer volume of both observation and investigation he had done in many different sports and I felt persuaded that what he had to say would be of real interest.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think Matthews&amp;rsquo; finding would beneficial, not so much in helping sports people to work on their weaker side.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But more that they can help them identify the most suitable strategies to use in a given game.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although most trainers know how important handedness is, at present they are rather reluctant to make use of the insights scientist like Matthews can give, which I think is rather short-sighted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because focusing on individual flexibility is only part of the story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway, back to the article, Matthews found a Germans study which looked at what he called &amp;lsquo;Mixed-handedness&amp;rsquo;, that is, the capacity to use both left and right hands equally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s looked at a mixed-handedness in 40 musicians on a variety of instruments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Researchers examined a number of variables, for example, type of instrument played, regularity of practice undertaken and length of time playing instrument. . . and found the following: keyboard players had high levels of mixed-handedness, where string players like cellists and violinists strongly favoured one hand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, those who started younger were more a mixed-handed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Matthews also reports studies of handedness in apes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apes get a large proportion of their food by &amp;lsquo;fishing&amp;rsquo; ants from ant hills.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These studies show that apes, like humans, show handedness - though for them right- and left-handedness is about equal, whereas about 85% of humans are right handed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Studies showed that apes consistently using the same hand fished out 30% more ants than those varying between the two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Matthews started researching several different sports and found different types of handedness in each.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By the way, he uses &amp;lsquo;handedness&amp;rsquo; to refer to the dominant side for feet and eyes as well as hands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway, his team measured the hand, feet and eyes of 2, 611 players and found that there are really three main types of laterality:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mixed - you work equally well on both sides - both hand and eye; single - you tend to favour one side but both hand and eye favour the same side; and cross-laterality a player&amp;rsquo;s hands and eyes favour only one side but they are opposite sides.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with hockey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Matthews found that it was best to be mixed-handed - this is because a hockey stick must be deployed in two directions - it would be a drawback to have hand and eye favour in one side.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An interesting finding is that mixed-handed players with significantly more confident than their single-handed counterparts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Things are slightly different in racket sports like tennis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here the important thing is to have the dominant hand and eye on the one side.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This means that there is a bigger area of vision on the side where most of the action occurs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If a player is a cross lateral the racket is invisible from the dominant eye for much of the swing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It means that they can only make corrections much later. . . and often the damage has been done by them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And moving to a rather different type sport which involves large but precise movements - gymnastics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been found that cross hand-eye favouring is best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The predominant reason for this is because it aids balance - which is of course absolutely central to performance in this sports.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 7.3.1</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.3.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.3.1/</guid><description>
&lt;p>section 1 Good morning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, good morning. Is this. . . er. . . room number 26? Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So is this the Student Job Centre? It certainly is. How can I help you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, actually I&amp;rsquo;m Looking for a job - a part-time job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do you have anything available at the moment?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ah. . . yes. . . Are you a registered student?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m afraid this service is only available to full-time students.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes. . . I am. I&amp;rsquo;m doing a degree in Business Studies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is my student card.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which year are you in?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well. . . I&amp;rsquo;ve been at uni for four years, but I&amp;rsquo;m in the Third Years because I took last year off.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, well. let&amp;rsquo;s just have a look at what positions are available at the moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ah, there&amp;rsquo;s a job working at the reception desk at the Sports Center, for three evening a week- that&amp;rsquo;s Wednesdays, Thursdays and Fridays.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>En. . . that&amp;rsquo;s sounds like fun but unfortunately I have evening lectures - so that&amp;rsquo;s not possible, I&amp;rsquo;m afraid.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is there anything during the day?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, that&amp;rsquo;s no good then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Um, what about cleaning?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s a position for a cleaner at the Child Care Centre. Right. . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But you&amp;rsquo;d need to be there at 6 am. Does that appeal?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Six o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning! Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s far to early for me, I&amp;rsquo;m afraid.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d never make it that early in the morning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mmm. . . well, there was a position going in a Computer Lab. for three days a week might be OK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ah, here it is. No, it&amp;rsquo;s in the Library, not the Lab. , Clerical assistant required I think mostly involves putting the books back on shelves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh no, hang on. It&amp;rsquo;s for Wednesday and friday evening again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No, I can&amp;rsquo;t manage that because of the lectures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ok, I&amp;rsquo;m getting the idea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Look, I just get a few details from you anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then we can check through the list and see what comes up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ll fill in the personal detail on this application from first, if that&amp;rsquo;s OK?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s fine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, what&amp;rsquo;s your name again?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anita Newman - that&amp;rsquo;s N-E-W-M-A-N.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And your address, Anita?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m in one of the Halls of Residence for post-graduate students, you know, International House.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, that&amp;rsquo;s easy. What&amp;rsquo;s your room number there?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rom B569, - no, sorry, B659. I always get that wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I haven&amp;rsquo;t been living there very long.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do you have any other skills? typing, languages, that sort of thing?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, I speak some Japanese.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, I&amp;rsquo;ll make a note that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now - let&amp;rsquo;s see what else is available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What do you think of administrative work? There&amp;rsquo;s a position for- an office assistant at the English Language Centre.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Um, that sounds interesting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s for three days a week - Monday, friday and saturday mornings, interested?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mmm. I was hoping to have saturdays free.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I need the work so. . . can you tell me the job involves?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, sure. It says here that you will be required to deal with student enquires and answer the phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m sure I can handle all that without a problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Great. Well, would you like me to a arrange an interview for you? say, Friday morning, around ten?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Could we make it a bit later? unfortunately I have got something to do at ten.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Would that be OK?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not a problem. How about eleven thirty?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hope works out for you Anita.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Me too, And thanks for all your help.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 7.3.2</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.3.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.3.2/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 2 Good morning, I&amp;rsquo;m very pleased to be invented along to your club talk about our Charity Sponsored Walking Holiday for Education Aid.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll start by giving you a brief overview of what it entails.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First of all let me explain what we mean by &amp;lsquo;sponsored&amp;rsquo; here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is where people promise to donate money to the charity if you achieve your goal, in this case to walk a certain number of miles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically, we are organizing a ten-day holiday, from the sixth to the sixteenth of November, with eight days actual walking trekking in this Semira Mountains.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at some of the details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ll require you to raise sponsorship money of at least $3, 200, pay $250 of it up front as deposit, and the rest in stages through out the year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Out of this about 35% will go on your expenses, and that leaves 65% guaranteed to go to the charity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which brings me the the most important part.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This trek is being specifically organized to help education in the Semira region.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last year we helped train teachers for the disabled, and this year we&amp;rsquo;re focusing on the pupils.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each of the walkers&amp;rsquo; sponsorship money will go to help an individual special needs pupil in one of the mountain schools.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the second part of the talk I&amp;rsquo;ll give your a lot more details, but back the basic information, Age limits.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the second time we have run this kind of Holiday, and um, on the first we even had an eighty-year-old, but we found it was wise to establish limit this time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You have to be at least eighteen and the top limit is now seventy, though you need to obtain a health certificate from your doctor if you are over sixty years old.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, the Semira Mountains are among the highest on the world but you mustn&amp;rsquo;t be too daunted, we will mainly be trekking in foothill only, although there will be spectacular views even in the foothills.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, you will need be extremely fit if you aren&amp;rsquo;t now and you are interested in coming with us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You have plenty of time to get into shape.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You will be sleeping in tents so you must have quite a bit equipment with you but you will be helped by local assistants.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your bedding and so forth will be carried by them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We ask that you only walk with small rucksack with needs for the day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve really said enough about the marvellous area you will be walking in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at some of the sights you will be seeing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apart from this spectacular snow-covered peaks and valleys, there are marvellous historic villages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The area have been famous centuries for making beautiful carpets, although recently there has been a trend to move into weaving blanket and wood carving.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The people are extremely friendly and welcoming.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We deliberately keep the parties smaller in size to minimize disruption to people and landscape.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope that there are still some people interested.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll be distributing leaflets at the end where you can find out more information, but just for the moment I&amp;rsquo;ll outline the itinerary, the main hight points of the holiday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obviously, you will start by flying out to Kishba, the capital city, on Day One.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a couple of days you acclimatize yourself, you&amp;rsquo;ll start the trek on Day Three, walking through the enormous Katiba forest which will take the whole of the day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Day Four takes us higher up, going through the foothill past a number of villages and visiting a school for the disabled in Sohan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then you have a rest day, that&amp;rsquo;s Day Five, before going to the spectacular Kumi Temple with twelfth-century carvings set in a small forest by lake and that&amp;rsquo;s Day Six, the highlight for many.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We stay near there for Day Seven because then comes the hardest day, walking through very mountainous country, but culminating in a swim in the Parteh Falls.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the highest waterfall in this region.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Day Nine is much easier, with part of the day spent in the village where they make some gorgeous red blankets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then back down to Kishba and the journey home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, you can see it&amp;rsquo;s pretty packed timetable. . .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 7.3.3</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.3.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.3.3/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 3 Thanks to all of you for coming along today to hear about how the robotic float project is helping with ocean research.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, first of all we&amp;rsquo;ll look at what a robotic float does and its use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So let&amp;rsquo;s start with the device itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It looks a bit like a cigar and it&amp;rsquo;s about one and a half meters long.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More importantly it&amp;rsquo;s full of the equipment that&amp;rsquo;s designed to collect data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, it can help us in building a profile of different factors which work together within the world&amp;rsquo;s oceans.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sounds like a big project. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it too big for one country to undertake?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s quite true but this project is a really good example of international co-operation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the last five year scientists from thirteen countries have been taking part in the project and launching floats in their area of ocean control.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And next year this number will rise to fourteen when Indonesia joins the project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s impressive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But let&amp;rsquo;s move onto how floats work, the operational circle goes like this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each of the floats is dropped in the ocean from a boat at a set point and activated from a satellite.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then the float immediately sinks about 2, 000 meters. . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s two whole kilometers down in the water.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It stays at this depth for about ten days and is carried around by the currents which operate in the ocean at this level.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During this time it&amp;rsquo;s possible for it to cover quite large distances but the average is fifty kilometers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, what is it actually recording?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, at this stage nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But as it rises to the surface it collects all sort of data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most importantly, variations in salinity, that&amp;rsquo;s salt levels, and changes in temperature, a bit like underwater weather balloons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then when it gets back to the surface all the data it&amp;rsquo;s collected is beamed up to the satellite.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After about five hours on the surface the float automatically sinks, beginning the whole process again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What happens to the data?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well the information is transferred direct to onshore meteorological stations. . . like our in Hobart. . . and within four hours the finding can be on computers and them can be mapped and analysed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You say you&amp;rsquo;re building models of the world&amp;rsquo;s ocean systems but how&amp;rsquo;re they going to be used, and more importantly, when?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some of the data has already helped in completing projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, our understanding of the underlying causes of Ei Niro events is being confirmed by float data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another way we are using float data is to help us to understand the mechanics of climate change, like global warming and ozone depletion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a part of an ongoing variability study but the results still a long way off.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, this is not the case with our ocean weather forecasting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because we know from the float what the prevailing weather conditions will be in certain parts of the ocean, we can advise the Navy on search and rescue missions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s happening right now and many yachtsmen own their lives to the success of this project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition, that float data can help us to look at the biological implications of the ocean process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Would that help with preserving fishing stocks?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, and advising the government on fisheries legislation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re well on the way to completing a project on this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We hope it will help to bring about more sustainable fishing practise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We will be seeing the results of that quite soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It sounds like the data from floats has lots of applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, it does. It&amp;rsquo;s also a powerful agricultural tool.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we were aware of the weather would like, say, next next year, we could make sure that the famers planted appropriate grain varieties to produced the best yield from the available rainfall.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That sounds a bit like science fiction especially when now we can&amp;rsquo;t even tell them when a drought will break.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I agree that this concept still a long way in the future but it will come eventually and the float data will have made a contribution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 7.3.4</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.3.4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.3.4/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 4 Good morning every.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today&amp;rsquo;s lecture forms part of the Hospitality and Tourism module.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last week I look at the economy end of the hotel business; this week I&amp;rsquo;m going to discuss the luxury end of the market.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s consider the following scenario. . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You wake up in the middle of the night in a strange hotel miles away from home disoriented most probably from jet lag, when even the most expensive surrounding can seem empty and dispiriting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You have paid a great deal of money to stay in this first-class hotel with its contemporary technology, but according to recent research carried out by the international travel and public relations company, all is not well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The research suggests that even the most opulent, luxurious hotel seems to have underestimated the most basic needs of their customers - be they travelling for work or pleasure: the need to feel at home in surroundings which are both familiar and inviting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do this finding however, apply only to hotels situated in particular areas?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is it possible that external environment can effect a guests well-bing?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The company&amp;rsquo;s research covered the whole range of different hotels types both independent hotels and those which are part of large chains.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They investigated chic so-called boutique hotels in the heart of downtown business districts, stately mansions located the depth beautiful countryside, and plush hotels build at the edge of tropical beaches surround by palm trees and idyllic blue ocean.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the research concluded. That what was outside the hotel building simply didn&amp;rsquo;t matter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a fascinating revelation and those of your hoping to move into careers in the travel and leisure industry would be well advised to look at the findings in more detail.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But back to the main point of this lecture. . . the need to feel at home, what can the hotel industry do about it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And is the very idea so subjective that it&amp;rsquo;s possible to do anything about it on the global basis?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, nothing stands still in this world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One company has come up with the slogan &amp;lsquo;Take Your Home With You&amp;rsquo;, and aims to provide clients with luxury serviced apartments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those in the business travel industry maintain that these serviced apartment dispense with all the unwanted and expensive hotel services that business travelers don&amp;rsquo;t want, while maximising the facilities they do want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, not only sleeping and living accommodation, But also a sleek modern kitchen. that allows guests to cook and entertain if they wish, at no additional cost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The attraction of such facilities are obvious, and it&amp;rsquo;ll be interesting to see whether the company manages to establish a trend all over the world to make a lasting impact on the luxury accommodation market.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, finally I want to consider the psychology underpinning the traditional holiday hotel industry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a hotelier, how do you go bout attracting people to give up a security of their own home and entrust themselves staying in a completely strange place and sleeping in a unfamiliar bed?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Firstly, hotels exploit people&amp;rsquo;s need to escape the predictability of their everyday lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a few days people can pretend they are free of responsibilities and can indulge themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Secondly, there is something very powerful in our need to be pampered and looked after, It&amp;rsquo;s almost as if we return to being a baby, when everything was done for us and we felt safe and secure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And not far removed from this is the pleasure in being spoilt and given little treats- like the miniscule bottles of shampoo and tiny bars of soap, the chocolate on your pillow on night - and we actually forget that we are paying for it all!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next week, I&amp;rsquo;m going to look at eco-hotel, a fairly new phenomenon but increasingly popular. . .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 7.4.1</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.4.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.4.1/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 1 Yes, what can I do for you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My friend is in homestay. . . and she really enjoys it. . . so I&amp;rsquo;d like to join a family as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Okay, so let me get some details. What&amp;rsquo;s your name?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My name is Keiko Yunchini.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Could you spell your family name for me? It&amp;rsquo;s. . . Yuichini, that&amp;rsquo;s Y-U-I-C-H-I-N-I.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And your first name? It&amp;rsquo;s Keiko, K-E-I-K-O.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s Keiko Yuichini. . . Okay. . . and you&amp;rsquo;re female. and your nationality? I&amp;rsquo;m Japanese.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, and could I see your passport, please? Here it is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Okay. . . your passport number is JO6337. . . and you are how old?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m twenty-eight years old.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now you are living one of the colleges. . . which one?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Willow College, umm. . . Room 21C.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right, 21C Willow College, and how long are you planing on staying with homestay?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>About four month. . . long if I like it. . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And what course are you enrolled in?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve enrolled for twenty weeks in the. . Umm. . . Advanced English Studies because I need help with my writing. . . and I&amp;rsquo;m nearly at the end of my first five-week course.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, do you have any preference for a family with children or without children?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I prefer. . . I mean I like young children, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to be with older people. . . you know. . . adults. . . someone around my age.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ok, and what about pets?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m a veterinarian so that&amp;rsquo;s fine. . . the more the better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All right, now what about you? Are you a vegetarian or do you have special food requirements?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, I&amp;rsquo;m not a vegetarian. . . but I don&amp;rsquo;t eat a lot of meat. . . I really like seafood.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And what are your hobbies?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like reading and going to the movies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do you play any sports?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, I joined the handball team, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t like that. . . so I stopped playing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now I play tennis on the weekend with my friends. . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All right. Let&amp;rsquo;s see, name, age, now the location. Are you familiar with the public transport system?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No I&amp;rsquo;m not really because I have been living on campus. . . I&amp;rsquo;ve been to the city in few times on the bus, but they are always late.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s about the trains?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like catching the train. . . they are much faster.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, let me go check on the computer and see who I&amp;rsquo;ve got. . . Listen, leave it with me. . . I&amp;rsquo;ll check my records and I&amp;rsquo;ll give you details this afternoon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thank you for helping me. . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a pleasure. Bye. Bye.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 7.4.2</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.4.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.4.2/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 2 Welcome to all of you. . . Can everybody see and hear me?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good, I&amp;rsquo;m Sally, your guide for the tour of the Bicentennial Park. . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope that you&amp;rsquo;re all wearing in your most comfortable shoes and that you can keep up the pace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, let&amp;rsquo;s get under way on our tour around this wonderful park.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll start today with some general background information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There used to be a lot of factories in this area until the 1960s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Creating the park required the demolition of lots of derelict buildings on the site, so most of the exciting park space all around you was originally warehouses and storehouses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The idea of building a public park here was first discussed when a property developer proposed a high-rise housing development, but the local community wasn&amp;rsquo;t happy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If the land was cleaned up, they want to use the site for recreation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Resident wanted open space for outdoor activities, rather the housing and even an indoor sports complex.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, to the Bicentennial Park itself, It has two areas, a natural reserve and a formal park with man-made features and gardens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The tall blue-and-white building in front of us is called The Tower and is the centre point for the formal gardens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It stands twelve meters high, so follow me the upstairs to where we can take advantage of the fantastic views.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, here we are at the top of The Tower, and we&amp;rsquo;re going on to look at the view from each direction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Out to the east, the large building about a kilometer away are on the Olympic site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is an indoor arena for Gymnastics, a stadium for track and field and a swimming pool for races and synchronised swimming, and also diving.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you look carefully down there you can see the train lines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Olympic site has it&amp;rsquo;s own station to encourage the use of public transport.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s also have a car park, but it only holds a limited number of cars.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The formal park has some specially-created water features.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you look out here to the south, you can see a circular ornamental Pond.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And around to the west, you can relax and seat on the bench to smell the flowers in the Rose Garden, and finally up to the north, if you look in front of you now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is the lake with a small island in the center, you can hire rowing boats from the boat shed, which you can&amp;rsquo;t see from here, but if you look through the trees, you can see the cafe which has lovely views across the water.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, let&amp;rsquo;s climb down now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ll go now and have a look at the nature reserve section of the park, which has opened up natural wetland to the public.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Mangroves have been made more accessible to visitors by the boardwalk build during the park&amp;rsquo;s upgrade.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;d think that people would come here to look at the unusual plant life of the area, but in fact it&amp;rsquo;s more often used for cycling and is very popular with the local clubs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the far end of the park and over there you can see the Frog Pond, a natural feature here long before the park was designed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just next to it we have our outdoor classroom, a favourite spot for school parties.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The area is now most often used by primary schools for Biology lessons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And finally let&amp;rsquo;s pass by the Waterbird Refuge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This area is in a sheltered part of the estuary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s why the park&amp;rsquo;s viewing shelter is a favourite spot for bird watchers who can use it to spy through binoculars.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can watch a variety of water birds, but most visitors expect to see black swans when they come to the shelter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You might spot one yourself right now!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, here we are back at our starting point, the visitors center.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 7.4.3</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.4.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.4.3/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 3 Remind me, Trevor&amp;hellip; how long is the presentation?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dr White said three per hour.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So about twenty minutes?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;ll be fifteen minutes per presentation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And five minutes for questions?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And is this one going be assessed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No&amp;hellip; not this time around, because it&amp;rsquo;s first one, you know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good news.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, Trevor, what are we going to include?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, Do you think we ought to give some historical background?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, no&amp;hellip; definitely not&amp;hellip; we won&amp;rsquo;t have time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, but I think we ought to say something about Geographical location&amp;hellip; because not of the people know where the island are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes&amp;hellip; Ok&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ll take notes, shall I?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yeah&amp;hellip; that will be a help&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So Geographical&amp;hellip; location&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then we ought to give an overview of the whole education system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t we say something about the economy? you know agriculture produce&amp;hellip; minerals and so forth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well&amp;hellip; Dr White said that we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t go into that sort of detail.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But it&amp;rsquo;s pretty important when you think about it&amp;hellip; you know, because it does influence the education system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Look&amp;hellip; let&amp;rsquo;s think about that one later shall we&amp;hellip; let&amp;rsquo;s see how we are doing for time&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK&amp;hellip; so&amp;hellip; . general overview of education Of course&amp;hellip; And then the role of English Language?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nope, that goes in the Language Policy Seminar, don&amp;rsquo;t you remember?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Are you sure? Positive!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All right&amp;hellip; so those are the topics we&amp;rsquo;re going to be&amp;hellip; to be covering&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We need to think about what to prepare&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dr. White said he wanted us to use plenty of visuals and things and we might as well try them out when we are not being assessed&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well the most important thing is the overhead project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No problem. . . we&amp;rsquo;ll get them from the media room. . . must remember to book it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well&amp;hellip; we&amp;rsquo;ll need a map of course.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Probably two&amp;hellip; . One of the islands&amp;hellip; large scale&amp;hellip; .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And one of the West Africa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, the West Africa one is no problem. . . there&amp;rsquo;s one in the resource room.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh yeah, of course, the resources room; The islands are going to be more of problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tell you what&amp;hellip; there is a very clear map of Santiago in that tourist brochure I showed you last week. Don&amp;rsquo;t you remember it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh yeah&amp;hellip; that&amp;rsquo;s right. We can just use the tourist brochure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also need statistics&amp;hellip; on several different things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Literacy rates.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, and school places.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How about the encyclopaedia?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nah&amp;hellip; not up-to-date enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mmm. . . Why don&amp;rsquo;t we call the embassy?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh&amp;hellip; someone&amp;rsquo;s enthusiastic!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well&amp;hellip; if something&amp;rsquo;s worth doing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know it&amp;rsquo;s worth doing well&amp;hellip; Ok.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We can find out statistics on school places from them as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Umm, might as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Look Julie, it&amp;rsquo;s almost time for our tutorials&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We can meet again on Monday. but we need to prepare some stuff before then&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 7.4.4</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.4.4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/l7.4.4/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Section 4 In today&amp;rsquo;s lecture, I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about Monosodium Glutamate, or MSG, as it&amp;rsquo;s more commonly now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now MSG as you probably know, a flavour enhancer which is used particularly in Chinese and Japanese cooking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, I&amp;rsquo;m going to explore why it&amp;rsquo;s so popular in these cuisines and, more importantly, how does it enhance the flavour of food.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main reason why MSG is more commonly used in Japanese meals is tradition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For many thousands of years the Japanese has incorporated a type of seaweed Know as kombu in their cooking, as they discovered it had the ability to make food taste better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until 1908 that the ingredient in kombu which was responsible for the improvement for flavour was actually discovered to be glutamate by scientists working there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From 1908 until 1956, glutamate was produced commercially in Japan by a very slow and expensive means of extraction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was in 1956, that the speed of the process was improved, and industrial production increase dramatically and still continues to increase to this day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In fact, hundreds of thousands tonnes MSG are produced all over the world today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what exactly is MSSG?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, Monosodium Glutamate contains seventy-eight point two per cent (78. 2%) glutamate twelve point two per cent (12. 2%) sodium and nine point six per cent (9. 6%) water.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Glutamate is an amino acid that can be found naturally in all protein-containing foods.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So that includes food such as meat and cheese.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is widely known that Chinese and Japanese food contains the MSG but many people don&amp;rsquo;t seems to be aware that it also used in food in other parts of the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, It&amp;rsquo;s found in commercially made Italian pizzas, in American fast food and in Britain MSG is used in things like potato crisps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So how exactly does MSG work?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, in the western world, we commonly talk of four &amp;rsquo;tastes&amp;rsquo;, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure you&amp;rsquo;re all familiar with the concepts of sweet, sour, bitter and salt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, in 1908, Kikunae Ikeda identify a fifth &amp;rsquo;taste&amp;rsquo;. and it is thought that MSG intensifies this naturally occurring &amp;rsquo;taste&amp;rsquo; in some food.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It does make perfect evolutionary sense that we should have the ability to detect or taste glutamate because it is the minor acid which is the most common in natural foods.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John Prescott, an associate professor at the University of Chicago, suggest that this &amp;lsquo;fifth taste&amp;rsquo; services a purpose just as the others tastes do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He suggest that it signal to us to presence of protein in food in the same way the sweetness indicates that food contains energy-giving carbohydrates.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bitterness, he said, alerts us to toxins in the food while sourness warns us of spoilage and saltiness signals the presence of some minerals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what else do we know about this fifth taste. . .&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>