<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notebook – IELTS Essays</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/docs/ielts/writing/ielts-mentor/</link><description>Recent content in IELTS Essays on Notebook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://note.codiy.net/docs/ielts/writing/ielts-mentor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: 1219 - Music for bringing people of different cultures and ages together</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/writing/ielts-mentor/task2/1219/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/writing/ielts-mentor/task2/1219/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Some people say that music is a good way of bringing people of different cultures and ages together.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>To what extent do you agree or disagree with this opinion?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="model-answer-1-agreement">Model Answer 1: [Agreement]&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Music plays a crucial role in our lives and eliminates differences among various cultures and generations. It symbolises harmony and reflects humanity. So, I agree with the notion that music helps bring people from various cultures and generations together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the reasons music excretes the barriers among different nations and cultures is that people enjoy music from every part of the world, and it speaks the same language, which embodies human emotion, joy, love and sorrow. Music does not need interpretation to be enjoyed and understood as it touches our hearts and resonates in our minds. No matter what language we speak or understand, we appreciate the melody and depth of music which is why people of all ages can sit together and enjoy the same music. For instance, some viral music in foreign languages in our country signifies how it speaks our minds and hearts rather than just a human language.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreover, nations influence each other with the type of music they produce and the type of musical instruments they use. This amalgamation reduces cultural differences and brings people from different cultures and ages to a common platform. To cite an example, many music genres, that we enjoy these days, were derived from multiple nations and cultures and people from all these cultures enjoy and love them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, music is an art form which is enjoyed by all, and this helps reduce the generation and age gaps among people. To illustrate, when the national anthem is played, children, adults and elders all tune to the same emotion, which is patriotism, and their unity is stronger than ever. The same can be said when music evokes other emotions like love, sadness and so on. Besides, some music categories are loved by all, and the listeners feel a sense of togetherness in a divine way which is almost absent in other art forms. It not only eliminates age gaps but also the generation and cultural gaps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In conclusion, music, as a universally accepted and supreme art form, enriches our lives and strengthens the connections between us, regardless of our backgrounds, culture and age.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="model-answer-2-disagreement">Model Answer 2: [Disagreement]&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Music can stimulate our minds and bodies and also offer some temporary relief from mental agony and sadness. Music probably can do many other things, but it can not bring people of different cultures and ages together. And this essay will explain why we can not rely on music to accomplish such a difficult task.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Music has some elements and qualities to bring some like-minded people within, not outside of a certain culture, country or nation closer together in a common bond because the tone and tune of that music sound so familiar to them. Many music lovers even suggest that music is the food for our soul, regardless of our ages. True that may be, but when we are pinning our hopes on music to unite people of different cultures and ages, we are becoming too much optimistic, to say the least, because culture is a very difficult subject to understand and so is “human nature”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Culture is not only about what we like to listen to, or what we do not for some temporary pleasure or gratification. Rather, culture, among other things, very predominantly is also about “how we are so dissimilar to each other”, and it is essentially this “wish” or “sentiment” that helps us cling to our own ways of life, no matter how “peculiar” or “weird” that may look to other cultures. It is because of this strong “sentiment” that even though, almost all the countries in the continent of South America essentially speak the same language or practice the same religion, they are not merged into only one country. The same applies to different ages as well, and that is why we see, more often than not, that while a young guy likes some heavy rock or heavy metal music, an older person likes a more traditional or classic type of music.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, from the discussion above, it should be fairly clear to us that music is important for our life, but it is not a good way to bring people of different cultures or ages together.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.ielts-mentor.com/writing-sample/writing-task-2/3530-music-for-bringing-people-of-different-cultures-and-ages-together">https://www.ielts-mentor.com/writing-sample/writing-task-2/3530-music-for-bringing-people-of-different-cultures-and-ages-together&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 1222 - Negative impacts of children playing computer games</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/writing/ielts-mentor/task2/1222/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/writing/ielts-mentor/task2/1222/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Nowadays many people have access to computers on a wide basis and a large number of children play computer games.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What are the negative impacts of children playing computer games and what can be done to minimize the bad effects?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="model-answer">Model Answer:&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>People use computers more extensively these days than ever before, and it is so widespread in our modern world that even children have access to these devices for playing games. This essay discusses the disadvantages of playing digital games on computer devices by youngsters and suggests some measures to reduce its negative effects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Concerning the adverse impacts of young children playing video games, the most devastating one is the addiction these games create. Millions of dollars are spent to make computer games so that they attract a large number of audiences and keep them glued to the computer screens. So they are addictive by design. And this obsession hampers children&amp;rsquo;s outdoor activities, studies and even time to socialise and learn important life skills. To illustrate, many research works suggest that children who spend many hours playing computer games each day end up performing poorly in schools and avoid social events and outdoor activities. It results in physical and psychological issues including poor eyesight and despair. Moreover, violent games cloud the youngsters&amp;rsquo; judgement and make their rational thinking unstable. Oftentimes, youngsters who play violent games develop violent behaviours. To cite an example, an unfortunate shooting event that claimed many innocent lives took place in an American school a few years ago was carried out by a teenager who was addicted to shooting games.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To minimise the severity of these negative impacts, parents must monitor what their children are doing, especially on computers. They should not be allowed to play computer games for more than a couple of hours each week, and parents can actively participate in those games with their children so that it becomes family time. An ideal example of it could be my aunt and uncle who play video games with their children, and as a result, children are also interested in doing outdoor activities with them. Finally, parents can use parental control over the digital content and games their children watch or play. These measures would deter children from downloading and playing games that are not suitable for their age.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To conclude, computer games, when played excessively by children, have many detrimental effects. Proper parenting and monitoring seem like the best solution to solve these problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.ielts-mentor.com/writing-sample/writing-task-2/3533-negative-impacts-of-children-playing-computer-games">https://www.ielts-mentor.com/writing-sample/writing-task-2/3533-negative-impacts-of-children-playing-computer-games&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: 1233 - Keeping pets is good for children</title><link>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/writing/ielts-mentor/task2/1233/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://note.codiy.net/ielts/writing/ielts-mentor/task2/1233/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Some people think that keeping pets is good for children while others think it is dangerous and unhealthy for them.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Which viewpoint do you agree with?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h4 id="model-answer-1-view-keeping-pets-is-good-for-children">Model Answer 1: [View: Keeping pets is good for children]&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Some individuals support keeping pets around young children as they think it is beneficial while others oppose the idea citing pet-related injuries and fatalities in recent times. In this essay, I shall argue that dangers that stem from young children having pets are overemphasised, sometimes even exaggerated, and children receive substantive psychological benefits from having pets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To commence with, most parents allow common and friendly pets like cats, dogs and birds as their children&amp;rsquo;s companions and the number of strange pets like snakes, spiders, apes, etc. are very rare. Such unfamiliar pets, which are a bit wild in nature, have been reported to hurt some children. However, such incidents are so rare that they are negligible because the overwhelming majority of children have non-lethal pets like cats, dogs, fish, rodents and rabbits. For instance, recent statistical data reveals that 93% of children own non-lethal and friendly pets that have almost zero per cent chance of harming or hurting children. So, I believe that pets are not a physical danger to children.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To shed some light on the positivity of letting children have pets, I can think of many. However, the most important of them is the favourable effects it has on children&amp;rsquo;s psychology and growth. Young pet owners frequently empathise with their pets and perform a diverse range of activities to maintain their well-being. The Cambridge Developmental Psychology Unit found that children who had grown up with pets were 30% less likely to bully others and show aggression. Pets are also conducive to young children&amp;rsquo;s mental growth, and they get involved in interesting activities with their pets that help them realise empathy more deeply. So it is undeniable that a child’s prosociality and mental health can be improved through exposure to pets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In conclusion, letting young children possess and interact with friendly pets has important benefits. It is not a threat to children, but rather beneficial to nurture some important good qualities in them. So, it is expected that parents who wish to have pets for their children would consider those benefits and finally select one of the friendly pets for their children.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="model-answer-2-view-keeping-pets-is-good-for-children">Model Answer 2: [View: Keeping pets is good for children]&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>While some people prefer to keep their children at a distance from pets because of health and safety reasons, others choose to do just the opposite. In this essay, I would like to argue that pets are actually good for the overall well-being of children for some obvious reasons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first reason, of course, is that pets provide the children with comfort and company, especially when nobody else is accompanying them. But, even when somebody is accompanying them, children still feel a sense of comfort in the company of their pets, mainly because those pets are usually more “passive” and “loyal” than other humans. And that is exactly probably why, as some researchers have found, a very significant percentage of parents allow their youngsters to have pets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pets also help young children with learning. In fact, we often can see the children, who otherwise do not like to read, lying on their beds and reading to their dogs or cats and showing them pictures. The juniors even ask questions to their pets to see if they - the pets, are actually paying enough attention to the readings. In other words, the little ones actually learn important and fun things in a pleasant environment while petting their cats and dogs. Besides, researchers have also monitored that the stress level of the kids goes significantly down when they are with their pets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, some researchers have also found that having pets can reduce a child’s risk of developing certain common allergies. Such research showed that children, who had animals, had fewer positive skin tests for indoor allergens - like a pet and dust-mite allergen, and also outdoor allergens such as ragweed and grass, compared to those juniors who did not live with pets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, based on these findings, it can easily be argued that pets actually help children&amp;rsquo;s development, rather than harming them.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.ielts-mentor.com/writing-sample/writing-task-2/3577-keeping-pets-is-good-for-children">https://www.ielts-mentor.com/writing-sample/writing-task-2/3577-keeping-pets-is-good-for-children&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>